<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: web | Artsy Engineering]]></title>
  <link href="http://artsy.github.io/blog/categories/web/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://artsy.github.io/"/>
  <updated>2018-12-16T10:16:31+00:00</updated>
  <id>http://artsy.github.io/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Making Artsy Editorial Accessible]]></title>
    <link href="http://artsy.github.io/blog/2017/08/29/Making-Artsy-Editorial-Accessible/"/>
    <updated>2017-08-29T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <id>http://artsy.github.io/blog/2017/08/29/Making-Artsy-Editorial-Accessible</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>During Artsy's recent 2017 Hackathon we tackled making all of our editorial content <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Accessibility">accessible</a>. The idea was hatched at  Berlin JSConf this spring, where <a href="https://youtu.be/H4FzW9oFObs">Laura Carvajal gave a talk</a> following the <em>Financial Times</em>' experience implementing better accessibility requirements, and how they built these considerations into their testing process.</p>

<p>What does accessibility mean in a browser? Generally the term refers to supporting the wide range of assistive technologies for users with vision or motor impairments. These include screen readers, as well as mouseless navigation using a keyboard, eye tracking and other devices. Interestingly these technologies are implemented at the OS level rather than the browser itself. Mac's OS includes a built in screen-reader, and <a href="http://www.freedomscientific.com/Products/Blindness/JAWS">JAWS</a> is the most popular application in this vein. It is also notable that browsers do not track users who employ assistive tools.</p>

<p>Two users on <a href="http://webaim.org/discussion/mail_thread?thread=6326">WebAIM's forum</a> excellently present the case for accessibility as a developer's responsibility:</p>

<blockquote><p>"Users may be highly resistant to having their disabilities identified as they go throughout the web. Most persons with disabilities would really just rather that <em>the Web just work</em> for them."</p>

<p>"Looking at accessibility as a way to serve a specific population is missing the point that accessibility is about inclusion of all people."</p></blockquote>

<p>A central tenant of Artsy's mission is to 'make art as accessible as music'. By expanding accessibility for the visually and motor impaired to writing on art and culture, this projects allows us to follow through on this statement in a very literal way. Furthermore, there's no reason to ignore this audience; accommodating use of assistive technologies is an ethically responsible thing to do.</p>

<!-- more -->


<a name="Putting.it.into.practice"></a>
<h2>Putting it into practice</h2>

<p>Smartly structured HTML is essential for screen readers. They take note of semantic elements like headings or <code>&lt;nav&gt;</code>, and interpret our page's elements in the order they are written. Absolute and fixed spacing are ignored in this context, so it is important to realize non-visual reading of your site may prioritize different information, or present it in a different order than expected. This means that in JavaScript-oriented environments, and anywhere elements are inserted on the client, it is important to keep all elements necessary to navigating available in a semantic form at all times, including drop downs.</p>

<p>We used three tools to evaluate pain points on our site: the npm module <a href="https://github.com/pa11y/pa11y">pa11y</a>, Chrome's <a href="https://chrome.google.com/webstore/detail/accessibility-developer-t/fpkknkljclfencbdbgkenhalefipecmb?utm_source=chrome-ntp-icon">Accessibility Developer Tools</a>, and <a href="http://wave.webaim.org/">WAVE</a>&mdash; a web accessibility evaluation tool by <a href="http://webaim.org/">WebAIM</a>, a non-profit dedicated to "empowering organizations to make their own content accessible".  All three work similarly. Input a web address, and an error report is generated. Pa11y works in the terminal, and can export to a CSV, and even create a dashboard tracking separate URLs. Chrome handily provides a color-coded scorecard in addition to an accessibility audit report. Because Chrome's reporting lives in the browser's console, it is especially easy to inspect your code directly from an error. However, each tool brought up unique issues, so it is prudent to try a few.</p>

<p>We found a range of warnings and errors on our first run, where Chrome gave us a failing grade of 62, and pa11y raked up 48 errors, not counting a sizeable number of warnings. Luckily, most of the changes were fast and easy:</p>

<ul>
<li>Use meta language property (<code>&lt;html lang="en"&gt;</code>)</li>
<li>Increase the meta property for maximum scale to 5</li>
<li>Add hidden text to icon-only links and UI elements</li>
<li>Add alt text to all images</li>
<li>Include aria form attributes on input fields</li>
<li>Use semantic roles for the article body (<code>&lt;div role='article'&gt;</code>)</li>
<li>Remove of duplicate IDs from pages</li>
<li>Remove vendor-generated ids from SVGs, which in our case were often duplicates.</li>
</ul>


<p>A summary of changes implemented can be seen in pull requests <a href="https://github.com/artsy/force/pull/1730">here</a> and <a href="https://github.com/artsy/force/pull/1732">here</a>.</p>

<p>There were several places on our site where we wanted to include text that was intended only for screen readers. However, <code>display: none</code> is not necessarily acceptable in this context. Instead we opted for absolute positing of screen-reader targeted elements far out of the screen.</p>

<pre><code class="css">// hides text that is only for screen-readers

.screen-reader-text {
  position: absolute;
  left: 10000px;
  top: auto;
  width: 1px;
  height: 1px;
  overflow: hidden;
}
</code></pre>

<p>A few challenges were encountered as we worked through the error reports. My research brought up mixed messages on <code>display: none</code>. For example, Artsy renders the main menu in both desktop and mobile versions, but hides one view based on the user agent. We saw errors with all testing frameworks for having duplicate IDs, despite the fact that these elements were hidden via <code>display: none</code>.  This is a problem that would be well solved with React, where we could render content based to screen width rather than hiding a duplicate.</p>

<p><img src="/images/2017-08-29-Making-Artsy-Editorial-Accessible/Chrome-Accessibility-Dashboard.png" alt="Chrome Accessibility Audit Score" /></p>

<p>Another road block encountered was for headers that contain links&mdash; which the error reports recognized as empty headers, rather than reading the link. We use linked headings frequently for section titles in our articles, so this is an issue we are still mitigating. Lastly, using a screen reader is a skill set all its own! While our Chrome audit score is now far higher than where we started, my own experience using a screen reader proved far more difficult than expected. To be completely sure our implementation is working, I hope to find an experienced screen-reader user to give it a spin.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Helping the Web Towards OSS by Default]]></title>
    <link href="http://artsy.github.io/blog/2016/09/06/Milestone-on-OSS-by-Default/"/>
    <updated>2016-09-06T12:17:00+00:00</updated>
    <id>http://artsy.github.io/blog/2016/09/06/Milestone-on-OSS-by-Default</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>The main Artsy.net website for the desktop, <a href="https://github.com/artsy/force">Force</a>, was our first Artsy application to open its source code, <a href="http://artsy.github.io/author/craig">Craig</a> and <a href="http://artsy.github.io/author/brennan">Brennan</a> did it <a href="/blog/2014/09/05/we-open-sourced-our-isomorphic-javascript-website/">back in 2014</a>. Force's public offering laid the groundwork for the iOS OSS projects to come afterwards: <a href="/blog/2014/11/13/eidolon-retrospective/">Eidolon</a>, <a href="/blog/2015/04/28/how-we-open-sourced-eigen/">Eigen</a>, <a href="/blog/2015/08/06/open-sourcing-energy/">Energy</a> and <a href="/blog/2015/11/05/Emergence-Code-Review/">Emergence</a>.</p>

<p>Though Force wasn't quite Open Source by Default, it represented a <em>really</em> important step for  Artsy's OSS perspective but was not the end goal. We were opening our source, but not opening our process.</p>

<p>This month both <a href="https://github.com/artsy/force">Force</a>, the desktop version of <a href="https://www.artsy.net/">Artsy.net</a> and <a href="https://github.com/artsy/microgravity">Microgravity</a>, the mobile version - moved to being built entirely in the open. Read on to find out how.</p>

<!-- more -->


<a name="Force"></a>
<h2>Force</h2>

<p>Over the course of the last month, I've sat on and off with Charles "<a href="http://charlesbroskoski.com/_/">Cab</a>" Broskoski, and figured out what it would take to migrate Force to work in the public. Previous to this, work happened on a private repo, and we would push that code to the public.</p>

<p>We scoped out what it would require, creating an issue that summarized the work. Then we waited for 2 weeks, to give people the chance to discuss the idea and to offer examples for why we should delay or not move. Not all projects <em>should</em> be OSS, and everyone should have a say when it affects them - giving some time let the team speak their mind. Especially during summer, when people were less active at work.</p>

<p></div></div><a href='/images/oss-milestone/force-oss.png'><img src="/images/oss-milestone/force-oss.png"></a><div class='meta-container'><header>&nbsp;</header></div><div class='date-container'>&nbsp;</div><div class='content-container'><div class='entry-content'></p>

<p>It had been 9 months since the last commit to the public repo, and so auditing the commits was a matter of investigating into configuration files, and seeing what's changed since the last public commit.</p>

<p>Next up, we renamed the current <code>force</code> repo to <code>force-private</code>. This was to keep the old issues and PRs around after we moved to working in the public. With <code>force</code> now available we re-named the already public project.</p>

<p>We then ensured all outstanding PRs were merged or closed, and pushed the commits from <code>force-private</code> to the now OSS <code>force</code>.</p>

<a name="CI"></a>
<h3>CI</h3>

<p>To get back up to speed we needed to set up CI, figuring this out took time.</p>

<p>We got testing up and running in no time. However, Force is deployed via <a href="https://semaphoreci.com/">Semaphore CI</a>, and to deploy we needed to push compiled assets to S3. To pull that off, we needed access to an S3 key, and token.</p>

<p>In our iOS projects, <a href="https://github.com/artsy/eidolon/pull/607">we do not expose environment variables</a> to PRs from forks, so we don't expect them to pass from external contributors. This is fine, because we have <a href="http://artsy.github.io/blog/2016/01/13/OSS-Expectations/">different expectations</a> for OSS apps vs libraries. We do this to ensure that we don't receive a PR that adds <code>printenv</code> to the CI scripts, exposing our secret keys.</p>

<p>As we couldn't add the keys to our testing environment, we added them to our heroku environment then took them from that. Semaphore sets up our heroku environment only during deployment, so in the deployment phase, we can use a line like:</p>

<pre><code class="sh">export FORCE_S3_KEY=$(heroku config:get FORCE_S3_KEY --app force-production)
</code></pre>

<p>This sets up the environment like we used to have it when force was private.</p>

<a name="Team"></a>
<h3>Team</h3>

<p>We needed to move all the team members to using the OSS version of our apps. This is a little bit complicated as <a href="/blog/2012/01/29/how-art-dot-sy-uses-github-to-build-art-dot-sy/">we work from forks</a>. <a href="http://www.anandarooproy.com/portfolio">Roop</a>, an engineer on the web team, created a "Force OSS Dance Script" ( sidenote: <a href="http://www.anandarooproy.com/portfolio">his site</a> is worth a visit, there's 15 years of interesting maps. )</p>

<pre><code class="sh">## RENAME THE OLD REPO

# on GitHub

# - Go to my fork https://github.com/&lt;username&gt;/force
# - Go to Settings tab
# - Rename repo to "force-private"

# on my local machine

mv force force-private
cd force-private
git remote set-url upstream git@github.com:artsy/force-private.git
git remote set-url origin git@github.com:&lt;username&gt;/force-private.git


## FORK AND CLONE THE NEW REPO

# back to GitHub

# - Go to the new Force repo https://github.com/artsy/force
# - Fork it to my account

# back to my local machine

git clone git@github.com:&lt;username&gt;/force.git
cd force
git remote add upstream git@github.com:artsy/force.git
cp ../force-private/.env ./
cp ../force-private/node_modules ./ # or just 'npm install' again


# all good now - both repos on local machine with correct remotes, envs, deps
</code></pre>

<p>For Force, all the same commits existed in both repos, so it would be difficult to push secrets to the open repo by accident. However, individuals did to sync up a new version of their forks.</p>

<p>And that, is how we moved force into OSS by Default. :+1: - We'll cover the issues migration later.</p>

<a name="Microgravity"></a>
<h2>Microgravity</h2>

<p>I have a lot of love for Microgravity. It's the web project that made <a href="/blog/2015/04/28/how-we-open-sourced-eigen/">Eigen</a> possible. Once Force had moved, I started spending time with Craig trying to understand what it would take to open up Microgravity.</p>

<p></div></div><a href='/images/oss-milestone/micrograv-oss.png'><img src="/images/oss-milestone/micrograv-oss.png"></a><div class='meta-container'><header>&nbsp;</header></div><div class='date-container'>&nbsp;</div><div class='content-container'><div class='entry-content'></p>

<p>It is no surprise to find a lot of overlap, both projects are based on the same foundations: <a href="https://github.com/artsy/ezel">Ezel.js</a>.</p>

<p>We didn't trust the commit history for microgravity, so we nuked it. Same as our native OSS apps.</p>

<p>We came up with a pattern to make it easier for people to migrate issues, we created a <code>migrate</code> GitHub label that anyone can apply to an issue in a private repo. Then we use <a href="https://github-issue-mover.appspot.com">Issue Mover for GitHub</a> with some inline JavaScript to loop through all our issues to migrate. As it's applying a label we can ask product owners and designers to choose ones that are important to them too.</p>

<p>--</p>

<p>I love that I got to help make these changes, the web team started the process of opening our apps at Artsy, then the mobile team took the next big step. Now the teams are both in lock-step, and if you work on the front-end at Artsy - OSS by Default is the way we all work now.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Using Paw with Per-Developer Settings]]></title>
    <link href="http://artsy.github.io/blog/2016/04/14/net-working-with-paw/"/>
    <updated>2016-04-14T12:09:00+00:00</updated>
    <id>http://artsy.github.io/blog/2016/04/14/net-working-with-paw</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I am a big fan of developer tooling, as spending time upfront on improving your process can pay a lot of dividends over time. I want to talk about one in particular: <a href="https://luckymarmot.com/paw">Paw</a>. Paw is a native HTTP client with a bunch of features. I want to cover one that means that we can now <a href="https://github.com/artsy/energy/pull/192">introduce</a> <code>[AppName].paw</code> files in our mobile projects, making it easy for us to discuss networking requests.</p>

<!-- more -->


<a name="OK..what.is.Paw."></a>
<h3>OK, what is Paw?</h3>

<p>Paw is a tool that stores collections of API endpoints, along with all the metadata required to call them. We first started using Paw during the creation <a href="https://github.com/artsy/eidolon/blob/master/Kiosk/Stubbed%20Responses/Me.json">of Eidolon</a> as a way to keep track of the auction-related API calls we would need to stub for <a href="http://cocoapods.org/pods/moya">Moya</a>, an iOS networking library that required stubbed data. It made it easy for us to keep track of how all the different API routes work together, and to verify that we were doing things right.</p>

<p></div></div><a href='/images/2016-04-14-Paw/eidolon.png'><img src="/images/2016-04-14-Paw/eidolon.png" title="paw tokens" ></a><div class='meta-container'><header>&nbsp;</header></div><div class='date-container'>&nbsp;</div><div class='content-container'><div class='entry-content'></p>

<p>We used environment variables to keep track of things we wanted to change, but in using them this way we couldn't publicise our Paw files, the real versions contained secrets that should stay secret.</p>

<p><img src="/images/2016-04-14-Paw/eidolon-env.png" alt="Environments for Eidolon" /></p>

<p>The environment tooling made it easy to change the routes, users and settings easily, but were also the thing keeping us from being able to share the files in source. Because of this, we stopped using Paw to keep track of our routes as we had to ad-hoc share the file over chat.</p>

<a name="A.Second.Shot"></a>
<h3>A Second Shot</h3>

<p>This week, roughly a year and a half later, I started work on a <a href="https://github.com/artsy/energy/pull/189">large project</a> that I knew would involve using new networking APIs. So I took the time to look for ways to interpret what I was going to be working with. After exploring some alternatives, I came back to Paw, and discovered they had a <a href="https://blog.luckymarmot.com/posts/paw-23-keep-it-secret-keep-it-safe/">new feature</a>: Keychain integration. This stopped my search.</p>

<p>In our iOS projects, as they are all open source, we use <a href="https://github.com/orta/cocoapods-keys">CocoaPods-Keys</a> to ensure that our development configuration secrets are kept safe and outside of the project's source code. It stores the per-project keys inside a developer's Keychain. This means they can be accessed from inside the iOS app, but also from the <a href="/images/2016-04-14-Paw/keychain.png">developer's computer</a> via a determinate location in the Keychain app.</p>

<pre><code>~/d/i/a/energy (master) ⏛  bundle exec pod keys
Keys for Folio
 ├  ArtsyAPIClientSecret - [***********]
 ├  ArtsyAPIClientKey - [***********]
 ├  HockeyAppBetaID - [***********]
 ├  HockeyAppLiveID - [***********]
 ├  IntercomAppID - [***********]
 ├  IntercomAPIKey - [***********]
 ├  SegmentProduction - [***********]
 ├  SegmentBeta - [***********]
 └  SegmentDev - [***********]
</code></pre>

<p>This means that we can use CocoaPods-Keys with Paw in order to use the same <code>ArtsyAPIClientSecret</code> and <code>ArtsyAPIClientKey</code> environment config variables. Great. This is almost enough to make the first API call to to get an access token.</p>

<p>I re-used this idea to allow developers to have unique username and passwords. I created two more entries in Keychain, username and <a href="/images/2016-04-14-Paw/keychain-password.png">password</a>. This is something that every developer using our Paw file has to do, otherwise Paw won't know who to log you in as.</p>

<p><img src="/images/2016-04-14-Paw/keychain-username.png" alt="Keychain Email" /></p>

<p>With these all hooked up, I could set up Paw to use all of our Keychain entities:</p>

<p><img src="/images/2016-04-14-Paw/paw-adding-keychain.png" alt="Paw Adding Keychain" />
<img src="/images/2016-04-14-Paw/paw-setting-password.png" alt="Paw Setting Password" /></p>

<p>Tada! Now I can run my route, and I've got an access token to use with our API.</p>

<a name="Route.Resolving"></a>
<h3>Route Resolving</h3>

<p>Automating the route to get an access token is the first step because Paw allows you to use the output of one route inside any new route. I'll show you, then talk it through.</p>

<p></div></div><a href='/images/2016-04-14-Paw/paw-tokens.png'><img src="/images/2016-04-14-Paw/paw-tokens.png" title="paw tokens" ></a><div class='meta-container'><header>&nbsp;</header></div><div class='date-container'>&nbsp;</div><div class='content-container'><div class='entry-content'></p>

<p>I made it so that my new request ( for the route <code>api/v1/me</code>)  passes in an header of <code>X-Access-Token</code>, with the value being the <code>access_token</code> from the route we just made called <code>Auth</code>. This means that when the token expires, it will automatically re-generate a new one and we're never storing the token explicitly inside the Paw file. Our secrets stay secret, and per-developer - I don't want to know other people's passwords.</p>

<p>Once those two routes were set up, it was a matter of looking up what routes I would need and added them to the paw file for the project. I used the group system to make it easy to show / hide sections, and experimented with using environments to differentiate between staging and production servers. Not quite figured that yet.</p>

<a name="Wrap.up"></a>
<h3>Wrap up</h3>

<p>It's easier to talk about your API when any other developer can open this one file and shoot off requests at the same time as you. One of my favourite nice-touches is to be able to easily convert any request into a cURL command.</p>

<p>I am using this event as a reminder to myself that tools evolve, and maybe your first impression on a developer tool may require re-interpreting in light of software evolution.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
