<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: learning | Artsy Engineering]]></title>
  <link href="https://artsy.github.io/blog/categories/learning/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="https://artsy.github.io/"/>
  <updated>2022-04-12T23:43:17+00:00</updated>
  <id>https://artsy.github.io/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Why Asking for Help Strengthens Engineering Teams]]></title>
    <link href="https://artsy.github.io/blog/2021/02/11/asking-for-help/"/>
    <updated>2021-02-11T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <id>https://artsy.github.io/blog/2021/02/11/asking-for-help</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I know that for many developers, especially those early in their careers, asking for help can be intimidating. I
often fear wasting someone’s time or exposing myself as less skilled or smart than my team initially thought.</p>

<p>In my first month as a software engineer at Artsy (and barely six months into life as an engineer after
<a href="https://medium.com/swlh/how-losing-my-job-helped-me-find-my-way-back-8c8f86552acc">transitioning from a career in communications</a>), I was struggling
through a ticket assigned to me as a “good first issue.” (The team estimated the task to be straightforward enough
for someone new to the team.) After a few hours stumbling between the ticket, my code, and Google, I made very
little progress.</p>

<!-- more -->

<p>Early and often, my fellow engineers at Artsy encourage me to ask for help when I hit roadblocks. Even with the
support explicitly offered to me, I was shaky. The extra 10 seconds it took to type out my question in Slack was
just enough time for me to chicken out.</p>

<p>Opening up with my team members about my concerns, I learned that asking for help is not just for me but ultimately
benefits my team. Sharing their insights below, I hope other engineers, early-career or not, feel empowered to ask
questions, stay curious, and prioritize learning for themselves and their team — all hallmarks of great engineers.</p>

<h2 id="why-its-so-hard-to-ask-for-help">Why It’s So Hard to Ask For Help</h2>

<p>Working in tech and as an engineer (and even in <a href="https://medium.com/better-programming/why-women-dont-pursue-software-engineering-17d0dead24e9">undergraduate computer science
classes</a>,) I often felt surrounded by people smarter than me.
Operating alongside peers who are excelling motivates me to set the bar higher for myself. But at times, it can
also be intimidating. There is a reason that imposter syndrome is so pervasive in tech industry discourse. (A 2018
study found that <a href="https://www.cnet.com/news/tech-employees-likely-to-suffer-from-impostor-syndrome/">58% of tech workers suffer from
it</a>.) The fear of being “found out” as an imposter,
inadequate, or less impressive can be especially acute for those early in their career and from <a href="https://zora.medium.com/why-imposter-syndrome-is-worse-for-women-of-color-3bcf37335405">underrepresented
groups</a>.</p>

<p>Like other VC-backed companies, Artsy is working toward aggressive business targets and ships software at a high
velocity. At high-growth companies, tight deadlines and high-energy cultures make it tempting to shy away from hard
problems and to let the more senior people tackle the tough challenges. But these moments are critical for growth
and learning across the team.</p>

<figure class="illustration">
    <a target="_blank" href="https://www.artsy.net/artwork/pipilotti-rist-help-me">
        <img src="https://d32dm0rphc51dk.cloudfront.net/P24AUuVFX50Tr2Q6w58-fQ/large.jpg" />
    </a>
    <figcaption>Pipilotti Rist, Help me, 2016, Hauser &amp; Wirth, available on Artsy
    </figcaption>
</figure>

<h2 id="rethinking-productivity">Rethinking Productivity</h2>

<p>On Artsy’s engineering team, we put a lot of energy into optimizing developer workflows and communication channels.
While asking for help seemed counter to productivity, my team helped me see that the opposite is true: Encouraging
engineers to support one another is integral to building an effective engineering organization.</p>

<p>Pair programming is growing in popularity, not because society is becoming more kind and patient, but because it’s
good for business. Teams in synergy can <a href="https://martinfowler.com/articles/on-pair-programming.html">ship higher-quality code more quickly</a>.</p>

<p>Because teaching is one of the best ways to become an expert, a more experienced engineer can level up when pairing
with a less experienced engineer. Teaching solidifies understanding, reveals gaps in knowledge, and opens up new
questions for exploration. Recently, a senior engineer shared that they never questioned something in our codebase
until I prompted them to take a closer look. We deepened our understanding together.</p>

<p>Providing help also cultivates an engineer’s mentoring skills, which is especially important if they aim for
management or leadership roles.</p>

<p>Finally, a lot of people enjoy helping others for the pure reason that it feels good. Studies show that a majority
of workers prioritize meaning in their work over salary and that meaningful work translates to greater retention
and productivity. (<a href="https://hbr.org/2018/11/9-out-of-10-people-are-willing-to-earn-less-money-to-do-more-meaningful-work">Harvard Business Review</a> goes
so far as attaching a dollar sign to meaningful work: they estimate highly meaningful work generates an extra
$9,078 per worker per year and saves an average of $6.43 million in annual turnover-related costs for every 10,000
workers.) All good arguments for engaging in collaborative and empathetic workflows.</p>

<h2 id="building-community-and-scaling-knowledge">Building Community and Scaling Knowledge</h2>

<p>Building a culture of collaboration is particularly challenging, especially for distributed teams and those working
remotely during the pandemic. Pair programming provides opportunities for connecting, which can reverberate
throughout an organization.</p>

<p>Learning also has a network effect, so knowledge scales exponentially. If someone teaches me a new concept, I am
now empowered to share the knowledge with others, and then they can then spread that knowledge even further.</p>

<p>Put simply by one of my coworkers: Learning is contributing.</p>

<figure class="illustration">
    <a target="_blank" href="https://www.artsy.net/artwork/richard-artschwager-question-mark">
        <img src="https://d32dm0rphc51dk.cloudfront.net/fccQIzHtxIwf2eHTrEg0Dw/large.jpg" />
    </a>
    <figcaption>Richard Artschwager, Question Mark, 2001, Gagosian, available on Artsy
    </figcaption>
</figure>

<h2 id="why-prioritizing-your-growth-is-okay">Why Prioritizing Your Growth is Okay</h2>

<p>My natural tendency is to want to give more than I ask. But for all early-career engineers, it is also normal to
need a lot of help at the beginning. I need to trust that our recruitment team knew to ask the right questions to
make an informed decision to hire me — the real me, beginner and all. The fastest way to improve is to tackle
difficult problems head-on and ask questions when I need support. Investing in my learning at this point in my
career will pay dividends to my team in the months and years to come.</p>

<p>So yes, I went ahead and pressed send on that Slack to ask for help.</p>

<blockquote>
  <p><em>This post originally appeared on Anna’s blog on <a href="https://anna-carey.medium.com/">Medium</a>.</em></p>
</blockquote>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Introducing Artsy Engineering Radio]]></title>
    <link href="https://artsy.github.io/blog/2021/01/06/introducing-artsy-engineering-radio/"/>
    <updated>2021-01-06T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <id>https://artsy.github.io/blog/2021/01/06/introducing-artsy-engineering-radio</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Available now on <a href="https://podcasts.apple.com/us/podcast/artsy-engineering-radio/id1545870104">Apple Podcasts</a>, <a href="https://open.spotify.com/show/0gJYxpqN6P11dbjNw8VT2a?si=L4TWDrQETwuVO6JR1SOZTQ">Spotify</a>, and coming soon elsewhere, is Artsy
Engineering Radio!</p>

<p>Solving problems in the world of software engineering can mean a lot of different things, and this podcast will
explore what that looks like at Artsy. If you’ve followed our blog, you can expect a podcast that sounds like it.
There are a ton of amazing engineers here at Artsy and we’re excited for you to hear their voices and stories. Our
hope is that this podcast will make it easy for more engineers at Artsy to contribute to the public persona of
Artsy Engineering.</p>

<!-- more -->

<p>We’ll release new episodes every other week. Our target episode length is 30 minutes. Some episodes will be
technical and others less so. Because
<a href="https://github.com/artsy/README/blob/master/culture/engineering-principles.md#open-source-by-default">we work in the open</a>
it’s easy for us to talk about our work in public.</p>

<p>This isn’t the first attempt at an Artsy engineering podcast! Our engineering team has attempted multiple times to
start one. When <a href="https://artsy.github.io/author/jonallured/">Jon</a> went to create new Slack and Notion hubs, he found that both already existed. The
<a href="https://github.com/artsy/artsy.github.io/pull/368">PR for the podcast RSS feed</a> was opened in July, 2017!</p>

<p>We’re beating the fizzle this time, though. We’ve got momentum and enthusiasm on our side — several episodes are
already published and we’ve got more lined up. Instead of tinkering with tooling we’re focusing on making episodes,
even if they aren’t perfect. Like the software we build, the podcast will get better over time as we iterate.</p>

<p>What do we have so far? In
<a href="https://podcasts.apple.com/us/podcast/0-introducing-artsy-engineering-radio/id1545870104?i=1000503035175">episode 0</a>,
<a href="https://artsy.github.io/author/jonallured/">Jon</a>, <a href="https://artsy.github.io/author/matt-dole/">Matt</a>, and <a href="https://artsy.github.io/author/steve-hicks/">Steve</a> introduced the podcast and talked about what you can expect from
future episodes. <a href="https://podcasts.apple.com/us/podcast/1-how-to-have-good-meetings/id1545870104?i=1000503035176">Episode 1</a> features a conversation with <a href="https://artsy.github.io/author/ash/">Ash</a> about facilitating meaningful and
inclusive team meetings, and how meetings are part of building teams, trust, and systems. <a href="https://podcasts.apple.com/us/podcast/2-how-artsy-hires-engineers/id1545870104?i=1000504558896">Episode 2</a> is
a conversation between <a href="https://artsy.github.io/author/steve-hicks/">Steve</a> and <a href="https://artsy.github.io/author/ash/">Ash</a> about how Artsy hires engineers.</p>

<p>Find the first few episodes right now in your podcast player. Watch for future episodes in your feed and we’ll
announce them <a href="https://twitter.com/artsyopensource">on Twitter</a> when they’re released.</p>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[iOS Learning Group]]></title>
    <link href="https://artsy.github.io/blog/2019/12/03/ios-learning-group/"/>
    <updated>2019-12-03T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <id>https://artsy.github.io/blog/2019/12/03/ios-learning-group</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Regular readers of our blog might be familiar with <a href="https://www.cultureamp.com">Culture Amp</a>, a tool Artsy uses to
collect anonymous feedback and take action on cultural issues (we most recently discussed the tool
<a href="https://artsy.github.io/blog/2019/04/19/having-a-coffee-with-every-engineer/">in this blog post</a>). At a
company-wide level, Culture Amp has helped guide everything from Artsy’s evolving culture, to our physical work
spaces, to our support for remote work. At an engineering-team level, we’ve also been using Culture Amp to guide
our choices in technology, documentation, and training.</p>

<p>In this blog post I’ll be detailing a recent learning course we ran to share knowledge about how Artsy builds iOS
software for our entire engineering team.</p>

<!-- more -->

<p>Let’s start at the beginning. Earlier this year, Artsy Engineering ran a survey through Culture Amp to get answers
to the following questions:</p>

<ol>
  <li>What is our team’s opinion on our current technology choices?</li>
  <li>What is our team’s familiarity with or preparedness for our current technology?</li>
  <li>Where are the areas of strength and opportunities for both learning and teaching?</li>
</ol>

<p>There are a lot of things we learned from this survey, and among them was a desire for engineers to better
understand how to build iOS software at Artsy. With a nudge (and support!) from our <em>Peer Learning Working Group</em>,
I set out to create a learning plan. I wasn’t starting from scratch – we already ran a few learning groups on
topics ranging from Scala fundamentals to React Hooks. We used the lessons learned from <em>those</em> experiences to
define and deliver a learning plan.</p>

<p>I started by booking five sessions, spread out by a week. I picked a time that was a good fit for as many engineers
as possible, and I scheduled them a month ahead to give people a chance to move their schedules around. Scheduling
them up front was important, to give learners a sense of what to expect; previous learning groups had suffered from
inconsistent schedules, which led to intermittent attendance. I also asked each Tech Lead to make sure at least one
engineer from their team attended.</p>

<p>Next was the actual curriculum. In the spirit of “proudly discovered elsewhere”, we actually looked at using
existing learning resources that someone else had already developed. However, since
<a href="https://artsy.github.io/series/react-native-at-artsy/">our iOS stack is a bit unique</a> and I was keen to keep
honing my own skills as a technical educator, we decided to make our own. With the help of our Peer Learning
Working Group, we set learning objectives for the five sessions. Here was the original plan:</p>

<ul>
  <li><strong>Week 1</strong>: This week, we will cover how iOS software is developed, QA’d, and deployed. By the end of this
session, all participants should be able to pull the latest code from <a href="https://github.com/artsy/eigen">Eigen</a>
(our native iOS repo) and <a href="https://github.com/artsy/emission">Emission</a> (our React Native repo), see their work
in an iOS simulator, and link the two projects together.</li>
  <li><strong>Week 2</strong>: This week, we will cover what makes React Native distinct from React on the web, as well as how Artsy
leverages shared infrastructure (such as our design-system, <a href="https://github.com/artsy/palette">Palette</a>) to make
it easier for engineers to work in either one.</li>
  <li><strong>Week 3</strong>: This week, we will cover how to create a new view controller. View controllers are the main unit of
composition for native iOS apps, and we integrate our “Scene” React components <em>as</em> view controllers. This
includes routing between view controller, from both native Objective-C and React Native code.</li>
  <li><strong>Week 4</strong>: This week, we will create our own React component to fit within the new view controller from Week 3.
This will be a Relay container, fetching data from our GraphQL API,
<a href="https://github.com/artsy/metaphysics">Metaphysics</a>. We will cover how to fetch data, how to <em>re</em>-fetch data, as
well as how Eigen and Emission integrate together to provide client-side API response caches (both Relay and
others).</li>
  <li><strong>Week 5</strong>: This is the final week. Participants are asked to bring an iOS bug from their product team’s backlog
that they would like to fix. Pairing is encouraged.</li>
</ul>

<p>Things mostly went to plan. I made sure to provide the learning resources at least a day or two ahead of each
session; this let me respond to feedback from the previous week, and also gave learners a chance to review
materials ahead of time.</p>

<p>Every session was recorded for anyone who missed it. We had a shared Slack channel set up for questions, so
engineers could help each other. I also made sure to provide weekly office hours: this was space for people who
missed sessions to catch up, or to just dig into concepts in more detail. I’ll return to the topic of office hours
later in this post.</p>

<p>Around the time of the learning group, I was reading
<em><a href="https://www.amazon.com/Make-Stick-Science-Successful-Learning/dp/0674729013/ref=sr_1_1?keywords=making+it+stick&amp;qid=1575314498&amp;sr=8-1">Make It Stick: The Science of Successful Learning</a></em>.
The book is written for people who want to improve their own learning skills, but it was <em>very</em> helpful to read as
I was developing and delivering this curriculum. Here are a few lessons that I learned from the book that were
helpful while teaching engineers at Artsy about how we build iOS software:</p>

<ul>
  <li>If someone tries to do something themselves <em>before</em> being told how to do it, the attempt will strengthen their
understanding of the underlying concept. To put this into practice, I would often ask learners questions that I
didn’t expect they could answer yet, and the resulting discussion was always worthwhile.</li>
  <li>Interleaving different concepts together helps learners form connections between those concepts. This was
especially important, since a big motivator for using React Native at Artsy was to share skills between web and
iOS codebases. As an example of putting this into practice, I interleaved a discussion of
<a href="https://relay.dev">Relay</a> into our curriculum; I hoped to show learners both a new perspective of Relay, as well
as show them how familiar writing React Native code was to writing React web code.</li>
  <li>Allowing for some forgetting to take place before reviewing concepts will
<a href="https://njcideas.wordpress.com/2017/09/22/the-cognitive-science-of-studying-massed-practice-vs-spaced-practice/">help strengthen learner’s understanding</a>.
To put this into practice, I would return to topics from a few weeks ago to cement their understanding with
learners.</li>
</ul>

<p>I had to push through some discomfort as an educator, too. Each session ended with homework questions, which we
reviewed at the top of the next session. I would ask each question and then just sit there, in awkward silence,
while everyone looked around for someone to answer. Eventually, inevitably, someone would.</p>

<p>All of the learning materials
<a href="https://github.com/artsy/README/tree/master/resources/mobile/learning-group">are open source</a>. While the materials
are mostly specific to Artsy, they may be of help to others. And regardless, we want to adhere to our
<a href="https://github.com/artsy/README/blob/master/culture/engineering-principles.md#open-source-by-default">Open Source by Default</a>
principle.</p>

<p>We learned quite a lot from delivering this curriculum – lessons we can apply to our next learning group:</p>

<ul>
  <li>Learners appreciated the weekly schedule set upfront, affirming what we learned from previous learning groups.</li>
  <li>Learners appreciated having access to the materials ahead of time.</li>
  <li>Learners appreciated having the sessions recorded, to be reviewed later (or watched, in case they missed the
session).</li>
  <li>Learners appreciated having office hours available; even though the office hours weren’t well-attended, learners
appreciated having access to them if they needed to.</li>
  <li>Learners even appreciated the awkward silences while I waited for an answer to my questions. (One survey
respondent described it as “like pulling teeth, but helpful.”)</li>
  <li>Learners are varied in how they want to learn. Some liked going through things together. Some thought we went too
slow. Still others thought we should expect learners to do more work ahead of class.</li>
</ul>

<p>This last point is worth expanding upon. While everyone learns differently, there is a distinction between what
<em>feels</em> effective and what <em>is</em> effective. I tried to structure the course so that it was accessible to as many
types of learners as possible: some like to review materials ahead of time, some like to have them on hand during
the session, etc. Some are in-person, others are remote, still others are reviewing the recording. I could write
another blog post about learning styles, but for now it suffices to say that I aimed for <em>inclusion</em> of as many
different learners as possible while also recognizing that I can’t make everyone happy.</p>

<p>As I enter a new chapter of my own career, leading Artsy’s new Mobile Experience team, it was helpful to return to
some fundamentals; to get familiar with technology choices that we made years ago
(<a href="https://ashfurrow.com/blog/swift-vs-react-native-feels/">choices which I originally resisted</a>); and to learn from
learners’ perspectives as beginners. The future of iOS software at Artsy is very bright, and now every product team
is more prepared than ever to deliver user experiences that are of a quality worthy of art.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Public Speaking - Part 2: Where To Start?]]></title>
    <link href="https://artsy.github.io/blog/2016/03/14/public-speaking-part2-where-to-start/"/>
    <updated>2016-03-14T11:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <id>https://artsy.github.io/blog/2016/03/14/public-speaking-part2-where-to-start</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>So you’ve decided <a href="http://artsy.github.io/blog/2016/03/09/public-speaking-part1-is-it-for-me/">you’d like to give speaking a go</a>, or perhaps you were always interested. By now you’re probably wondering where to start.</p>

<p>There are various options depending on what you’re looking for. Would you prefer a smaller, intimate audience or would you like to reach far and wide? Is the topic of your choice suited for a quick talk or would you rather discuss it at length? Let’s have a look.</p>

<!-- more -->

<h3 id="in-house--workplace-knowledge-share">In-house / Workplace Knowledge Share</h3>

<p>Lots of workplaces dedicate some time to knowledge sharing nowadays (and if yours doesn’t, see if you can start one!). They can be technical, for instance at Artsy we host a technical Lunch and Learn weekly. They could also be on any topic, like <a href="https://www.artsy.net/article/natalia-maldonado-introduction-to-office-meditation-5-steps-to-peace-of-mind-at-work">meditation</a>. Anywhere between 5 and 15 minutes in length is common, and they are a perfect opportunity to talk about things you know well. This could be centred around your day to day work, spreading the knowledge to decrease <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Bus_factor">the bus factor</a>, or something from your personal life. I’ve given a talk on <a href="https://speakerdeck.com/mennenia/colour-theory">colour theory in painting</a> once.</p>

<p>If you have a workplace you feel comfortable at, this is definitely a good place to start.</p>

<p>One of the key elements in public speaking that is often forgotten is the fact that the audience wants you to succeed. They’re not there to poke holes or boo you off stage. They are curious to see what you have to say and learn from you. Give them that opportunity.</p>

<p>Even if your goal is towards speaking at bigger events, any chance at practicing and putting together a well flowing talk is good and shouldn’t be ignored.</p>

<h3 id="local-meet-ups">Local meet-ups</h3>

<p>If you’re in a city that has a thriving meet-up scene, you may want to put your name forward to speak on a certain topic. A UK meet-up, <a href="http://www.meetup.com/NSLondon/">NSLondon</a>, is a great example of this. Many different members of the community have spoken, and it’s created a lovely atmosphere where it feels like you’re exchanging interesting tidbits of information continuously. Also for newcomers it’s created a welcoming atmosphere, as the people speaking are often people they know or “just like them”.</p>

<p>If you have a meet-up with a similar positive vibe, there’s no reason not to have a chat with the organisers and see what the next steps would be. It might even be well worth practicing a talk here, for when you’ve got a bigger event coming up and you would like feedback. Bare in mind, the audience wants you to succeed!</p>

<p>Sidenote — if your city does not (yet) have a great meet-up, it’s well worth starting one.</p>

<h3 id="conferences">Conferences</h3>

<p>Often considered the most intimidating of all. People have purchased tickets and possibly travelled from far. The audience is usually in the hundreds, occasionally even more than a thousand. Even the most experienced speakers can get a bit nervous for this.</p>

<p>Funnily enough, my first ever talk, since starting out as a developer, was at a <a href="http://www.iosdevuk.com/">conference</a>. It happened to have a very friendly atmosphere and really wasn’t that scary. I can’t stress enough that, yes, the audience wants you to succeed. I remember talking through my introduction and seeing all the curious, attentive faces. They were there because they were interested. They cared for what I had to say.</p>

<p>I will say that this doesn’t necessarily mean you should go talk about anything your heart desires. Ultimately the attendees are there to learn, so it’s only fair that as speakers you’d tailor your presentation towards your audience. But more on that in Part 3.</p>

<p>To be considered, often conference organisers ask people to submit a CfP (Call for Papers / Call for Proposals). This is your chance to submit details on what you’d like to present on, although they may <a href="http://www.osfeels.com/talk-ideas/">give you suggestions</a>. You usually want to include a preliminary talk title, an abstract, and a bit of background on yourself. If you’ve done any talks before and they happen to have been recorded, it’s worth including the video or otherwise previous slidedecks.</p>

<p>As for how CfPs then get chosen depends on the conference. Most of the time the organisational committee selects talks from the proposal list. Some conferences have <a href="http://www.altconf.com">an independent panel</a> review anonymised proposals or have a system in place where <a href="http://cfp.uikonf.com/about">the community votes</a>. Once it’s been decided, they will get back in touch with you.</p>

<p>Usually conferences are swarmed with CfPs so please don’t be discouraged if it takes a few tries to get picked. It’s understandable to feel rejected and give up, but bare in mind that a friend of mine felt this way yet kept applying. He got his break at NSSpain 2014, and now is incredibly active in the <a href="http://www.meetup.com/swift-language/">San Francisco Swift</a> meet-up scene. All of this got the ball rolling and now he’s given talks all around the world. <a href="https://twitter.com/simjp">You might even have heard of him</a>.</p>

<h3 id="lightning-talks">Lightning talks</h3>

<p>If a CfP is a bit too much to prepare at the moment (we’re all busy) or you didn’t get in, another option is to give a lightning talk if the conference of your choice has slots. When done well, they are great.</p>

<p>A lightning talk is usually capped at 5 minutes, and gives you the time and space to cover one thing well. The best ones I’ve heard, have had one main message to convey and did so excellently.</p>

<p>They require a bit of planning as you <a href="http://quoteinvestigator.com/2012/04/28/shorter-letter/">want to be concise</a>, but will be done before you know it and gives the audience a great point of reference to engage with you. Not to mention that sometimes you might get asked to do a full talk based off these.</p>

<h3 id="preparing-content">Preparing content</h3>

<p><a href="http://artsy.github.io/blog/2016/03/09/public-speaking-part1-is-it-for-me/">Choosing to publicly speak</a> and where is only half the battle. Deciding the content, formulating an abstract, talk title, and slides are not trivial. But fear not, Part 3 in this series will have you covered. Stay tuned!</p>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Public Speaking - Part 1: Is It For Me?]]></title>
    <link href="https://artsy.github.io/blog/2016/03/09/public-speaking-part1-is-it-for-me/"/>
    <updated>2016-03-09T11:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <id>https://artsy.github.io/blog/2016/03/09/public-speaking-part1-is-it-for-me</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>At Artsy, sharing knowledge is heavily encouraged and so we write our code in the open, document using blog posts, and speak about our experiences. Many have <a href="https://twitter.com/qnoid/status/702955785064677376">bumped into us</a> at various places around the world. And so I often get the question: “How did you get started? I’m interested in speaking too”.</p>

<p>In the name of sharing experiences with others, I can’t encourage this enough. Unfortunately though, public speaking is still considered <a href="https://www.washingtonpost.com/news/wonk/wp/2014/10/30/clowns-are-twice-as-scary-to-democrats-as-they-are-to-republicans/">man’s biggest fear</a>.</p>

<p>I’d like to share with you the benefits of public speaking, tips on how to get started, and how to give great presentations.</p>

<!-- more -->

<h2 id="why-do-it">Why do it?</h2>

<h3 id="communication">Communication</h3>

<p>Without necessarily realising, you’re publicly speaking all the time. At the heart of it, it’s the act of communicating and expressing your ideas and viewpoints for others to understand.</p>

<p>It could be as simple as ordering your morning coffee or as important as trying to convince your team that they should use a new technology. Regardless of the context, it involves restructuring your thoughts into words and metaphors that you think others can relate to in order for them to understand your concepts.</p>

<p><strong>Public speaking is a skill that is always good to improve on</strong>. Misunderstandings happen all the time, and at the heart of that is often poor communication.</p>

<p>I know people have refrained from speaking up in meetings at work, because they struggle with speaking in front of others. There’s no need for everyone to be a keynote speaker at a conference, but if it’s hindering you in your career, it may be worth practicing. Everyone should feel empowered to call a meeting, participate in discussions, or ask questions at an all hands.</p>

<h3 id="learning">Learning</h3>

<p>Another reason giving talks is 👍🏽 is that it will allow you to learn more fully. One of the best ways to learn is by <a href="http://ideas.time.com/2011/11/30/the-protege-effect/">teaching others</a>. You grasp ideas better yourself and in order to communicate them properly, you get into the habit of restructuring your ideas and concepts.</p>

<p>Unfortunately, people often also consider this the blocker to public speaking. Not only are you afraid you’ll accidentally make a fool of yourself (“what if I trip?”) but also that it will be apparent that you don’t know something well enough. The only way to get over this is by doing it.</p>

<p>Chances are that you are actually very knowledgeable in certain fields, you just perceive that as normal. “Yeah, but that’s not interesting… everyone knows about <em>that</em>”. And I can bet that, well, probably not everyone knows about that. Definitely not as much as you might actually do.</p>

<p>We all have our strengths. This is the time to play on them. We can’t be experts in both Core Image, Core Animation, and the Objective C runtime, all the while knowing everything about Swift Protocols. Pick your slice from a much wider scope. It doesn’t need to be a full framework, even just a specific use case of it, like <a href="https://realm.io/news/gwendolyn-weston-ios-background-networking/">background transfer services</a>.</p>

<p>Furthermore, see it as a learning opportunity. Speak about a topic that truly interests you and take this time to uncover things you’ve always wanted to know. It does not require you to be an expert up front — sharing knowledge gives you the chance to become one.</p>

<p>For example, I wanted to give a talk on the beauty of design and why beautiful things “just work”. I took this chance to read papers and books on the field of positive psychology and design, learning all kinds of fun new facts. Others have shared with me also that it wasn’t until they decided to write or speak about certain API that they fully got to understand all the ins and outs.</p>

<h2 id="ok-you-got-me-interested-now-what">Ok you got me interested… now what?</h2>

<p>That’s great!</p>

<p>Next you’d probably want to figure out where you’d like to speak and how to prepare a good talk. This will be covered in the next two posts, so stay tuned.</p>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
