<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: objective c | Artsy Engineering]]></title>
  <link href="http://artsy.github.io/blog/categories/objective-c/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://artsy.github.io/"/>
  <updated>2018-12-16T10:16:31+00:00</updated>
  <id>http://artsy.github.io/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Notorious BUG – The Unbugged Sessions Part 1]]></title>
    <link href="http://artsy.github.io/blog/2015/07/30/Notorious-BUG-Part-1/"/>
    <updated>2015-07-30T19:21:00+00:00</updated>
    <id>http://artsy.github.io/blog/2015/07/30/Notorious-BUG-Part-1</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>When the odds are stacked against you, your mind is overflowing, and you are ready to just pop, there’s always practical
debugging tips to help you through a cloudy day.</p>

<p>In this post I’ll take you through a debugging session where I reproduce a crash, for which we were receiving a bunch of
crash reports, but I was unable to reproduce by just using the application.</p>

<p>It will cover the following topics:</p>

<ul>
<li>Narrow down the breakpoint to the method invocation where the crash occurs.</li>
<li>Locate the exact instruction that causes the crash.</li>
<li>Look at the implementation of the method where the crash occurs.</li>
<li>Simulate the crash.</li>
</ul>


<!-- more -->


<a name="The.crash.report"></a>
<h3>The crash report</h3>

<pre><code>Hardware Model:  iPhone5,2
OS Version:      iPhone OS 8.1.2 (12B440)

Exception Type:  SIGSEGV
Exception Codes: SEGV_ACCERR at 0x10
Crashed Thread:  0

Thread 0 Crashed:
0   libobjc.A.dylib                      0x33034f46 objc_msgSend + 5
1   UIKit                                0x28d7e4bd -[UIScrollView _getDelegateZoomView] + 66
2   UIKit                                0x2599b757 -[UIScrollView _offsetForCenterOfPossibleZoomView:withIncomingBoundsSize:] + 42
[SNIP]
7   Artsy                                0x00107087 -[ARArtworkView setUpCallbacks] + 1238
[SNIP]
</code></pre>

<p><em>This crash report was shortened for clarity sake, you can find the full report
<a href="https://gist.github.com/alloy/cfaab5b754fdd2c551e0">here</a>.</em></p>

<p>Now, this might not be the toughest nut to crack –if you’ve been doing UIKit development for a while, you may already
know that <code>UIScrollView</code> does not weakify it’s <code>delegate</code>– but instead of just going by experience and making some
changes, let’s see if we can’t figure out exactly what’s happening, for the sake of reproducing and confidently making
the right fix.</p>

<p>The lines near the top of the stack trace tell me that it’s probably a message being sent to some garbage memory, i.e.
a released object, so that’s where I want to be poking around.</p>

<a name="Getting.at.often.called.locations"></a>
<h3>Getting at often called locations</h3>

<p>So I want to get at the 2nd frame in the stack, but that method and the one at the 3rd frame get invoked <em>a lot</em> while
navigating to the view I want to debug. There’s many ways to do this, but the simple approach I often take in these
cases is to set a breakpoint for the last frame in the stack that is <em>unique to the location that I want to get at</em> and
then keep refining the breakpoints every time I hit one.</p>

<p>In this case that starts off with a breakpoint in
<a href="https://github.com/artsy/eigen/blob/1.7.0/Artsy/Classes/Views/ARArtworkView.m#L85">our code</a>:</p>

<pre><code>(lldb) b -[ARArtworkView setUpCallbacks]
Breakpoint 1: where = Artsy`-[ARArtworkView setUpCallbacks] + 19 at ARArtworkView.m:101, address = 0x000000010e722853
</code></pre>

<p>With that set I then navigate to the view I want to get at and, once the breakpoint is hit, set the breakpoint for a
frame that’s even closer to the location I want to get at:</p>

<pre><code>Process 74926 stopped
* thread #1: tid = 0x1b5faf, 0x000000010e722853 Artsy`-[ARArtworkView setUpCallbacks](self=0x00007fc99c95b230, _cmd=0x000000010eb60e58) + 19 at ARArtworkView.m:101, queue = 'com.apple.main-thread', stop reason = breakpoint 1.1
    frame #0: 0x000000010e722853 Artsy`-[ARArtworkView setUpCallbacks](self=0x00007fc99c95b230, _cmd=0x000000010eb60e58) + 19 at ARArtworkView.m:101

(lldb) b -[UIScrollView _offsetForCenterOfPossibleZoomView:withIncomingBoundsSize:]
Breakpoint 2: where = UIKit`-[UIScrollView _offsetForCenterOfPossibleZoomView:withIncomingBoundsSize:], address = 0x00000001105c1fb7
</code></pre>

<p>And finally I repeat the process and set the breakpoint that I <em>really</em> want to get to:</p>

<pre><code>(lldb) b -[UIScrollView _getDelegateZoomView]
Breakpoint 3: where = UIKit`-[UIScrollView _getDelegateZoomView], address = 0x00000001105bf8cd
</code></pre>

<a name="Locating.the.instruction.that.crashes.by.looking.at.the.real..em.on-device..em..framework..iPhoneOS.SDK."></a>
<h3>Locating the instruction that crashes by looking at the real <em>on-device</em> framework (iPhoneOS SDK)</h3>

<p>By this point, I’m left with the realization that I don’t have a device running iOS 8.1.x anymore –the above was all on
the simulator– and thus jumping through the code in a debugger on a device is not going to be reliable. Instead, I’m
going to take a look at the disassembly and (pseudo) decompiled code in <a href="http://www.hopperapp.com">Hopper</a> –a tool I
highly suggest you go and buy <strong>right now</strong>, it’s ridiculously cheap for the amount of time it will save you–.</p>

<p>To be able to do so, though, I first had to get a copy of UIKit for one of the devices of which we received crash logs.</p>

<ul>
<li><p><strong>Firmware decryption keys</strong>: keys for many variants are listed
<a href="https://www.theiphonewiki.com/wiki/Firmware_Keys">here</a>. If the model you need is not listed you’ll have to manually
figure out the key, which is beyond the scope of this article.</p></li>
<li><p><strong>Download firmware</strong>: you can find links for all variants on
<a href="https://www.theiphonewiki.com/wiki/Firmware">this page</a>. I chose iOS 8.1.2 for the 2nd revision of the iPhone 5
(iPhone 5,2), because the keys to decrypt that are known and it’s one of the devices and OS versions for which we had
received crash reports.</p></li>
<li><p><strong>Decrypt image</strong>: there are a bunch of tools that allow you to decrypt firmware images, which are listed
<a href="https://www.theiphonewiki.com/wiki/Category:Decryption">here</a>. I’m using
<a href="https://www.theiphonewiki.com/wiki/Dmg_(command">xpwn’s ‘dmg’ tool</a>) which you can get from
<a href="https://github.com/planetbeing/xpwn/tree/master/dmg">planetbeing’s GitHub repo</a>. Once you’ve got the key from
<a href="https://www.theiphonewiki.com/wiki/Firmware_Keys">here</a>, or have otherwise manually figured it out, you can decrypt
the disk image like so:</p></li>
</ul>


<pre><code>$ unzip -d iPhone5,2_8.1.2 iPhone5,2_8.1.2_12B440_Restore.ipsw
$ cd iPhone5,2_8.1.2
$ /path/to/xpwn/dmg/dmg extract 058-09875-017.dmg decrypted.dmg -k 02e89744a7143b9bac48fd1adc32a8ed6bcf74d428d0861d790153accb96a413e1c3b8d8
</code></pre>

<ul>
<li><strong>Extract UIKit from shared DYLD cache</strong>: for performance reasons, Apple decided to create one big cache that
contains all of the commonly used frameworks, including UIKit. To get just UIKit, you’ll need to use any of the tools
listed <a href="http://iphonedevwiki.net/index.php/Dyld_shared_cache#Cache_extraction">here</a>, I used
<a href="https://github.com/kennytm/Miscellaneous/downloads">dyld_decache</a>:</li>
</ul>


<pre><code>$ open decrypted.dmg
$ /path/to/dyld_decache-v0.1c -o Extracted -f UIKit /Volumes/SUOkemoTaos12B440.N42OS/System/Library/Caches/com.apple.dyld/dyld_shared_cache_armv7s
$ ls -l Extracted/System/Library/Frameworks/UIKit.framework/UIKit
-rw-r--r--  1 eloy  staff  12142776 Aug  1 10:50 Extracted/System/Library/Frameworks/UIKit.framework/UIKit
</code></pre>

<p>With that out of the way, I can finally load that up in Hopper and look at the instruction. I can get the offset of
the instruction from the stack frame, specifically the ‘66’ in
<code>-[UIScrollView _getDelegateZoomView] + 66</code>. This means that the instruction’s address is that of the function it is
located in <em>plus</em> 66, which, as you can see in the below screenshot, is halfway through the <code>objc_msgSend</code> call:</p>

<p></div></div>
<a href='/images/2015-07-30-Notorious-BUG-1/Hopper-Disassembled.png'>
  <img src="/images/2015-07-30-Notorious-BUG-1/Hopper-Disassembled.png" alt="The assembly of the <code>-[UIScrollView _getDelegateZoomView]</code> method." style="">
</a>
<div class='meta-container'><header>&nbsp;</header></div><div class='content-container'><div class='entry-content'>
</p>

<p>If you want to get into the details of what these instructions are doing, I suggest you read up on a blog post such as
<a href="https://www.mikeash.com/pyblog/friday-qa-2011-12-30-disassembling-the-assembly-part-3-arm-edition.html">this article by Mike Ash</a>.
The important part here is that you can easily see that it’s all related to sending the following message to the scroll
view’s delegate:</p>

<pre><code>[delegate respondsToSelector:@selector(viewForZoomingInScrollView:)]
</code></pre>

<p>Hopper can give us (pseudo) decompiled code for this method, which looks like the following:</p>

<p></div></div>
<a href='/images/2015-07-30-Notorious-BUG-1/Hopper-Decompiled.png'>
  <img src="/images/2015-07-30-Notorious-BUG-1/Hopper-Decompiled.png" alt="The pseudo-code of the <code>-[UIScrollView _getDelegateZoomView]</code> method." style="">
</a>
<div class='meta-container'><header>&nbsp;</header></div><div class='content-container'><div class='entry-content'>
</p>

<p>Based on that, it’s clear to see that that’s what happens and so it’s the delegate that points to garbage, <code>0x10</code> in
this crash report to be specific.</p>

<a name="Simulating.the.crash"></a>
<h3>Simulating the crash</h3>

<p>Now that I know what’s happening, it’s time to simulate the crash on the Simulator so that I can confidently make the
fix for what I think is going wrong.</p>

<p>Based on the above, I now know that, on the Simulator, this crash would occur around the 16th instruction, which is
where the <code>-respondsToSelector:</code> message gets sent, so I’ll jump to just before it, but <em>after</em> where the <code>delegate</code>
variable would get set:</p>

<pre><code>(lldb) disassemble --frame
UIKit`-[UIScrollView _getDelegateZoomView]:
-&gt; 0x1105bf8cd:  pushq  %rbp
   0x1105bf8ce:  movq   %rsp, %rbp
   0x1105bf8d1:  pushq  %r15
   0x1105bf8d3:  pushq  %r14
   0x1105bf8d5:  pushq  %rbx
   0x1105bf8d6:  pushq  %rax
   0x1105bf8d7:  movq   %rdi, %r14
   0x1105bf8da:  movq   0xd344ef(%rip), %rax      ; UIScrollView._zoomView
   0x1105bf8e1:  movq   (%r14,%rax), %rbx
   0x1105bf8e5:  testq  %rbx, %rbx
   0x1105bf8e8:  jne    0x1105bf97b               ; -[UIScrollView _getDelegateZoomView] + 174
   0x1105bf8ee:  movq   0xd344c3(%rip), %r15      ; UIScrollView._delegate
   0x1105bf8f5:  movq   (%r14,%r15), %rdi
   0x1105bf8f9:  movq   0xd08228(%rip), %rdx      ; "viewForZoomingInScrollView:"
   0x1105bf900:  movq   0xd02df9(%rip), %rsi      ; "respondsToSelector:"
   0x1105bf907:  callq  *0xac2783(%rip)           ; (void *)0x0000000111fe1000: objc_msgSend
[SNIP]

(lldb) step --count 13
Process 74926 stopped
* thread #1: tid = 0x1b5faf, 0x00000001105bf8f9 UIKit`-[UIScrollView _getDelegateZoomView] + 44, queue = 'com.apple.main-thread', stop reason = instruction step into
    frame #0: 0x00000001105bf8f9 UIKit`-[UIScrollView _getDelegateZoomView] + 44
UIKit`-[UIScrollView _getDelegateZoomView] + 44:
   0x1105bf8f5:  movq   (%r14,%r15), %rdi
-&gt; 0x1105bf8f9:  movq   0xd08228(%rip), %rdx      ; "viewForZoomingInScrollView:"
   0x1105bf900:  movq   0xd02df9(%rip), %rsi      ; "respondsToSelector:"
   0x1105bf907:  callq  *0xac2783(%rip)           ; (void *)0x0000000111fe1000: objc_msgSend
   0x1105bf90d:  xorl   %ebx, %ebx
</code></pre>

<p>At this instruction, the object to which the message will be sent has been assigned to the <code>$rdi</code> register, which in my
case is still the expected and valid object:</p>

<pre><code>(lldb) po $rdi
&lt;ARArtworkViewController: 0x7fc99c9681d0&gt;
</code></pre>

<p>At this point I can just override the register with the garbage shown in the crash report:</p>

<pre><code>(lldb) register write rdi 0x10
</code></pre>

<p>And finally continue execution and let the crashing occur:</p>

<pre><code>(lldb) bt
* thread #1: tid = 0x1b5faf, 0x0000000111fe1005 libobjc.A.dylib`objc_msgSend + 5, queue = 'com.apple.main-thread', stop reason = EXC_BAD_ACCESS (code=1, address=0x10)
  * frame #0: 0x0000000111fe1005 libobjc.A.dylib`objc_msgSend + 5
    frame #1: 0x00000001105bf90d UIKit`-[UIScrollView _getDelegateZoomView] + 64
    frame #2: 0x00000001105c1fe9 UIKit`-[UIScrollView _offsetForCenterOfPossibleZoomView:withIncomingBoundsSize:] + 50
[SNIP]
    frame #7: 0x000000010e722853 Artsy`-[ARArtworkView setUpCallbacks] + 19
[SNIP]
</code></pre>

<p>💥</p>

<p>Perfect, an exact replica of the crash report, so now I know with confidence that the problem is that the
<code>ARArtworkViewController</code> is released by the time that method is called.</p>

<a name="Closing.thoughts"></a>
<h3>Closing thoughts</h3>

<p>The fix for this crash is simple and not really interesting for this post, as it’s all about the steps I took to arrive
there. I think these are way more interesting, as you can apply some/all of these in many different situations.</p>

<p>But for completeness sake, the fix is to make sure that <a href="https://github.com/artsy/eigen/blob/356b88d1ff035a9f0aa28f19e42255c7152a88f4/Artsy/View_Controllers/Artwork/ARArtworkViewController.m#L28">the scroll view’s delegate gets nillified</a>
before the view controller is released and <em>in addition</em> it lead to me figuring out why the scroll view was still even
alive at that time, which was <a href="https://github.com/artsy/eigen/commit/8db7b1e75563ee2ee7b547223cb02e1e646e7bd8">a block retention-cycle</a>.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[On Grid Thumbnails]]></title>
    <link href="http://artsy.github.io/blog/2012/09/13/on-grid-thumbnails/"/>
    <updated>2012-09-13T16:40:00+00:00</updated>
    <id>http://artsy.github.io/blog/2012/09/13/on-grid-thumbnails</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><img src="/images/2012-09-13-on-grid-thumbnails/grid.jpg"></p>

<p>Artsy Folio, our free iPad app for Gallery Partners, had been in the App Store for a couple of weeks before the iPad with a Retina display was announced. This had been something we expected internally and felt the application would be ready. We had all our image assets available in <em>@2x</em> versions and an image pipeline that would take scaling into account. With that in mind, we changed our artwork grid view to show a double resolution image. Finally, once we were happy that it worked fine on the simulator, we sent the build off to Apple for review.</p>

<p>The app passed review, and was Retina-ready before the actual release. But within hours of getting our hands on a real Retina iPad, we had to pull the app. This post will explain why, and what we did to work it out.</p>

<!--more-->


<p>Scrolling the grid view was slow. Extremely slow. The reason why wasn't obvious initially, but thanks to digging around using <a href="http://developer.apple.com/library/mac/#documentation/DeveloperTools/Conceptual/InstrumentsUserGuide/Introduction/Introduction.html">Instruments</a>, we saw that a great deal of time was spent in Apple's image processing libraries. This was a strong hint that the problem involved taking the file and getting it to the screen.</p>

<p>In our naiveté, Folio was originally using <code>UIImage</code>'s <code>initWithContentsOfFile:</code> to load (without caching) a jpg from the file system. Once the file was loaded into memory, we displayed it onscreen in an <code>UIImageView.</code> This was fast enough to deal with our small thumbnails of <em>240x240</em> but the moment that you start asking it to pull 3 or 4 <em>480x480</em> jpg files off the filesystem, decompress them and then put them on the screen, you're not going to have a smooth scroll.</p>

<p><img src="/images/2012-09-13-on-grid-thumbnails/thumbnails.jpg"></p>

<p>As we knew that we were looking at an issue with getting images from a file, it made sense to start looking at ways to move image processing off the main thread. This Stack Overflow thread on <a href="http://stackoverflow.com/questions/1815476/cgimage-uiimage-lazily-loading-on-ui-thread-causes-stutter">UIImage lazy loading</a> proved to be an essential start to dealing with our issue. We needed a thread-safe way to get the contents of a file and to pass them through once the images had been decoded. What we needed was <a href="https://gist.github.com/3715588">initImmediateLoadWithContentsOfFile</a>, a thread-safe way to go from a filepath to a <code>UIImage</code>.</p>

<p>Now that we had a way to get an image that was safe to go on a background thread, we gave our grid an <code>NSOperationQueue</code> and created a method to kick off a <code>NSInvocationOperation</code> with our the cell we're looking at and the address it needs to load the thumbnail.</p>

<pre><code class="objc">- (void)setImageAsyncAtPath:(NSString *)imageAddress forGridCell:(ARImageGridViewCell *)cell {
    NSDictionary *operationOptions = @{@"address": imageAddress, @"cell": cell};
    NSInvocationOperation *operation = [[NSInvocationOperation alloc] initWithTarget:self selector:@selector(asyncLoadImage:) object:operationOptions];

    [_operationQueue addOperation:operation];
}
</code></pre>

<p>When we had the simplest implementation of <code>asyncLoadImage</code> we found that scrolling would sometimes result in grid cells displaying the wrong image. It turned out that in the time it took to decode the jpg,  the cell had already been reused for a different artwork. This one totally caught us off guard!</p>

<pre><code class="objc">- (void)asyncLoadImage:(NSDictionary *)options {
    @autoreleasepool {
        NSString *address = options[@"address"];
        ARImageGridViewCell *cell = options[@"cell"];

        // don't load if it's on a different cell
        if ([cell.imagePath isEqualToString:address]) {
            UIImage *thumbnail = [[UIImage alloc] initImmediateLoadWithContentsOfFile:address];

            // double check that during the decoding the cell's not been re-used
            if ([cell.imagePath isEqualToString:address] &amp;&amp; thumbnail) {
                [cell performSelectorOnMainThread:@selector(setImage:) withObject:thumbnail waitUntilDone:NO];
            }
        }
    }
}
</code></pre>

<p>This meant we could have our UI thread dealing with scrolling, whilst <a href="https://developer.apple.com/technologies/mac/core.html">Grand Central Dispatch</a> would deal with ensuring the image processing was done asynchronously and as fast as possible.However, this still wasn't enough. We were finding if you scrolled fast enough, you could still see images pop in after the grid cell was visible. For this, we actually went back to the beginning, and made our image pipeline create a <em>120x120</em> thumbnail for each artwork that we use <code>initImmediateLoadWithContentsOfFile</code> to load on the UI thread. This is fast enough to smoothly scroll, and is replaced by the higher resolution image practically instantly.</p>

<p><img src="/images/2012-09-13-on-grid-thumbnails/hover-thumbnails.jpg"></p>

<p>The rest of the story is pretty straightforward. We wrapped all this up within a few days and got out a version of Folio for the Retina iPad, I ended up doing a talk about the issues involved in doing this in <a href="http://lsx.co/lsxcafe/">Leeds LSxCafé</a>, and you got a blog post out of it.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[On Our Objective-C Code Standards]]></title>
    <link href="http://artsy.github.io/blog/2012/08/14/on-objective-c-code-standards/"/>
    <updated>2012-08-14T14:23:00+00:00</updated>
    <id>http://artsy.github.io/blog/2012/08/14/on-objective-c-code-standards</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>With the release of Xcode 4.4 I've taken a look back at our existing code standards and tried to come up with something that is cleaner and more elegant. Here are a few of the ideas I've been using to modernize the codebase.</p>

<a name="Remove.private.method.declarations.and.use.class.extensions.to.add.ivars."></a>
<h3>Remove private method declarations and use class extensions to add ivars.</h3>

<p>First to get chopped by the deletion button are private method declarations. After Xcode 4.2 came out we took to using the class extension feature to add private method declarations at the top of implementation files. This was a nice way of keeping private methods out of the header files. Now that the compiler will check for pre-existing method signatures within the same object there's no need to define their interfaces.</p>

<!--more-->


<p>Occasionally it's necessary for subclass to know about private methods defined by its superclass, so we use a shared category to let them know what they respond to. Like Apple, we also quit using <code>@private</code> in header files.</p>

<p>Ivars now should go in class extensions, and be prefixed by an underscore. Apple advises that you don't use method names with underscores but encourage underscored variable names. This also can free up method parameters from having ugly names such as anArtwork or aString.</p>

<a name="Use.object.literals.when.possible."></a>
<h3>Use object literals when possible.</h3>

<p>Object literals are ways of adding syntacitcal sugar to the Objective-C language, they let you access keys and values easily on <code>NSDictionary</code>s and objects in <code>NSArray</code>s. There's no reason to not be using them if you're supporting iOS 4 and above. It's simple a matter of <code>_artworks[2]</code> vs <code>[_artworks objectAtIndex:2]</code>.</p>

<a name="Dot.syntax.is.OK.for.non-properties."></a>
<h3>Dot syntax is OK for non-properties.</h3>

<p>OK so, I admit it. I whined when properties came out. It was back in 2007 and the Objective-C was ranked 40th in the world, it's now ranked <a href="http://www.tiobe.com/index.php/paperinfo/tpci/Objective-C.html">3nd most popular programming language.</a> Within timeframe, my opinion on the subject of properties changed also.</p>

<p>Originally when properties came out they exclusively were given the right to use dot notation on objects. This makes sense as they were created to provide public access to ivars which normally you can only access internally using the dot notation. With Xcode 4.3, that also changed. Now, if a method doesn't have any arguments it can be called using dot notation. I'm in favour of using this. For me a good rule of thumb has been if a method returns something, dot notation is OK. For example, <code>_artworksArray.count</code> is fine whilst <code>_parsingOperation.stop</code> isn't.</p>

<a name="Keep.external.code.out.of.your.project."></a>
<h3>Keep external code out of your project.</h3>

<p>External, or vendored code should be kept out of the main body of your code. You can use CocoaPods to keep all that code in check and up-to-date. CocoaPods is a project that aims to be what bundler does for ruby projects, or npm for node. It will deal with your dependancies whilst you can concentrate on your own code. It will create a seperate Xcode project that handles all you dependancies leaving your project only as your own code.</p>

<a name="Use.umbrella.imports."></a>
<h3>Use umbrella imports.</h3>

<p>To try and keep the amount of noise we have at the top of our implementation files we have started to reduce the number of <code>#import "ARModel.h"</code> lines we use. By creating a <code>Models.h</code> file and having that include all the models it means we can still have a look through the <code>#imports</code> at the top to get an idea of the connections between the objects as that will only show the important imports. These can optionally be moved into your precompiled header files.</p>

<a name="Keep.your.code.clean."></a>
<h3>Keep your code clean.</h3>

<p>Whitespace can and does slowly accumulate at the line-endings of your code. You should make sure that the new preference for automatically trimming whitespace is turned on in the text editing section of Xcode's preferences.</p>

<a name="IBOutlets.should.probably.go.in.your.class.extensions."></a>
<h3>IBOutlets should probably go in your class extensions.</h3>

<p>With modern versions of Xcode, it doesn't matter that your IBOutlets are defined in places other than in headers. As Objective-C developers, we've come a long way from having to repeatedly drag a .h from Xcode to Interface Builder, so maybe it's time to rethink the idea that our interface outlets should be publicly accessible. My opinion is that a controller's views are for the most part a private affair and that if you want to expose their functionality you do it through custom methods in the controller. There are some downsides to this, in that  initially you have to change to the implementation file when using hybrid view when connecting them.</p>

<p>These decisions have come from internal discussions and from watching many WWDC sessions on the topic. We highly recommend watching the following <a href="https://developer.apple.com/wwdc/">WWDC sessions</a>.</p>

<p>  <a href="https://developer.apple.com/videos/wwdc/2011/">WWDC 2011</a>: 105 Polishing Your App, 112 Writing Easy To Change Code and 322 - Objective-C Advancements in Depth.</p>

<p>  <a href="https://developer.apple.com/videos/wwdc/2012/">WWDC 2012</a>: 405 Modern Objective-C and 413 Migrating to Modern Objective-C</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
