<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: graphql | Artsy Engineering]]></title>
  <link href="http://artsy.github.io/blog/categories/graphql/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://artsy.github.io/"/>
  <updated>2018-12-16T10:16:31+00:00</updated>
  <id>http://artsy.github.io/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[GraphQL Stitching 101]]></title>
    <link href="http://artsy.github.io/blog/2018/12/11/GraphQL-Stitching/"/>
    <updated>2018-12-11T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <id>http://artsy.github.io/blog/2018/12/11/GraphQL-Stitching</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Micro-Services make sense. You can scope a domain of your business to particular small unit of abstraction like an
API. Doing so makes it easy to work in isolation, experiment with new ideas and evolve in many directions.</p>

<p>We've been <a href="http://artsy.github.io/blog/2017/04/14/artsy-technology-stack-2017/#Artsy.Technology.Infrastructure.2017.-.Splitting.the.Monolith">carefully pushing</a> for years to move away from our single monolithic API, to a collection of
smaller, more focused projects. Our <a href="https://github.com/artsy/README/blob/master/culture/highlights.md#highlights">highlights docs</a> showcase this well. The movement to smaller composable
services works great from an isolated platform/systems perspective but can be a bit tricky to handle with front-end
clients. Until 2018, the way that we've addressed the growing complexity in our service later has been to migrate
the complexity inside our main GraphQL API, <a href="https://github.com/artsy/metaphysics/">metaphysics</a>. Metaphysics is our GraphQL API gateway that
consolidates many API sources into a single service, then extending and interleaving and their data to make clients
easier to write.</p>

<p>However, as more services have been created, and grown - so has metaphysics. This creates a worrying trend, as the
growth of code in metaphysics isn't quite linear.</p>

<p>Our main line-of-thought on how to address this is via GraphQL schema stitching. We've been <a href="https://github.com/artsy/metaphysics/pull/809">running
experiments</a> in stitching for over a year, and have have been running with stitching enabled in production for
a few months.</p>

<!-- more -->


<a name="What.is.Schema.Stitching."></a>
<h2>What is Schema Stitching?</h2>

<p>The core idea behind schema stitching is that because GraphQL talks in type systems, you should be able to merge
type systems from many GraphQL APIs into a single source of truth. Schema stitching came out at the <a href="https://dev-blog.apollodata.com/graphql-tools-2-0-with-schema-stitching-8944064904a5">end of
2017</a> via the <a href="https://github.com/apollographql/graphql-tools/"><code>graphql-tools</code></a> and became production-<a href="https://dev-blog.apollodata.com/the-next-generation-of-schema-stitching-2716b3b259c0">ready in April
2018</a>.</p>

<p>We started experimenting on staging last year and would occasionally run into edge-case issues. This meant the
state of the project would ebb &amp; flow between being blocked, or no-one having the bandwidth to work on it. This was
fine, because our aim was <a href="https://github.com/artsy/README/blob/master/culture/engineering-principles.md#incremental-revolution">incremental evolutions over bold revolution</a>.</p>

<p>Before we dive into implementation details, here's a quick glossary of terms before we start:</p>

<ul>
<li><strong>GraphQL <a href="https://graphql.org/learn/schema/#type-system">Type</a></strong> - the shape of an object exposed from your GraphQL API</li>
<li><strong>GraphQL Schema</strong> - a representation of your GraphQL's type system, containing all types and fields on them</li>
<li><strong>GraphQL Resolver</strong> - every field accessed in a query resolves to a corresponding value, the function doing that
is a resolver</li>
<li><strong>Schema Merging</strong> - taking two GraphQL schemas, and merging all the types and resolvers into one schema</li>
<li><strong>Schema Stitching</strong> - extending a GraphQL Schema programmatically, with the ability to delegate to merged
schemas</li>
</ul>


<p>Stitching is one of the end-goals, but merging may be enough for a lot of cases. Both of the two launch posts above
give a much more in-depth explanation of how everything comes together, but these should be enough for this post.</p>

<a name="How.Do.We.Do.It."></a>
<h2>How Do We Do It?</h2>

<p>We have 5 GraphQL APIs inside the Artsy ecosystem, our aim is to cautiously include these APIs inside metaphysics.
We don't need the entire contents of those APIs, and as you'll learn - we couldn't do that even if we wanted.</p>

<p>The technique we settled on was:</p>

<ol>
<li>Download the schema of each external API into metaphysics' source code</li>
<li>Have each schema trimmed to just the essentials that we need today</li>
<li>Merge in each schema incrementally</li>
<li>Stitch in any desired schema changes</li>
</ol>


<p>Let's dig, with some code into how we do each of these steps.</p>

<a name="Downloading.Schemas"></a>
<h4>Downloading Schemas</h4>

<p>We created a <a href="https://github.com/artsy/metaphysics/blob/1423ee39f8e348805710080a4857e6575d3ddade/scripts/dump-remote-schema.js#L15-L25">pretty minimal script</a> which can be run periodically from a developer's computer.</p>

<pre><code class="js">const destination = "src/data"

const httpConvectionLink = createHttpLink({
  fetch,
  uri: urljoin("https://convection-staging.artsy.net/api", "graphql")
})

introspectSchema(httpConvectionLink).then(schema =&gt; {
  fs.writeFileSync(
    path.join(destination, "convection.graphql"),
    printSchema(schema, { commentDescriptions: true })
  )
})
</code></pre>

<p>The script uses an <a href="https://www.apollographql.com/docs/link/links/http.html">apollo-http-link</a> to grab our schema, and store it in our repo, see
<a href="https://github.com/artsy/metaphysics/blob/master/src/data/convection.graphql"><code>src/data/convection.graphql</code></a>. This means that when someone wants to update to a new version of the
schema, it will go through code review and a normal testing-flow. The trade-off being that it will always be out of
date a little bit, but you can make guarantees about the current schema. This is a reasonable trade-off, as GraphQL
schemas <a href="https://graphql.org/learn/best-practices/#versioninghttps://graphql.org/learn/best-practices/#versioning">should always</a> be forward compatible for queries, and when someone wants to use a new field from another
service they can move the schema definition from <a href="https://github.com/artsy/README/issues/31">the git repo</a>.</p>

<p>This file is the <a href="https://blog.graph.cool/graphql-sdl-schema-definition-language-6755bcb9ce51">GraphQL SDL</a> representations of the entire type system for that schema. This means we have a
local copy of the schemas, so we can use it for tests for the next few steps.</p>

<a name="Schema.Manipulation"></a>
<h4>Schema Manipulation</h4>

<p>Each API writes for their own domain. This can be problematic when you use a <code>User</code> in one API, which isn't generic
enough to be a <code>User</code> in a global API of all services combined. When thinking about this problem, we created a
<a href="https://github.com/artsy/README/blob/master/playbooks/graphql-schema-design.md#notes">guide for ourselves</a> on how to think about schema design at local and global level.</p>

<p>We use a few of <a href="https://www.apollographql.com/docs/graphql-tools/schema-transforms.html">the transform APIs</a> available in graphql-tools to make the merges work. The first
approach is to force a namespace by prefixing the merged Types with their domain.</p>

<pre><code class="js">export const executableConvectionSchema = async () =&gt; {
  const convectionLink = createConvectionLink()
  const convectionTypeDefs = readFileSync("src/data/convection.graphql", "utf8")

  // Setup the default Schema
  const schema = await makeRemoteExecutableSchema({
    schema: convectionTypeDefs,
    link: convectionLink
  })

  // Remap the names of certain types from Convection to fit in the larger
  // metaphysics ecosystem.
  const remap = {
    Submission: "ConsignmentSubmission",
    Category: "ConsignmentSubmissionCategoryAggregation",
    Asset: "ConsignmentSubmissionCategoryAsset",
    State: "ConsignmentSubmissionStateAggregation",
    SubmissionConnection: "ConsignmentSubmissionConnection"
  }

  // Return the new modified schema
  return transformSchema(schema, [
    new RenameTypes(name =&gt; {
      const newName = remap[name] || name
      return newName
    })
  ])
}
</code></pre>

<p>Another example is to outright remove almost everything in the schema, and to only allow Types and fields which we
know to be useful.</p>

<pre><code class="js">export const executableGravitySchema = async () =&gt; {
  const gravityTypeDefs = readFileSync("src/data/gravity.graphql", "utf8")

  const gravityLink = createGravityLink()
  const schema = await makeRemoteExecutableSchema({
    schema: gravityTypeDefs,
    link: gravityLink,
  })

  // Types which come from Gravity which MP already has copies of.
  // In the future, these could get merged into the MP types.
  const blacklistedTypes = ["Artist", "Artwork"]

  // Gravity's GraphQL contains a bunch of objects and root fields that will conflict
  // with what we have in MP already, this lets us bring them in one by one
  const whitelistedRootFields = ["Query", "recordArtworkView"]

  // Return the new modified schema
  return transformSchema(schema, [
    new FilterRootFields((_type, name) =&gt; {
      return !whitelistedRootFields.includes(name)
    }),
    new FilterTypes(type =&gt; {
      return !blacklistedTypes.includes(type.name)
    }),
    // snip
  ])
})
</code></pre>

<p>We can write tests for this by running <a href="https://github.com/artsy/metaphysics/blob/1423ee39f8e348805710080a4857e6575d3ddade/src/lib/stitching/lib/getTypesFromSchema.ts">a query which returns all of the types</a> in a schema, and validating
what exists:</p>

<pre><code class="js">import { executableGravitySchema } from "../schema"
import { getTypesFromSchema } from "lib/stitching/lib/getTypesFromSchema"

it("Does not include blacklisted types", async () =&gt; {
  const gravitySchema = await executableGravitySchema()
  const gravityTypes = await getTypesFromSchema(gravitySchema)

  expect(gravityTypes).not.toContain("Artist")
  expect(gravityTypes).not.toContain("Artwork")
})
</code></pre>

<p>This one is interesting, we <em>don't</em> want the version of <code>Artist</code> and <code>Artwork</code> from Gravity's GraphQL
implementation - because the hand-rolled <code>Artwork</code> and <code>Artist</code> types which lives in the source code of Metaphysics
right now is a combination of many sources, and front-end-client specific code.</p>

<p>If we allowed the <code>Artist</code> or <code>Artwork</code> to overwrite the existing implementations it would be a massively breaking
change. For example, compare the Artwork type from <a href="https://github.com/artsy/metaphysics/blob/51939d1f8eb0d5a60e6e888bf701e082a9ee3731/src/data/gravity.graphql#L14-L29">Gravity's GraphQL</a> (5 fields) vs <a href="https://github.com/artsy/metaphysics/blob/51939d1f8eb0d5a60e6e888bf701e082a9ee3731/_schema.graphql#L723-L889">Metaphysics'
GraphQL</a> (~90 fields) accidentally switching the types would cripple our front-ends.</p>

<a name="Merging.Schemas"></a>
<h4>Merging Schemas</h4>

<p>There are two classes of schemas involved in our stitching. Local Schemas, which is our existing schema (e.g. the
resolver live inside the current source code), and Remote Schemas (e.g. where you make an API request to run those
resolvers). <a href="https://github.com/artsy/metaphysics/blob/1423ee39f8e348805710080a4857e6575d3ddade/src/lib/stitching/mergeSchemas.ts#L9-L39">Merging a schema</a> has a pretty small API surface and doesn't mind which type of schemas you
merge together.</p>

<pre><code class="js">import { mergeSchemas as _mergeSchemas } from "graphql-tools"
import { executableGravitySchema } from "lib/stitching/gravity/schema"
import { executableConvectionSchema } from "lib/stitching/convection/schema"
import { executableLewittSchema } from "lib/stitching/lewitt/schema"

import localSchema from "../../schema"

export const mergeSchemas = async () =&gt; {
  const convectionSchema = await executableConvectionSchema()
  const gravitySchema = await executableGravitySchema()

  const mergedSchema = _mergeSchemas({
    schemas: [gravitySchema, localSchema, convectionSchema]
  })

  return mergedSchema
}
</code></pre>

<p>It's a pretty simple composition model, makes it real easy to do some verification tests using the same techniques
as above.</p>

<a name="Stitching.Schemas"></a>
<h4>Stitching Schemas</h4>

<p>The next step from merging is stitching. Stitching is about taking the merged schemas and taking data from one and
re-applying it via another API. For example, we have a consignments API (for when you want to sell a work at
auction) and a consignment references the artwork's artist. These live inside an API called convection.</p>

<p>In this case, the consignment has an <code>artist_id</code> which represents an <code>Artist</code> type which lives in metaphysics. We
would like to stitch an Artist in from the local schema, into a <code>ConsignmentSubmission</code> which has come in from a
remote schema.</p>

<p>The API works by using <a href="https://github.com/graphql/graphql-js/pull/1117">Type Extensions</a> which are a way of opening up an existing Type and adding new fields
on it. We want to be working with the highest level abstraction, which in this case is directly writing <a href="https://blog.graph.cool/graphql-sdl-schema-definition-language-6755bcb9ce51">GraphQL
SDL</a> (basically writing the interface) and then hooking that up to its resolvers.</p>

<p>Here's what that looks like in our app:</p>

<pre><code class="js">export const consignmentStitchingEnvironment = (
  localSchema: GraphQLSchema,
  convectionSchema: GraphQLSchema
) =&gt; ({
  // The SDL used to declare how to stitch an object
  extensionSchema: `
    extend type ConsignmentSubmission {
      artist: Artist
    }
  `,

  // Resolvers which correspond to the above type extension
  resolvers: {
    ConsignmentSubmission: {
      artist: {
        // The required query to get access to the object, e.g. we have to
        // request `artist_id` on a ConsignmentSubmission in order to access the artist
        // at all
        fragment: `fragment SubmissionArtist on ConsignmentSubmission { artist_id }`,
        // The function to handle getting the Artist data correctly, we
        // use the root query `artist(id: id)` to grab the data from the local
        // metaphysics schema
        resolve: (parent, _args, context, info) =&gt; {
          const id = parent.artist_id
          return info.mergeInfo.delegateToSchema({
            schema: localSchema,
            operation: "query",
            fieldName: "artist",
            args: {
              id,
            },
            context,
            info,
            transforms: (convectionSchema as any).transforms,
          })
        },
      },
    },
  },
})
</code></pre>

<p>This file consolidates the two steps of merging and then stitching:</p>

<pre><code class="diff">export const mergeSchemas = async () =&gt; {
  const convectionSchema = await executableConvectionSchema()
+ const convectionStitching = consignmentStitchingEnvironment(localSchema, convectionSchema)

  const gravitySchema = await executableGravitySchema()

  // The order should only matter in that extension schemas come after the
  // objects that they are expected to build upon
  const mergedSchema = _mergeSchemas({
    schemas: [
      gravitySchema,
      localSchema,
      convectionSchema,
+      convectionStitching.extensionSchema,
+    ],
+    resolvers: {
+      ...convectionStitching.resolvers,
+    },
  })

  return mergedSchema
}
</code></pre>

<p>We extend the merge schema function to also include the SDL for our stitching, and de-structure in the extension
resolvers. We're still exploring how to write <em>useful</em> tests for this part.</p>

<a name="Validating.your.changes"></a>
<h2>Validating your changes</h2>

<p>We had some useful tools which were used to make the switch to using schema-stitching in production.</p>

<ol>
<li><p><strong>Stored Queries</strong></p>

<p>In order to validate that the runtime behavior of our queries wasn't changing, we used the <a href="https://github.com/artsy/emission/pull/999">persistent
queries</a> generated by our iOS app Emission to create JSON dumps of the results of many API calls in both
stitched and un-stitched environments in a script and compared the results.</p></li>
<li><p><strong>SDL dump comparison</strong></p>

<p>We can use the GraphQL type system to validate our changes don't break clients. We used a schema dump script to
validate the type system was the same across stitched and un-stitched environments.</p></li>
</ol>


<a name="Alternatives"></a>
<h2>Alternatives</h2>

<p>Our stitching implementation used metaphysics as a local schema - e.g. the merging and the stitching occurred
inside the same source code as our main GraphQL API. This wasn't the only way we cold achieve a single source of
truth, I explored an alternative which is to treat all schemas as remote schemas. Basically having an API gateway
in-front of our API gateway. I called it <a href="https://github.com/orta/incorporeal">incorporeal</a>, it's actually a tiny amount of code - a testament to
modern GraphQL techniques in JavaScript.</p>

<p>The advantage here is that we take reduce the acceleration of growing complexity in Metaphysics completely, because
the merging and stitching occurs outside of it. Metaphysics is merged and stitched in, just as all our other APIs
are.</p>

<p>The downside is that it's another hop to get what you want, and changes could require being updated in more places.
We'd be able to use the above ideas for validating that the API is working as expected.</p>

<a name="In.Production"></a>
<h2>In Production</h2>

<p>Today we stitch all new APIs by default, see <a href="https://github.com/artsy/metaphysics/pull/1327">Kaws' integration</a> PR. We're <em>slowly</em> trying to retro-actively
migrate existing APIs into stitching and then deleting the existing code, but that's real tricky when those APIs
are being used or use advanced features of GraphQL.</p>

<p>We've been using GraphQL <a href="https://github.com/artsy/metaphysics/commit/50b23f1738b9fa9757ff83c2d1e0d265c70e4e90">since mid-2015</a> and we've also used it with Relay for the past two years, this has
meant we have quite a few interesting edge cases in our use of the GraphQL. We got in touch with <a href="https://www.freiksenet.com">Mikhail
Novikov</a> and he contracted to help us with most of these issues and I'd strongly recommend doing the same (with
any OSS dependency, but that's, like, just my opinion man.)</p>

<p>GraphQL Stitching solves the problem of API consolidation in a really well thought out abstraction, and I consider
it one of the most interesting avenues of exploration into what GraphQL will be in the future (see <a href="http://artsy.github.io/blog/2018/05/08/is-graphql-the-future/">Is GraphQL The
Future?</a> for a more philosophical take also.)</p>

<!-- prettier-ignore-start -->




<!-- prettier-ignore-end -->

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Where art thou, my error?]]></title>
    <link href="http://artsy.github.io/blog/2018/10/19/where-art-thou-my-error/"/>
    <updated>2018-10-19T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <id>http://artsy.github.io/blog/2018/10/19/where-art-thou-my-error</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><em>Note: This is the text of a presentation given at <a href="https://graphql-finland.fi">GraphQL Finland 2018</a>, as such the
language may in some cases be slightly awkward for a blog post. You can find those slides on
<a href="https://speakerdeck.com/alloy/where-art-thou-my-error">Speaker Deck</a>.</em></p>

<p>GraphQL is still in its early stages and thus these are very exciting times, indeed! Traditionally the GraphQL team
has taken the approach of defining the bare minimum in the specification that was deemed needed and otherwise
letting the community come-up with defining problems and experimenting with solutions for those. One such example
is how metadata about the location in the graph where errors occurred during execution were <a href="https://github.com/facebook/graphql/pull/230">added to the
specification</a>.</p>

<p>This is great in the sense that we still have the ability, as a community, to shape the future of a GraphQL
specification that we all <em>want</em> to use, but on the other hand it also means that we may need to spend significant
amounts of time on thinking about these problems and iterating. Seeing as we all strive to have backwards
compatible schemas, it’s of great importance that we know of the various iterations that people have experimented
with and what the outcome was.</p>

<p>This is our story of thinking about and working with errors, thus far.</p>

<!-- more -->


<p>NOTE: Throughout this talk I’ll use ‘query execution’ to indicate executing a GraphQL document, be it a query or
mutation operation. I have a hard time relating to ‘document execution’, mostly because I don’t see others using
it, but perhaps I’ve just missed it. Come at me, at the bar, and set me straight!</p>

<a name="Errors.vs.errors"></a>
<h2>Errors vs errors</h2>

<p>First of all, I want to take a step back and talk about errors in general. The nomenclature around these can get
confusing, suffice to say that during this session we’ll talk about these two types:</p>

<ul>
<li><p>Errors that occur during query execution, that were unexpected, and <em>could</em> lead to corrupted data. We’ll refer
to these as (top-level) ‘GraphQL errors’, going forward.</p>

<p>These could be due to hardware failures, such as running out of memory or disk space, network failures, or
unexpected upstream data etc.</p>

<p>When these occur, <code>graphql-js</code> will return <code>null</code> for the field that triggered the error and serialize the error
into the top-level <code>errors</code> list, next to the successful response <code>data</code>. (Presumably other implementations
follow this reference implementation.)</p></li>
</ul>


<pre><code class="json">{
  "data": {
    "artwork": {
      "artist": {
        "name": "Vincent van Gogh",
        "leftEarSize": null
      }
    }
  },
  "errors": [
    {
      "message": "An unexpected error occurred",
      "path": ["artwork", "artist", "leftEarSize"]
    }
  ]
}
</code></pre>

<ul>
<li><p>Exceptions to these are errors that are <em>known</em> to occur and are expected to be handled by the user of an API.
We’ll refer to these as ‘exceptions’, going forward.</p>

<p>By default these are treated equally by <code>graphql-js</code> to top-level GraphQL errors, if uncaught.</p></li>
</ul>


<p>We will <strong>not</strong> be speaking about errors that occur <em>outside</em> of query execution, such as network failures reaching
the GraphQL server, parsing a syntactically incorrect document, or passing variables that don’t satisfy the
type-system; as these will all lead to a query being rejected wholesale and are solve-able using traditional means,
such as a <code>4xx</code> HTTP status code or <code>5xx</code> in some cases.</p>

<a name="What.is.the.problem.we...re.trying.to.solve."></a>
<h2>What is the problem we’re trying to solve?</h2>

<p>Because with GraphQL we’re usually requesting data for multiple resources, there may be a situation where some
fields resolve successfully and some may fail. This is also why, when using an HTTP transport layer, the advice is
to always respond with a HTTP 200 (ok) status. Determining how to process the response is left up to the client.</p>

<p>So how <em>do</em> we model errors in such a way that they can be meaningful and in context of their origin?</p>

<ul>
<li><p>What if you want to render partial data?</p>

<ul>
<li><p>Maybe the failed data is unrelated to other components that you were also requesting data for.</p>

<p><img src="/images/2018-10-19-where-art-thou-my-error/partial-data-unrelated-annotated.png" alt="Unrelated component" /></p></li>
<li><p>Or the data that failed was part of a list and other entries can still be rendered just fine.</p>

<p><img src="/images/2018-10-19-where-art-thou-my-error/partial-data-list-annotated.png" alt="Partial list data" /></p></li>
</ul>
</li>
<li><p>Or what if you’d (additionally) like to communicate the error in your interface?</p>

<ul>
<li><p>When the query is in response to a mutation and you’d like to communicate input validation failures.</p>

<p><img src="/images/2018-10-19-where-art-thou-my-error/mutation-validation-error.png" alt="Surface validation error" /></p></li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>


<a name="Possible.solutions"></a>
<h2>Possible solutions</h2>

<a name="Top-level.GraphQL.errors.and.treating.an.entire.response.as.unusable.when.such.errors.exist"></a>
<h3>Top-level GraphQL errors and treating an entire response as unusable when such errors exist</h3>

<p>Some clients, such as Apollo and Relay Classic, have made the decision to reject a response entirely, by default,
if any top-level GraphQL errors exist. This is because clients can really only fully assume that the response data
is incomplete, not whether or not your application could handle that case.</p>

<p>This may be an ok solution when you’re starting out or all the requested data is part of a single holistic view,
but it quickly breaks down when you want a little more than that.</p>

<a name="Top-level.GraphQL.errors.with.extra.metadata"></a>
<h3>Top-level GraphQL errors with extra metadata</h3>

<p>GraphQL errors only have a single field in <a href="https://facebook.github.io/graphql/draft/#sec-Errors">the specification</a> to provide context around the cause of
the error, which is the <code>message</code> field. However, <a href="https://facebook.github.io/graphql/draft/#sec-Response-Format">the specification</a> also defines a top-level
<code>extensions</code> key, which may hold a map of freeform data for the schema implementors to extend the protocol however
they see fit.</p>

<p>Apollo Server 2.0, for instance, <a href="https://blog.apollographql.com/full-stack-error-handling-with-graphql-apollo-5c12da407210">introduced standardized errors</a> you can throw from your
resolvers, which end up being serialized into the <code>extensions</code> map. An example they give is for bad user input:</p>

<pre><code class="js">import { UserInputError } from "apollo-server"

const resolvers = {
  Query: {
    events(root, { zipCode }) {
      // do custom validation for user inputs
      const validationErrors = {}
      if (!isValidZipCode(zipCode)) {
        validationErrors.zipCode = "This is not a valid zipcode"
      }
      if (Object.keys(validationErrors).length &gt; 0) {
        throw new UserInputError("Failed to get events due to validation errors", { validationErrors })
      }
      // actually query events here and return successfully
      return getEventsByZipcode(zipCode)
    }
  }
}
</code></pre>

<p>Seeing as these extensions are freeform, however, this builds an <strong>implicit</strong> contract between the server and
client that then needs to be abstracted away by additional client code. This is unfortunate, when you think about
it, because GraphQL is meant to explicitly express shapes of data.</p>

<p>The Apollo team acknowledges this by adding:</p>

<blockquote><p>While convenient, the weakness of this approach is that the format of the validation error messages is not
captured by your schema, making it brittle to changes. Unless you maintain tight control of both server and
client, you should keep the error responses as simple as possible.</p>

<p>For mutations, it can be worthwhile defining these validation errors as first class citizens within your schema.</p></blockquote>

<p>(Which we’ll address next.)</p>

<a name="Make..mutation..error.metadata.part.of.schema.as.separate.fields"></a>
<h3>Make (mutation) error metadata part of schema as separate fields</h3>

<p>One <a href="https://www.apollographql.com/docs/guides/schema-design.html#mutation-responses">commonly suggested approach</a> around mutations is to define status metadata on the
response type next to the field of the affected entity. For example, a response type could look like:</p>

<pre><code>type UpdateArtworkMutationResponse {
  success: Boolean!
  message: String!
  artwork: Artwork
}
</code></pre>

<p>Here there’s a boolean that indicates success, an extra message that sheds context on the situation when a failure
occurs, and finally the <code>artwork</code> that an update was attempted to be made to.</p>

<p>Adding these fields to the same namespace makes sense when we’re thinking of the failure case, but what about the
success case? Do we really need a <code>success</code> boolean to indicate that updates to the <code>artwork</code> were made? What
purpose serves the <code>message</code> field, other than possibly being a sign of an overly positive schema that sends you
happy messages?</p>

<p>Finally, this approach only really works for mutations, as their return type acts as a distinct root type to start
a query from. It would be hard to imagine how to apply this to queries.</p>

<a name="Make.error.metadata.part.of.schema.as.separate.field"></a>
<h3>Make error metadata part of schema as separate field</h3>

<p>Similarly, <a href="https://itnext.io/the-definitive-guide-to-handling-graphql-errors-e0c58b52b5e1">another suggested approach</a> is to add an additional <code>error</code> field to the type in
question, which then describes the error that occurred. The previous example could be rewritten like so:</p>

<pre><code>type GenericError {
  message: String!
}

type UpdateArtworkMutationResponse {
  error: GenericError
  artwork: Artwork
}
</code></pre>

<p>If <code>error</code> is not <code>null</code>, something went wrong. This cleans up the namespace a bit, but more importantly this
approach can be applied to queries too:</p>

<pre><code>type PublishedArtworkNotification {
  artwork: Artwork
}

type PublishedArtworkNotificationsPayload {
  error: GenericError
  notifications: [PublishedArtworkNotification]
}

type Query {
  publishedArtworkNotificationsPayload: PublishedArtworkNotificationsPayload!
}
</code></pre>

<p>Neat.</p>

<p>However, and this may just be our use-case, we don’t have partial data at these stages. We’ve either resolved the
data or we have an error. Hence, this approach would mean we’d always have an unneeded <code>null</code> field, which pollutes
the namespace of the type unnecessarily.</p>

<p>Side-note: if you don’t control the server schema, and are using a client that can extend a server schema on the
client, you could try to retrofit top-level GraphQL errors to these suggested error fields into the schema where
they occurred based on the error <code>path</code>, as shown <a href="https://github.com/facebook/relay/issues/1913#issuecomment-358636018">here</a>.</p>

<a name="Recap"></a>
<h2>Recap</h2>

<p>So to quickly recap, ideally we want a solution to:</p>

<ul>
<li>Use GraphQL: Utilize GraphQL to explicitly describe the error data.</li>
<li>In context: Present the error data exactly where the error occurred in the schema.</li>
<li>All operations: Work for both mutations and queries.</li>
<li>Explicit status: Be concise and encourage ‘clean’ types; that is, no pollution of namespaces with fields only
needed in some cases.</li>
</ul>


<a name="Make.exceptions.first-class.citizens.of.your.schema"></a>
<h3>Make exceptions first-class citizens of your schema</h3>

<p>To that end, the final approach we’ll be discussing, and the one that we at Artsy have started adopting, is to give
exceptions their own type and return those instead of the success type, when they occur. To do this we make use of
a union of both the success and the exception type (or multiples thereof) and then query for those.</p>

<p>The benefits are:</p>

<ul>
<li><p>You can further model the exception in an explicit and introspect-able way.</p>

<p>For example, in the case of an HTTP failure to an upstream service, your exception type could include an integer
status-code field and document it as such.</p></li>
</ul>


<pre><code>type Artwork {
  title: String!
}

type HTTPError {
  message: String!
  statusCode: Int!
}

union ArtworkOrError = Artwork | HTTPError

type Query {
  artworkOrError(id: ID!): ArtworkOrError
}
</code></pre>

<pre><code>query {
  artworkOrError("mona-lisa") {
    ... on Artwork {
      title
    }
    ... on HTTPError {
      statusCode
    }
  }
}
</code></pre>

<ul>
<li>You know exactly where the exception occurred in the graph.</li>
</ul>


<pre><code>type Artist {
  artworksOrErrors: [ArtworkOrError]
}

type Query {
  artist(id: ID!): Artist
}
</code></pre>

<pre><code>query {
  artist("leonardo-da-vinci") {
    artworksOrErrors {
      ... on Artwork {
        title
      }
      ... on HTTPError {
        statusCode
      }
    }
  }
}
</code></pre>

<ul>
<li>You can use it for both mutations and queries.</li>
</ul>


<pre><code>type UpdateArtworkMutationResponse {
  artworkOrError: ArtworkOrError
}
</code></pre>

<ul>
<li>All fields will always be captured in the single <code>artworkOrError</code> field <em>or</em>, if no information about the error
is needed, you simply don’t query for it and get back <code>null</code> instead.</li>
</ul>


<pre><code>query {
  artworkOrError("mona-lisa") {
    ... on Artwork {
      title
    }
  }
}
</code></pre>

<a name="How.we.encode.it.into.our.schema"></a>
<h2>How we encode it into our schema</h2>

<p>I should preface this by clearly stating that while have been thinking about this problem for a while now, only
recently have we started rolling these changes out into our schema, so some of these are not yet discoverable in
<a href="http://github.com/artsy/metaphysics">our open-source GraphQL service</a>.</p>

<a name="Types"></a>
<h3>Types</h3>

<p>As shown before, we define a union of the actual result type <em>and</em> the error type. However, we additionally (will)
define a set of error interfaces, which make it possible for clients to query for errors in a more generic way.</p>

<pre><code>interface Error {
  message: String!
}

interface HTTPError {
  message: String!
  statusCode: Int!
}

type HTTPErrorType implements Error &amp; HTTPError {
  message: String!
  statusCode: Int!
}

type Artwork {
  title: String!
}

union ArtworkOrError = Artwork | HTTPErrorType

type Query {
  artworkOrError(id: ID!): ArtworkOrError
}
</code></pre>

<p>We can now still query as shown in the earlier examples:</p>

<pre><code>query {
  artworkOrError("mona-lisa") {
    ... on Artwork {
      title
    }
    ... on HTTPError {
      message
      statusCode
    }
  }
}
</code></pre>

<p>…but we can now also have generic error components that would query like so:</p>

<pre><code>query {
  artworkOrError("mona-lisa") {
    ... on Artwork {
      title
    }
    ...GenericErrorComponent
    ...GenericHTTPErrorComponent
  }
}

fragment GenericErrorComponent on Error {
  message
}

fragment GenericHTTPErrorComponent on HTTPError {
  message
  statusCode
}
</code></pre>

<p>For the record, we have <em>not</em> yet put these interfaces into production, so the nomenclature is not set in stone yet
and I’d love to hear your input on this. Is <code>Error</code> <em>too</em> generic to use as the base error type? Is there a nicer
naming pattern that would allow us to avoid having to suffix concrete types of an error interface with <code>...Type</code>?</p>

<p>Side-note: there’s <a href="https://github.com/facebook/graphql/pull/373">an RFC</a> to the GraphQL specification that would make it possible to
have interfaces implement other interfaces, thus removing the need to keep repeating the fields of
super-interfaces. This RFC has recently been moved to the draft stage, yay!</p>

<a name="Field.naming"></a>
<h3>Field naming</h3>

<p>As you may have noticed, we’re calling these fields <code>something</code> <em>or</em> <code>error</code>. We are mostly doing this to stay
backwards compatible with our existing schema. While we could certainly add exception types to existing union
fields, we can’t change a single type field into a union type field without breaking compatibility.</p>

<p>Instead we may now have 2 versions of a given field:</p>

<ul>
<li>one with the single type field which is nullable, in case an exception occurred</li>
</ul>


<pre><code>query {
  artwork("mona-lisa") {
    title
  }
}
</code></pre>

<ul>
<li>and another that has the error union type</li>
</ul>


<pre><code>query {
  artworkOrError("mona-lisa") {
    ... on Artwork {
      title
    }
    ... on HTTPError {
      statusCode
    }
  }
}
</code></pre>

<p>This duplication is slightly unfortunate, from a clean schema design perspective, but it’s similar to an existing
pattern in the community. For instance, many schemas provide 2 ways to retrieve lists:</p>

<ul>
<li>one as an immediate list:</li>
</ul>


<pre><code>type Query {
  artworks: [Artwork]
}
</code></pre>

<ul>
<li>and one as a ‘connection’ (as defined by the <a href="https://facebook.github.io/relay/graphql/connections.htm">Relay Connection specification</a>)</li>
</ul>


<pre><code>type ArtworkEdge {
  node: Artwork
}

type ArtworksConnection {
  edges: [ArtworkEdge]
}

type Query {
  artworksConnection: ArtworksConnection
}
</code></pre>

<p>So the jury is still out on whether or not that’s a bad way to name things. We’ll have to see after using this for a
while.</p>

<a name="Downside.of.using.a.union"></a>
<h3>Downside of using a union</h3>

<p>One notable downside is that GraphQL scalar types can <em>not</em> be included in unions. Thus, if you have scalar fields
that could lead to exceptions, you will have to ‘box’ those in object types.</p>

<pre><code>type ArtworkPurchasableBox {
  value: Boolean!
}

union ArtworkPurchasableOrError = ArtworkPurchasableBox | HTTPError

type Artwork {
  currentlyPurchasableOrError: ArtworkPurchasableOrError
}
</code></pre>

<p>This is definitely a case where the pattern of defining 2 fields, one with and one without exception types, comes
in handy. Having to always query through the box type is inelegant, to put it softly.</p>

<p>Side-note: there actually is <a href="https://github.com/facebook/graphql/issues/215">an open RFC</a> to the specification to allow scalars in unions, but
it’s still in stage 0 and is in need of a champion in order to proceed. We may end up trying to do so, based on our
actual experiences with these cases where they may need to be boxed.</p>

<a name="Example.of.how.we.consume.query.errors"></a>
<h3>Example of how we consume query errors</h3>

<pre><code class="ts">import { OrderStatus_order } from "__generated__/OrderStatus_order.graphql"
import React from "react"
import { createFragmentContainer, graphql } from "react-relay"

interface Props {
  order: OrderStatus_order
}

const OrderStatus: React.SFC&lt;Props&gt; = ({ order: orderStatusOrError }) =&gt;
  orderStatusOrError.__typename === "OrderStatus" ? (
    &lt;div&gt;
      {orderStatusOrError.deliveryDispatched
        ? "Your order has been dispatched."
        : "Your order has not been dispatched yet."}
    &lt;/div&gt;
  ) : (
    &lt;div className="error"&gt;
      {orderStatusOrError.code === "unpublished"
        ? "Please contact gallery services."
        : `An unexpected error occurred: ${orderStatusOrError.message}`}
    &lt;/div&gt;
  )

export const OrderStatusContainer = createFragmentContainer(
  OrderStatus,
  graphql`
    fragment OrderStatus_order on Order {
      orderStatusOrError {
        __typename
        ... on OrderStatus {
          deliveryDispatched
        }
        ... on OrderError {
          message
          code
        }
      }
    }
  `
)
</code></pre>

<a name="Example.of.how.we.consume.mutation.errors"></a>
<h3>Example of how we consume mutation errors</h3>

<pre><code class="ts">import { SubmitOrder_order } from "__generated__/SubmitOrder_order.graphql"
import { SubmitOrderMutation } from "__generated__/SubmitOrderMutation.graphql"
import { Router } from "found-relay"
import React from "react"
import { commitMutation, createFragmentContainer, graphql, RelayProp } from "react-relay"

interface Props {
  order: SubmitOrder_order
  relay: RelayProp
  router: Router
}

const SubmitOrder: React.SFC&lt;Props&gt; = props =&gt; (
  &lt;button
    onClick={() =&gt; {
      commitMutation&lt;SubmitOrderMutation&gt;(props.relay.environment, {
        mutation: graphql`
          mutation SubmitOrderMutation($input: SubmitOrder!) {
            submitOrder(input: $input) {
              orderStatusOrError {
                __typename
                ... on OrderStatus {
                  submitted
                }
                ... on OrderError {
                  message
                  code
                }
              }
            }
          }
        `,
        variables: { input: { orderID: props.order.id } },
        onCompleted: ({ submitOrder: { orderStatusOrError } }, errors) =&gt; {
          if (orderStatusOrError.__typename === "OrderStatus") {
            props.router.push(
              `/orders/${props.order.id}/${orderStatusOrError.submitted ? "submitted" : "pending"}`
            )
          } else {
            alert(
              orderStatusOrError.code === "unpublished"
                ? "Please contact gallery services."
                : `An unexpected error occurred: ${orderStatusOrError.message}`
            )
          }
        }
      })
    }}
  /&gt;
)

export const SubmitOrderContainer = createFragmentContainer(
  SubmitOrder,
  graphql`
    fragment SubmitOrder_order on Order {
      id
    }
  `
)
</code></pre>

<!--

### Show example of factory code that produces both single and union typed fields

TODO

-->


<a name="Final.thoughts"></a>
<h2>Final thoughts</h2>

<p>As stated before, we having only recently begun rolling out these changes into our production schema. However, much
thought and experimentation has gone into this to ensure we will be able to address all of <em>our</em> needs, at least.</p>

<p>I would love to hear other people’s thoughts on this and definitely feedback if they try to adopt it themselves. As
a community we should openly iterate together, as much as possible, as we try to make the future of GraphQL a great
one and put legit questions to ‘REST’ ;)</p>

<p>For now, I’ll leave you with this message from some internet ‘rando’:</p>

<blockquote><p>@alloy That diff makes a lot of sense to me. I've also seen user errors as a field on the mutation result, but I
like that union makes it explicit that there was either success or failure and in the case of failure provides
rich information that's in your app's domain.</p></blockquote>

<p>-- <a href="https://twitter.com/leeb/status/1020054709694943232">Lee Byron</a></p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[The Relay Network Deep Dive]]></title>
    <link href="http://artsy.github.io/blog/2018/07/25/Relay-Networking-Deep-Dive/"/>
    <updated>2018-07-25T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <id>http://artsy.github.io/blog/2018/07/25/Relay-Networking-Deep-Dive</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<blockquote><p>Hey all, we have another guest post, this one comes from <a href="https://github.com/sibelius">Sibelius Seraphini</a> - a very active contributor to
Relay and its eco-system. When we spotted he had wrote an amazing article on how the networking aspects of Relay
comes together, we wanted to expand his reach and inform more people on how Relay comes together.</p>

<p>-- Orta</p></blockquote>

<p>Data fetching is a hard problem for apps. You need to ask yourself a lot of questions: How do you ask for data from
a server? How do you handle authentication? When is the right time to request data? How can you ensure you have all
the necessary data to render your views? How can you make sure you're not over-fetching? Can you do lazy loading?
When should you trigger lazy loading of data? What about pre-fetching data?</p>

<p><a href="https://facebook.github.io/relay/">Relay</a> is a framework for building data-driven applications which handles data fetching for you. For an
introduction to Relay, read <a href="https://facebook.github.io/relay/">their docs</a>, and also check out my Relay talk at <a href="https://speakerdeck.com/sibelius/reactconfbr-is-relay-modern-the-future">React Conf BR</a>.</p>

<blockquote><p>You don’t deep dive if you don’t know how to swim</p></blockquote>

<a name="TL.DR.Relay.Modern.Network"></a>
<h2>TL;DR Relay Modern Network</h2>

<p>Relay will aggregate the data requirements (fragments) for your components, then create a request to fulfill it. The
API to do this is via the <a href="https://facebook.github.io/relay/docs/en/relay-environment.html">Relay Environment</a>:</p>

<blockquote><p>The Relay "Environment" bundles together the configuration, cache storage, and network-handling that Relay needs
in order to operate.</p></blockquote>

<p>This post focuses on the "network-handling" part, the <a href="https://facebook.github.io/relay/docs/en/network-layer.html">Network Layer</a>. The network layer's responsibility
is to make a request to a server (or a local graphql) and return the response data to Relay. Your implementation
should conform to either <a href="https://github.com/facebook/relay/blob/v1.6.0/packages/relay-runtime/network/RelayNetworkTypes.js#L79-L90">FetchFunction</a> for a Promise-like API, or <a href="https://github.com/facebook/relay/blob/v1.6.0/packages/relay-runtime/network/RelayNetworkTypes.js#L92-L107">SubscribeFunction</a> for an
Observable-like API.</p>

<p>This article will provide 5 implementations of a Relay Network Interface, each of one providing more capabilities
than the other one, eventually enabling GraphQL Live Queries and Deferrable Queries.</p>

<p>You can see the code for these 5 network layers on GitHub here, open source under MIT license:
<a href="https://github.com/sibelius/relay-modern-network-deep-dive">https://github.com/sibelius/relay-modern-network-deep-dive</a>.</p>

<!-- more -->


<a name="Simplest.Network.Layer"></a>
<h3>Simplest Network Layer</h3>

<p>The simplest network layer would; get the request, send it to a GraphQL server to resolve and return the data to
Relay environment.</p>

<pre><code class="js">const fetchFunction = async (
  request: RequestNode,
  variables: Variables,
  cacheConfig: CacheConfig,
  uploadables: ?UploadableMap
) =&gt; {
  // Most GraphQL APIs expect a POST with a JSON
  // string containing the query and associated variables
  const body = JSON.stringify({
    query: request.text, // GraphQL text from input
    variables
  });

  const headers = {
    Accept: "application/json",
    "Content-type": "application/json",
    authorization: getToken()
  };

  const response = await fetchWithRetries(ENV.GRAPHQL_URL, {
    method: "POST",
    headers,
    body,
    fetchTimeout: 20000,
    retryDelays: [1000, 3000, 5000, 10000]
  });

  const data = await response.json();

  // Mutations should throw when they have errors, making it easier
  // for client code to react
  if (isMutation(request) &amp;&amp; data.errors) {
    throw data;
  }

  // We return the GraphQL response to update the Relay Environment
  // which updates internal store where relay keeps its data
  return data;
};
</code></pre>

<a name="Network.that.Handle.Uploadables"></a>
<h3>Network that Handle Uploadables</h3>

<p>The GraphQL spec does not handle form data, and so if you need to send along files to upload to your server with a
mutation, you'll want to use the uploadables API in Relay when you commit the mutation.</p>

<p>Adding uploadables in a mutation will inevitably get passed to your network interface, where you'll need to change
your request body to use FormData instead of the JSON string above:</p>

<pre><code class="js">function getRequestBodyWithUploadables(request, variables, uploadables) {
  let formData = new FormData();
  formData.append("query", request.text);
  formData.append("variables", JSON.stringify(variables));

  Object.keys(uploadables).forEach(key =&gt; {
    if (Object.prototype.hasOwnProperty.call(uploadables, key)) {
      formData.append(key, uploadables[key]);
    }
  });

  return formData;
}
</code></pre>

<a name="Network.that.Caches.Requests"></a>
<h3>Network that Caches Requests</h3>

<p>This builds on top of the other 2 implementations, we use
<a href="https://github.com/facebook/relay/blob/v1.6.0/packages/relay-runtime/network/RelayQueryResponseCache.js#L24-L29">RelayQueryResponseCache</a>
to query GraphQL requests based on query and variables.</p>

<p>Every time a mutation happens, we should invalidate our cache as we are not sure how a change can affect all cached
query responses.</p>

<pre><code class="js">// Create our own in-memory cache
const relayResponseCache = new RelayQueryResponseCache({ size: 250, ttl: oneMinute });

const cacheHandler = async (
  request: RequestNode,
  variables: Variables,
  cacheConfig: CacheConfig,
  uploadables: UploadableMap
) =&gt; {
  const queryID = request.text;

  // If it's a mutation, clear all cache, then call the implementation above
  if (isMutation(request)) {
    relayResponseCache.clear();
    return fetchFunction(request, variables, cacheConfig, uploadables);
  }

  // Try grab the request from the cache first
  const fromCache = relayResponseCache.get(queryID, variables);
  // Did it hit? Or did we suppress the cache for this request
  if (isQuery(request) &amp;&amp; fromCache !== null &amp;&amp; !forceFetch(cacheConfig)) {
    return fromCache;
  }

  // Make the request, and cache it if we get a response
  const fromServer = await fetchFunction(request, variables, cacheConfig, uploadables);
  if (fromServer) {
    relayResponseCache.set(queryID, variables, fromServer);
  }

  return fromServer;
};
</code></pre>

<a name="Network.using.Observable"></a>
<h3>Network using Observable</h3>

<p>Relay provides a limited implementation of the upcoming <a href="https://github.com/tc39/proposal-observable">ESObservables</a> spec. I recommend reading <a href="https://kriskowal.gitbooks.io/gtor/content/">A General
Theory of Reactivity</a> to understand why Observables are a great solution instead of promises in some
situations. Notably; a promise is one value in a time space, an observable is a stream of values in a time space.</p>

<!-- [TODO: Why Sink and not the Relay Observable? Observable is exported but has one more function (complete)] -->


<p>To work with this API, we're going to use a private interface for the observable object called Sink:</p>

<pre><code class="js">/**
 * A Sink is an object of methods provided by Observable during construction.
 * The methods are to be called to trigger each event. It also contains a closed
 * field to see if the resulting subscription has closed.
 */
export type Sink&lt;-T&gt; = {|
  +next: T =&gt; void,
  +error: (Error, isUncaughtThrownError?: boolean) =&gt; void,
  +complete: () =&gt; void,
  +closed: boolean
|};
</code></pre>

<p>Which is the shape of the Observable object we pass back to Relay:</p>

<pre><code class="js">const fetchFunction = async (
  request: RequestNode,
  variables: Variables,
  cacheConfig: CacheConfig,
  uploadables: ?UploadableMap,
  sink: Sink&lt;any&gt;
) =&gt; {
  const body = getRequestBody(request, variables, uploadables);

  const headers = {
    ...getHeaders(uploadables),
    authorization: getToken()
  };

  const response = await fetchWithRetries(ENV.GRAPHQL_URL, {
    method: "POST",
    headers,
    body,
    fetchTimeout: 20000,
    retryDelays: [1000, 3000, 5000, 10000]
  });

  const data = await handleData(response);

  if (isMutation(request) &amp;&amp; data.errors) {
    sink.error(data);
    sink.complete();

    return;
  }

  sink.next(data);
  sink.complete();
};

// Instead of returning a Promise that will resolve a single GraphQL response.
// We return an Observable that could fulfill many responses before it finishes.

const executeFunction = (
  request: RequestNode,
  variables: Variables,
  cacheConfig: CacheConfig,
  uploadables: ?UploadableMap
) =&gt; {
  return Observable.create(sink =&gt; {
    fetchFunction(request, variables, cacheConfig, uploadables, sink);
  });
};
</code></pre>

<p>This is an implementation you would need when working with <a href="https://github.com/facebook/relay/issues/2174">GraphQL Live Queries</a> (based on polling), as you
are going to resolve the same query more than once.</p>

<a name="Deferrable.Queries.Network"></a>
<h3>Deferrable Queries Network</h3>

<p>A common case for deferrable queries is to lazy load fragments. This lets you get request content above the page
fold first, and then request additional data after. A good example is loading a Post's content first and then
subsequently loading all comments of this post after the post has finished.</p>

<p>Without deferrable queries you could simulate this using the <a href="https://facebook.github.io/relay/docs/en/graphql-in-relay.html#directives">@include</a> directive in your Relay fragment
and a <a href="https://facebook.github.io/relay/docs/en/refetch-container.html">refetch container</a>. When the component mounts the refetch container changes the variable used on the
<code>@include</code> to true and it will request the rest of the data.</p>

<p>The problem with above approach is that you need to wait for the component to mount before you can start the next
request. This becomes a bigger problem as React does more work asynchronously.</p>

<!-- TODO: There are no docs for relay deferrable -->


<p>An ideal deferrable query will start as soon as the previous query has finished, rather than depending on your React
components render cycles. Relay provides a <a href="https://github.com/facebook/relay/issues/2194#issuecomment-383466255">directive</a> for this: <code>@relay(deferrable: true)</code>:</p>

<pre><code class="js">const PostFragment = createFragmentContainer(Post, {
  post: graphql`
    fragment Post_post on Post {
      title
      commentsCount
      ...CommentsList_post @relay(deferrable: true)
    }
  `
});
</code></pre>

<p>In the fragment above, Relay will first get the <code>title</code> and <code>commentsCount</code> from the Post, then afterwards Relay
will get the data for <code>CommentsList_post</code> fragment. Sending both through the observable.</p>

<p>Here is the implementation of an execute function to handle a batched request:</p>

<pre><code class="js">const executeFunction = (
  request: RequestNode,
  variables: Variables,
  cacheConfig: CacheConfig,
  uploadables: ?UploadableMap
) =&gt; {
  return Observable.create(sink =&gt; {
    if (request.kind === "Request") {
      cacheHandler(request, variables, cacheConfig, uploadables, sink, true);
    }

    if (request.kind === "BatchRequest") {
      batchRequestQuery(request, variables, cacheConfig, uploadables, sink);
    }
  });
};
</code></pre>

<p>This execute function now can handle 2 types of requests:</p>

<ul>
<li>a single GraphQL query <code>Request</code></li>
<li>or a <code>BatchRequest</code> that could have be many queries with inter-related data</li>
</ul>


<p>So, what does the <code>batchRequestQuery</code> function look like?</p>

<!-- TODO: Annotate ths code, I'm not 100% what it's doing myself -->


<pre><code class="js">// Get variables from the results that have already been sent
const getDeferrableVariables = (requests, request, variables: Variables) =&gt; {
  const { argumentDependencies } = request;

  if (argumentDependencies.length === 0) {
    return variables;
  }

  return argumentDependencies.reduce((acc, ad) =&gt; {
    const { response } = requests[ad.fromRequestName];

    const variable = get(response.data, ad.fromRequestPath);

    // TODO - handle ifList, ifNull
    // See: https://github.com/facebook/relay/issues/2194
    return {
      ...acc,
      [ad.name]: variable
    };
  }, {});
};

// Execute each of the requests, and call `sink.next()` as soon as it has the GraphQL
/// server response data.
//
// It will only close the Observable stream when all requests has been fulfilled.
const batchRequestQuery = async (
  request: RequestNode,
  variables: Variables,
  cacheConfig: CacheConfig,
  uploadables: ?UploadableMap,
  sink: Sink&lt;ExecutePayload&gt;
) =&gt; {
  const requests = {};

  for (const r of request.requests) {
    const v = getDeferrableVariables(requests, r, variables);

    const response = await cacheHandler(r, v, cacheConfig, uploadables, sink, false);

    requests[r.name] = response;
  }

  sink.complete();
};
</code></pre>

<a name="Relay.Modern.is.very.flexible"></a>
<h2>Relay Modern is very flexible</h2>

<p>Depending on your application needs, you can scale from a simpler Promise-based API for your custom network layer to
one that uses Observables to always resolves from cache data first and then resolves from the server.</p>

<p>Here are some production examples:</p>

<ul>
<li><p><a href="https://github.com/artsy/emission/blob/master/src/lib/relay/fetchQuery.ts">Artsy Emission</a>: Uses the Promise API, caches the results locally, and shares logic with native code in an
iOS app so that queries can be pre-cached before the JavaScript runtime has started.</p></li>
<li><p><a href="https://github.com/relay-tools/react-relay-network-modern">ReactRelayNetworkModern</a>: A network layer that uses the middleware pattern to separate responsibilities like
retrying, logging, caching and auth.</p></li>
<li><p><a href="https://github.com/facebook/relay/issues/2174#issuecomment-375274003">timobetina's example</a>: The simplest Observable network layer you can start with.</p></li>
</ul>


<!-- TODO: More, @sibelius do you have some good examples? -->


<a name="More.Resources"></a>
<h2>More Resources</h2>

<p>If you want to expand your understanding of GraphQL and Relay Modern, I have two great related resources:</p>

<ul>
<li><p>A boilerplate that uses dataloader to batch and cache requests to your database in a GraphQL API:
<a href="https://github.com/entria/graphql-dataloader-boilerplate">https://github.com/entria/graphql-dataloader-boilerplate</a></p></li>
<li><p>A simple boilerplate for working with Relay Modern and React Navigation:
<a href="https://github.com/entria/ReactNavigationRelayModern">https://github.com/entria/ReactNavigationRelayModern</a></p></li>
</ul>


<p>If you have questions about this or anything send me a DM on twitter <a href="https://twitter.com/sseraphini">https://twitter.com/sseraphini</a></p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Is GraphQL The Future?]]></title>
    <link href="http://artsy.github.io/blog/2018/05/08/is-graphql-the-future/"/>
    <updated>2018-05-08T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <id>http://artsy.github.io/blog/2018/05/08/is-graphql-the-future</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I have seen the future, and it looks a lot like GraphQL. Mark my words: in 5
years, newly minted full-stack app developers won’t be debating <em>RESTfulness</em>
anymore, because REST API design will be obsolete. By the end of this post, I
hope you'll see what I see in the promise of GraphQL as a new approach to
client-server interaction.</p>

<!-- more -->


<p>GraphQL is taking the full-stack world by storm. In case you’re not familiar,
GraphQL is a language-independent specification for client-server communication.
It lets you model the resources and processes provided by a server as a
<a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Domain-specific_language">domain-specific language (DSL)</a>.
Clients can use it to send scripts written in your DSL to the server to process
and respond to as a batch.</p>

<p>That’s...different from how GraphQL’s own page describes it. GraphQL is better
known as a query language designed for clients to fetch exactly the data they
need. While this is sort of true, I would argue that GraphQL actually fails this
test in reality. It’s neither a query language, nor particularly graph-oriented.
I argue that it's <em>not</em> a query language because it comes with no native
concepts of operators and expressions that build up to queries. <em>You</em> build
whatever facilities for specifying and fulfilling queries on your own. Likewise,
if your data is a graph, it’s on you to expose that structure. But your requests
are, if anything, trees.</p>

<p>I’m not trying to be pedantic. I believe GraphQL succeeds at something subtler
and more important than literally being a graph query language. I’m writing this
piece because I kept running into difficulties approaching GraphQL from the
standpoints of REST, graph theory, or typical query languages. As I read blog
posts, StackOverflow Q&amp;As, issues on the GraphQL repo and the GraphQL spec
itself, I developed a much more nuanced understanding, which I outline below.</p>

<p>For brevity, the following assumes a intermediate familiarity with GraphQL,
including its type system, syntax, and server-side implementation. If you don’t
have this level of familiarity, I recommend going through any tutorial that
requires you to set up a GraphQL server, not just play with the query language
(which is how I ended up with a lot of misconceptions).
<a href="https://graphql.org/graphql-js/">The docs for the official JavaScript server library</a>
are a good option. I’m going to start with the basics, but only so I can put my
own spin on those concepts, not to really illustrate them with examples.</p>

<a name="A.tree.of.fetches"></a>
<h1>A tree of fetches</h1>

<p>Most applications are designed in the form of discrete pages, which are seeded
with some tiny chunk of data—say, a key or slug for some domain object—and then
perform a cascade of contingent fetches to get the data needed to populate the
templates rendered to a user. This is the basis of designing applications driven
by URL-based routing and it has been a mainstay of the MVC approach to web
application architecture for the past decade.</p>

<blockquote><p><strong>Example:</strong> At Artsy, the seed of data for rendering an artwork page could be
the slug identifying some artwork. From this slug, we need a whole bunch more
data: the metadata of the artwork, information about the artist(s), sales data
if it’s available for purchase, information about the Artsy partner that owns
it, and so on. In classic REST, this data is aggregated by a cascade of dozens
of HTTP fetches to our backend API.</p></blockquote>

<p>I wasn’t in the room when GraphQL was invented, but it seems to me that the team
that built it made a particularly crucial insight:</p>

<blockquote><p>In most cases, all of this contingent fetching forms a tree, which is more or
less <em>fixed</em> for a given page.</p></blockquote>

<p>Data from early responses contain the keys for subsequent requests, but the
linkages between these requests are usually straightforward. So if it were
possible to factor all this disparate fetching into one spot and encode it into
one big “fetching tree” data structure ahead of time, this tree could be sent to
the the server, and the server could fulfill all of the data requirements in one
shot. This cuts out a tremendous amount of wasteful chatter between client and
server. Even in today's broadband world, bandwidth and latency matter,
especially for mobile users.</p>

<a name="GraphQL.anatomy"></a>
<h1>GraphQL anatomy</h1>

<blockquote><p><strong>Editorial note</strong> I'm going to use the term "operation" pretty liberally
here, but I mean it in the conceptual sense, not in the sense of the GraphQL
spec, where it defines the semantics of an entire GraphQL request.</p></blockquote>

<p>A GraphQL request always starts with at least <em>one root API operation</em> and some
finite number of follow-ups. Idiomatically, these follow-ups are queries,
meaning that they just retrieve data, without changing the server state in
observable ways. GraphQL models API operations as <strong>fields</strong>. How a field works
in GraphQL depends on its <strong>type</strong>, which falls into one of two basic
categories:</p>

<ul>
<li><strong>Scalar</strong> types (<code>Int</code>, <code>Float</code>, <code>String</code>, <code>Boolean</code>, and <code>ID</code>, as well as
application-defined <code>enum</code> and <code>scalar</code> types) represent the individual pieces
of <em>data actually sent to the client</em>. Contrary how I think of the term scalar
in other contexts, the data can be arbitrarily complex. As far as the GraphQL
spec is concerned, scalars are just opaque blobs of data with validation and
serialization rules. As an operation, a scalar field is terminal data fetch,
with no follow-ups. They are the leaves of the request tree.</li>
<li><strong>Object</strong> types (<code>type</code>, <code>union</code> and <code>interface</code>) are collections of fields.
As an operation, an object-typed field is an intermediate operation that
serves as the junction point for follow-up operations. But, it doesn’t
directly return any data. They are the branches of the request tree.</li>
</ul>


<p>The entire model for a given API is known as its <strong>schema</strong>. Every schema has a
root query type, whose fields serve as the API’s entry points.</p>

<pre><code># The root query object type
type Query {
  artwork(id: ID): Artwork
  artist(name: String)
  # … a whole bunch more root fields
}

type Artwork {
  title: String
  artist: Artist
}

type Artist {
  name: String
}
</code></pre>

<p>A GraphQL query request begins by mentioning at least one of the fields of the
root query object. This represents an initial query. And if that field is an
object, <em>its</em> fields are used to specify any number of follow-up queries.
Critically, <em>any</em> field in the request tree can take arguments, allowing a
request to be parameterized at all depths.</p>

<p>Take this query, for example:</p>

<pre><code>{
  artwork(id: "andy-warhol-campbells-soup-i-black-bean") {
    title
    artist {
      name
    }
  }
}
</code></pre>

<p>Here, we tell the server to look up an <code>Artwork</code> by its slug, and tell us the
title. So far, this is just like REST. But we <em>also</em> tell it to find us the
<code>Artist</code> for us. Importantly, object fields <em>must</em> be followed up with further
queries, and scalar fields <em>cannot</em> be. With that in mind, it’s easy to see that
<code>artwork</code> and <code>artist</code> are object fields, while <code>title</code> and <code>name</code> are scalar
fields.</p>

<p>Also note that the fact that there’s also an <code>artist</code> root query field actually
has nothing to do with its presence under <code>Artwork</code>. There can be multiple paths
to reach the same GraphQL type. This is defined explicitly by the schema.</p>

<p>Usefully, the server’s response to a GraphQL request will directly mirror the
shape of the request itself. The result of the request above looks like:</p>

<pre><code>{
  "data": {
    "artwork": {
      "title": "Campbell's Soup I: Black Bean",
      "artist": {
        "name": "Andy Warhol"
      }
    }
  }
}
</code></pre>

<a name="GraphQL.as.a..meta-.scripting.language"></a>
<h1>GraphQL as a (meta-)scripting language</h1>

<p>Let’s dig a little deeper into the scripting language interpretation of GraphQL,
because this is the crux of how I think people should think of GraphQL. If I
were to guess, I think Facebook…</p>

<ul>
<li>…knows this is true. After all, much of the spec is devoted to
<a href="http://facebook.github.io/graphql/October2016/#sec-Execution">the execution model of GraphQL</a>.</li>
<li>…might have backed into this design. It’s well known that they think of their
data as a graph, so I suspect GraphQL might have begun literally as a "graph
query language", analogous to <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/SQL">SQL</a> for
relational databases.</li>
<li>…thinks that this too difficult to explain, and thus, settled on the query
language paradigm.</li>
</ul>


<p>There are a couple reasons GraphQL might not look like a scripting language to
you. It didn’t to me, at first! After all, you don't write your request as list
of statements. It doesn’t have a concept of variables, other than parameters to
the whole document. There are no looping constructs or recursion. But I think a
closer look might shift your perspective.</p>

<a name="Control.flow"></a>
<h2>Control flow</h2>

<p>It’s true that a GraphQL request doesn’t follow the same vertical sequence of
steps model familiar to most programming languages. But sequencing <em>does</em> exist.
It’s just represented by calling nested fields of object types, terminating in a
scalar field. See this request:</p>

<pre><code>{
  step1(arg: “something”) {
    step2 {
      step3(arg: "something else”) {
        outputScalar
      }
    }
  }
</code></pre>

<p>In a more traditional language, this would look more like:</p>

<pre><code>step1(“something”)
step2()
return step3(“something else”)
</code></pre>

<p>So, sequencing got a bit more verbose, but it <em>is</em> there.</p>

<p>Interestingly, GraphQL reserves vertical stacking for something that’s an
afterthought in most languages: <em>concurrency</em>. (Granted, there’s no way to
<a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Synchronization_(computer_science)">synchronize</a>
concurrent paths of execution.) I’m not going to quote
<a href="https://facebook.github.io/graphql/October2016/">the spec</a>, but search it
yourself, and you can find the word “parallel” in there several times. This
design is intentional.</p>

<a name="Variables"></a>
<h2>Variables</h2>

<p>One of the core aspects of programming is the ability to pass intermediate data
around. The most basic way languages accomplish this is with named variables.
Many languages allow variables to be reassigned; some don't. GraphQL doesn’t
have them at all! But that doesn’t mean data can’t be propagated.</p>

<p>GraphQL supports one kind of propagation, which is the propagation of context
down the sequence of resolvers. It happens implicitly and invisibly. Exactly
what data is propagated and what that means is up to you.</p>

<p>How does this work? Well, if you have worked on GraphQL server code, you know
that every field has a <strong>resolver</strong>.</p>

<ul>
<li>For scalar fields, the resolver is responsible for returning the actual data
that the client sees.</li>
<li>For object fields, the resolver instead returns a hidden chunk of data that is
forwarded along to the resolvers of the fields contained in the object. So
these resolvers get their parent object’s hidden data, the global context, and
any arguments, and they can use all of these values to produce their value.</li>
</ul>


<p>Often, we just resolve an object field to a domain object. Its scalar fields
might correspond to properties of that domain object and its object fields might
correspond to related objects. But the architecture is more powerful than this!
A deeply nested field can potentially be the result of the resolved values of
all its parents. It all depends on how you design your resolvers to work
together.</p>

<p>This pattern reminds me a bit of when <a href="https://api.jquery.com/">jQuery</a> first
clicked for me. A lot of details are propagated invisibly within your <code>jquery</code>
object as you chain method calls to refine your DOM selections.</p>

<a name="Looping.and.recursion"></a>
<h2>Looping and recursion</h2>

<p>GraphQL doesn’t have them, plain and simple. Consequently, the GraphQL DSLs you
design are not
<a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Turing_completeness">Turing-complete</a>--they will
always halt in a finite amount of steps. This is really important, because it
prevents clients from being able to send servers on errands that will never end.
Of course, the <em>implementations</em> of field resolvers on the server are free to do
whatever they want in full Turing-complete glory.</p>

<a name="Putting.it.together"></a>
<h2>Putting it together</h2>

<p>My point here is that the execution model of GraphQL is in many ways just like a
scripting language interpreter. The limitations of its model are strategic, to
keep the technology focused on client-server interaction. What's interesting is
that you as a developer provide nearly all of the definition of what operations
exist, what they mean, and how they compose. For this reason, I consider GraphQL
to be a <em>meta-scripting language</em>, or, in other words, a toolkit for building
scripting languages.</p>

<a name="The.post-REST.world"></a>
<h1>The post-REST world</h1>

<p>Subtly, this paradigm is a sharp step away from a whole body of knowledge that
models APIs as resources with fixed verbs, which we know as REST. It’s more
appropriate to think of GraphQL requests as a script of remote procedure calls
(RPC). From this perspective, the design of the schema is a lot less about data
modeling than it is a question of how you want your entire API to be traversed.
This encourages a verb-oriented mindset.</p>

<a name="Verb.orientation"></a>
<h2>Verb orientation</h2>

<p>Speaking of verbs, you can think of "fetch" as being the default verb in
GraphQL. You model other verbs as <strong>mutations</strong>. I delayed learning about
mutations, because I thought they must be way more complex than queries. Quite
the opposite! They all sit in one big, flat bucket at the root of your schema,
as the fields of the root <code>mutation</code> type. These fields have a type too, and if
it is an object type, then you can issue effectively any number of follow-up
queries after your mutation completes. Learning about mutations was when it
really dawned on me that <em>fields are just function calls</em>.</p>

<p>Mutations are a major break with REST. In GraphQL, your mutations are defined
under root mutation object that is separate from your root query object.
Therefore, you are immediately asked to accept that they don't represent verbs
on a resource, but verbs <em>on your entire service</em>. This eliminates one of REST’s
key weak points, namely that complex operations that touch multiple parts of an
application’s data model are difficult to model as a PUT, DELETE, POST, or PATCH
on a single resource. In my experience, this "impedance mismatch” between API
modeling and domain modeling has led to the worst aspects of my HTTP API
designs.</p>

<a name="REST.is.dead..Long.live.REST."></a>
<h2>REST is dead. Long live REST!</h2>

<p>It is borderline heresy in some circles to suggest that REST API design is dead.
But I’m saying it. Don’t get me wrong, REST is still a great paradigm for
serving static assets. It’s the <em>API</em> part I have an issue with.</p>

<p>Ironically, I think there’s a strong argument that a GraphQL request document
maps very nicely to the concept of a resource:</p>

<ul>
<li>It doesn’t change that often, and you could PUT it to store it, perhaps using
a hash of the request document to form the URL.</li>
<li>GraphQL queries map elegantly to GET operations on a stored query request
document’s URL.</li>
<li>GraphQL mutations map decently to POST operations to a stored mutation request
document’s URL.</li>
<li>The arguments of a GraphQL request map elegantly to HTTP query parameters.</li>
</ul>


<p>In other words, GraphQL is simply another formalization layer of HTTP-based API
design. Think of it as being akin to the way JSON representation changed the way
we think about client-server communication in full-stack apps. It’s not so much
that REST will cease to exist, but that it will fade to the background, as an
implementation detail of GraphQL application frameworks.</p>

<a name="GraphQL.is.not.your.data.model"></a>
<h1>GraphQL is not your data model</h1>

<p>Another realization I’ve had in learning to apply GraphQL is that the schema is
<em>not</em> the actual data model, and therefore raw GraphQL responses cannot be
directly used by the client. You <em>could</em> choose to think of it this way, but
you’re likely to run into some conundrums:</p>

<ul>
<li><a href="https://github.com/facebook/graphql/issues/101">There is no free-form map data structure</a>.
There are only objects with fixed fields, scalars, and lists.</li>
<li>It is difficult to design abstractions over types.</li>
<li>The object tree you get in return from a query request is neither normalized
nor is it an object graph (multiple copies of the same object may be
returned).</li>
<li>Commonly used protocol patterns, like
<a href="https://facebook.github.io/relay/docs/graphql-connections.html">the connection pattern</a>,
require explicit modeling within your schema.</li>
<li>The limitations of GraphQL's type system make certain modeling techniques
difficult to directly model, such as
<a href="https://stackoverflow.com/questions/47933512/representing-enum-object-variant-type-in-graphql">singletons within unions</a>.</li>
<li>Recursive data types can’t be queried to undefined depth in their nested form.
Think of your comment board with nested replies.</li>
</ul>


<p>The upshot of this is that there likely needs to be some process of conversion
from your native data model on your server to your GraphQL API, and then again
from your client’s API consumption code to its internal data model.
<a href="https://facebook.github.io/relay/">Relay</a> and
<a href="https://www.apollographql.com/client">Apollo</a> serve this purpose. Their utility
wasn’t immediately clear to me when I naively imagined GraphQL to literally be a
system for reproducing a slice of server-side object graph. (Hmm, where might I
have gotten that impression from?)</p>

<p>A lot of discussion in the GraphQL space centers on data modeling—the nouns.
There’s a lot of debate and worthwhile work to be done on that front, but one of
my primary reasons for writing this piece is to think about the verbs. What
happens when you think of GraphQL requests as not just verbs, but <em>chains</em> of
verbs? My inkling is that you start to be able to represent services in a much
more fluid way. Complex processes no longer have to be orchestrated by API
clients or hidden behind unwieldy black-box POST endpoints. Instead, clients can
compose processes from the easily inspectable building blocks that the server
provides via its GraphQL schema. That’s a whole different approach to API
design.</p>

<a name="So..where.to.now."></a>
<h1>So, where to now?</h1>

<p>I began by asserting that the future looks a lot <em>like</em> GraphQL. But I did not
say that GraphQL <em>is the future</em>. I hedge because there are a lot of unanswered
questions and some pain points within today’s GraphQL, even as it paints a
compelling picture of the future. I may write a follow-up piece bringing up some
of these gripes. At the moment, Facebook still largely controls the development
of the technology and it has been slow to evolve. Arguably, this is a good
thing, as the full-stack community continues to digest the basic concepts. But
I’m sure impatient folks will attempt forks or create parallel technologies. How
it all balances out is anybody’s guess.</p>

<p>Nonetheless, today’s GraphQL is already a tremendous leap forward from REST API
design. It much more directly models the sort of data traversals a client needs
to perform in order to do its job. I expect significant refinement within this
space over the next couple years. And after a couple more, the days before
GraphQL will be just another source of lore for grizzled vets like us.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Relay Mutations]]></title>
    <link href="http://artsy.github.io/blog/2017/04/26/Relay-Mutations/"/>
    <updated>2017-04-26T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <id>http://artsy.github.io/blog/2017/04/26/Relay-Mutations</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<blockquote><p>Hey there everyone, it took us two years to <a href="https://github.com/artsy/metaphysics/pull/583">make our</a> GraphQL implementation support any mutations. We opted to keep it read-only for quite a long time because we use GraphQL to consolidate multiple APIs, but as we start new projects as GraphQL + databases then understanding mutations becomes much more important.</p>

<p>Last month, I talked with the team at <a href="https://www.graph.cool/">Graph.cool</a> about having them talk through Relay mutations comprehensively as a guest post on the Artsy Engineering blog. So, I'm really excited to introduce this great post on the topic by <a href="http://twitter.com/nikolasburk">Nikolas Burk</a>.</p>

<p>-- Orta</p></blockquote>

<a name="The.Magic.behind.Relay.Mutations"></a>
<h1>The Magic behind Relay Mutations</h1>

<p><a href="https://facebook.github.io/relay/">Relay</a> is a powerful GraphQL client for React and React Native applications. It was open sourced by Facebook alongside GraphQL in 2015 and is a great tool for supporting you with managing your app's data layer.</p>

<p>In this post, we are going to explore how Relay mutations work by looking at a React Native app. The code can be found on <a href="https://github.com/graphcool-examples/react-native-relay-pokedex-example">GitHub</a>. Our sample application is a simple <em>Pokedex</em>, where users can manage their Pokemons.</p>

<p><img src="http://i.imgur.com/S21GfEo.png" alt="" /></p>

<blockquote><p>Note: We're going to assume a basic familiarity with GraphQL in this article. If you haven't heard of GraphQL before, the <a href="www.graphql.org">documentation</a> and the <a href="http://artsy.github.io/blog/2016/06/19/graphql-for-mobile/">GraphQL for iOS Developers</a> post are great places to start. If you're interested in learning more about Relay in general, head over to <a href="www.learnrelay.org">Learn Relay</a> for a comprehensive tutorial.</p></blockquote>

<!-- more -->


<p>If you want to run the example with your own GraphQL server, you can use <a href="https://www.graph.cool/graphql-up/">graphql-up</a> to quickly spin one up yourself from within your browser. Simply click the pink button and follow the instructions on the website.</p>

<p><a href="https://www.graph.cool/graphql-up/new?source=https://raw.githubusercontent.com/graphcool-examples/react-native-relay-pokedex-example/master/pokedex.schema"><img src="http://static.graph.cool/images/graphql-up.svg" alt="graphql-up" /></a></p>

<a name="Relay.-.A.brief.Overview"></a>
<h2>Relay - A brief Overview</h2>

<p>Relay is the most sophisticated GraphQL client available at the moment. Like GraphQL, it has been used and battle-tested internally by Facebook for many years before it was open sourced.</p>

<p>Relay surely isn't the easiest framework to learn - but when used correctly, it takes care of managing large parts of your app's data layer in a consistent and reliable manner! It therefore is particularly well-suited for complex applications with lots of data interdependencies and provides outstanding longterm developer productivity.</p>

<a name="Declarative.API.and.Colocation"></a>
<h3>Declarative API and Colocation</h3>

<p>With Relay, React components specify their data requirements in a declarative fashion, making use of GraphQL <em>fragments</em>.</p>

<blockquote><p>A <a href="https://learngraphql.com/basics/fragments">GraphQL fragment</a> is a selection of fields on a GraphQL type. You can use them to define <em>reusable sub-parts</em> of queries or mutations.</p></blockquote>

<p>Considering the <code>PokemonDetails</code> view above, we need to display the Pokemon's name and image. The fragment that represents these data requirements looks as follows:</p>

<pre><code>fragment PokemonDetails on Node {
  ... on Pokemon {
    id
    name
    url
  }
}
</code></pre>

<p>Note that the <code>id</code> is required so that Relay can identify the objects in the cache, so it's included in the payload as well (even if it's not displayed on the UI).</p>

<p>These fragments are kept in the same file as the React component, so UI and data requirements are <em>colocated</em>. Relay then uses a <a href="https://facebook.github.io/react/docs/higher-order-components.html">higher-order component</a> called <a href="https://facebook.github.io/relay/docs/guides-containers.html#content"><code>Relay.Container</code></a>, to wrap the component along with its data requirements. From this point, the developer doesn't have to worry about the data any more! It will be fetched behind the scenes and is made available to the component via its props.</p>

<a name="Build-time.Schema.Validation"></a>
<h3>Build-time Schema Validation</h3>

<p>Another great feature of Relay that ensures developer productivity is  <em>schema validation</em>. At build time, Relay checks your GraphQL queries, fragments and mutations to ensure their compatibility with the GraphQL API. It is thus able to catch any typos or other schema-related errors before you run (or even worse: deploy) your app, saving your users from unpleasant experiences. Note that the schema validation step requires a <a href="https://facebook.github.io/relay/docs/guides-babel-plugin.html">Babel Relay Plugin</a>.</p>

<a name="Mutations.in.Relay"></a>
<h2>Mutations in Relay</h2>

<a name="GraphQL.Recap"></a>
<h3>GraphQL Recap</h3>

<p>In GraphQL, a <em>mutation</em> is the only way to create, update or delete data on the server - they effectively are the GraphQL abstraction for <em>changing state</em> in your backend.</p>

<p>As an example, creating a new Pokemon in our sample app uses the following mutation:</p>

<pre><code>mutation CreatePokemon($name: String!, $url: String!) {
  createPokemon(input: {
    name: $name,
    url: $url
  }) {
    # payload of the mutation (will be returned by the server)
    pokemon {
      id 
    }
  }
}
</code></pre>

<p>Notice that mutations, similar to queries, also require a <em>payload</em> to be specified. This payload represents the information that we'd like to have returned from the server after the mutation was performed. In the above example, we're asking for the <code>id</code> of the new <code>pokemon</code>.</p>

<a name="The.Magic:.Declarative.Mutations....."></a>
<h3>The Magic: Declarative Mutations 🔮</h3>

<p>Relay doesn't (yet) give the developer the ability to manually modify the data that it stores internally. Instead, with every change, it requires a declarative <em>description</em> of how the local cache should be updated after the change happened in the form of a <a href="https://facebook.github.io/relay/docs/guides-mutations.html#content">mutation</a> and then takes care of the update under the hood.</p>

<p>The description is provided by subclassing <code>Relay.Mutation</code> and implementing (at least) four methods that help Relay to properly update the local store:</p>

<ul>
<li><code>getMutation()</code>: the name of the mutation (from the GraphQL schema)</li>
<li><code>getVariables()</code>: the input variables for the mutation</li>
<li><code>getFatQuery()</code>: a GraphQL query that fetches all data that potentially was changed due to the mutation</li>
<li><code>getConfigs()</code>: a precise specification how the mutation should be incorporated into the cache</li>
</ul>


<p>In the following, we'll take a deeper look at the different kinds of mutations in our sample app, which are used for creating, updating and deleting Pokemons.</p>

<blockquote><p>Note: We're using the <a href="https://www.graph.cool/docs/reference/relay-api/overview-aizoong9ah">Graphcool Relay API</a> for this example. If you used <code>graphql-up</code> to create your own backend, you can explore the API by pasting the endpoint for the Relay API into the address bar of a browser.</p></blockquote>

<a name="Creating.a.new.Pokemon:..code.RANGE_ADD..code."></a>
<h3>Creating a new Pokemon: <code>RANGE_ADD</code></h3>

<p><img src="http://i.imgur.com/yskx5KU.png" alt="" /></p>

<p>Let's walk through the different methods and understand what information we have to provide so that Relay can successfully merge the newly created Pokemon into its store.</p>

<p>The first two methods, <code>getMutation()</code> and <code>getVariables()</code> are relatively obvious and can be retrieved directly from the documentation where the API is described.</p>

<p>The implementations look as follows:</p>

<pre><code class="js">getMutation() {
  return Relay.QL`mutation { createPokemon }`
}

getVariables() {
  return {
    name: this.props.name,
    url: this.props.url,
  }
}
</code></pre>

<p>Notice that the <code>props</code> of a <code>Relay.Mutation</code> are passed through its constructor. Here, we simply provide the <code>name</code> and the <code>url</code> of the Pokemon that is to be created.</p>

<p>Now, on to the interesting parts. In <code>getFatQuery()</code>, we need to specify the parts that might change due to the mutation. Here, we simply specify the <code>viewer</code>:</p>

<pre><code class="js">getFatQuery() {
  return Relay.QL`
    fragment on CreatePokemonPayload {
      viewer {
        allPokemons
      }
    }
  `
}
</code></pre>

<p>Notice that <em>every</em> subfield of <code>allPokemons</code> is also automatically included with this approach. In our example app, <code>allPokemons</code> is the only point we expect to change after our mutation is performed.</p>

<p>Finally, in <code>getConfigs()</code>, we need to specify the <a href="https://facebook.github.io/relay/docs/guides-mutations.html#mutator-configuration">mutator configurations</a>, telling Relay exactly how the new data should be incorporated into the cache. This is where the magic happens:</p>

<pre><code class="js">getConfigs() {
  return [{
    type: 'RANGE_ADD',
    parentName: 'viewer',
    parentID: this.props.viewerId,
    connectionName: 'allPokemons',
    edgeName: 'edge',
    rangeBehaviors: {
      '': 'append'
    }
  }]
}
</code></pre>

<p>We first express that we want to <em>add</em> the node using <code>RANGE_ADD</code> for the <code>type</code> (there are 5 different types in total).</p>

<p>Relay internally represents the stored data as a graph, so the remaining information expresses where exactly the new node should be hooked into the existing structure.</p>

<p>Let's consider the shape of the data before we move on:</p>

<pre><code>viewer {
  allPokemons {
    edges {
      node {
        id
        name
      }
    }
  }
}
</code></pre>

<p>Here we clearly see the direct connection between <code>viewer</code> and the Pokemons goes through <code>allPokemons</code> <em>connection</em>, so the <em>parent</em> of the new Pokemon is the <code>viewer</code>. The name of that connection is <code>allPokemons</code>, and lastly the <code>edgeName</code> is taken from the payload of the mutation.</p>

<p>The last piece, <code>rangeBehaviors</code>, specifies whether we want to <em>append</em> or <em>prepend</em> the new node.</p>

<p>Executing the mutation is as simple as calling <code>commitUpdate</code> on the <code>relay</code> prop that's injected to each component being wrapped with a <code>Relay.Container</code>. An instance of the mutation and the expected variables are passed as arguments to the constructor:</p>

<pre><code class="js">_sendCreatePokemonMutation = () =&gt; {
  const createPokemonMutation = new CreatePokemonMutation({
    viewerId: this.props.viewer.id,
    name: this.state.pokemonName,
    url: this.state.pokemonUrl,
  })
  this.props.relay.commitUpdate(createPokemonMutation)
}
</code></pre>

<a name="Updating.a.Pokemon:..code.FIELDS_CHANGE..code."></a>
<h3>Updating a Pokemon: <code>FIELDS_CHANGE</code></h3>

<p>Like with creating a Pokemon, <code>getMutation()</code> and <code>getVariables()</code> are trivial to implement and can be derived directly from the API documentation:</p>

<pre><code class="js">getMutation() {
  return Relay.QL`mutation { updatePokemon }`
}

getVariables() {
  return {
    id: this.props.id,
    name: this.props.name,
    url: this.props.url,
  }
}
</code></pre>

<p>In <code>getFatQuery()</code>, we only include the <code>pokemon</code> which includes the updated info this time, since that is the only part we expect to change after our mutation:</p>

<pre><code class="js">getFatQuery() {
  return Relay.QL`
    fragment on UpdatePokemonPayload {
      pokemon
    }
  `
}
</code></pre>

<p>Finally, <code>getConfigs()</code>, this time specifies a mutator configuration of type <code>FIELDS_CHANGE</code> since we're only updating properties on a single Pokemon:</p>

<pre><code class="js">getConfigs() {
  return [{
    type: 'FIELDS_CHANGE',
    fieldIDs: {
      pokemon: this.props.id,
    }
  }]
}
</code></pre>

<p>As sole additional piece of info, we declare the ID of the Pokemon that is being updated so that Relay has this information available when receiving the new Pokemon data.</p>

<a name="Deleting.a.Pokemon:..code.NODE_DELETE..code."></a>
<h3>Deleting a Pokemon: <code>NODE_DELETE</code></h3>

<p>As before, <code>getMutation()</code> and <code>getVariables()</code> are self-explanatory:</p>

<pre><code class="js">getMutation() {
  return Relay.QL`mutation { deletePokemon }`
}

getVariables() {
  return {
    id: this.props.id,
  }
}
</code></pre>

<p>Then, in <code>getFatQuery()</code>, we need to retrieve the <code>pokemon</code> from the mutation payload:</p>

<pre><code class="js">getFatQuery() {
  return Relay.QL`
    fragment on DeletePokemonPayload {
      pokemon
    }
  `
}
</code></pre>

<p>In <code>getConfigs()</code>, we're getting to know another mutator configuration type called <code>NODE_DELETE</code>. This one requires a <code>parentName</code> as well as a <code>connectionName</code>, both coming from the mutation payload and specifying where that node existed in Relay's data graph. Another requirement, that is specifically relevant for the implementation of a GraphQL server, is that the mutation payload of a deleting mutation always needs to return the <code>id</code> of the deleted node so that Relay can find that node in its store. Taking all of this together, our implementation of <code>getConfigs()</code> can be written like so:</p>

<pre><code class="js">getConfigs() {
  return [{
    type: 'NODE_DELETE',
    parentName: 'pokemon',
    connectionName: 'edge',
    deletedIDFieldName: 'deletedId'
  }]
}
</code></pre>

<a name="Wrapping.Up"></a>
<h2>Wrapping Up</h2>

<p>Relay has a lot of benefits that make it a very compelling framework to use for state management and interaction with GraphQL APIs. Its major strengths are a highly optimized cache, thoughtful UI integration as well as the declarative API for data fetching and mutations.</p>

<p>The initial version of Relay came with a notable learning curve due to lots of magic happening behind the scenes. However, Facebook recently released the first release candidates of <a href="https://github.com/facebook/relay/releases/">Relay v1.0.0</a> (<em>Relay Modern</em>) with the <a href="https://code.facebook.com/posts/1362748677097871">goal of making Relay generally more approachable</a>.</p>

<p>It's worth noting that Relay isn't the only available GraphQL client. Apollo Client is a great alternative which is a lot easier to get started with. <a href="https://www.graph.cool/docs/tutorials/relay-vs-apollo-iechu0shia/">For a detailed comparison please refer to this article.</a></p>

<p>If you want to learn more about GraphQL and want to stay up-to-date with the latest news of the GraphQL community, subscribe to <a href="https://graphqlweekly.com/">GraphQL Weekly</a>.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
