<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: graphql | Artsy Engineering]]></title>
  <link href="https://artsy.github.io/blog/categories/graphql/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="https://artsy.github.io/"/>
  <updated>2022-03-03T15:10:26+00:00</updated>
  <id>https://artsy.github.io/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Accessing the Relay Store Without a Mutation]]></title>
    <link href="https://artsy.github.io/blog/2021/04/15/accessing-the-relay-store/"/>
    <updated>2021-04-15T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <id>https://artsy.github.io/blog/2021/04/15/accessing-the-relay-store</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I recently encountered a problem where client-side data (returned from a Relay query) became out of sync after a
user interaction. How can we make sure our data is consistent while maintaining a single source of truth? This post
explores why a developer might want to update client-side data locally, the basics of Relay and its store, and how
to delete records in the store when you're not using a mutation.</p>

<a name="Relay.x.Artsy.x.Me"></a>
<h2>Relay x Artsy x Me</h2>

<p><a href="https://relay.dev/">Relay</a> is a GraphQL client library maintained by Facebook engineers and enables rapid client-side data
fetching in React applications. <a href="https://artsy.github.io/blog/2019/04/10/omakase-relay/">Artsy's adoption of Relay</a> coincided with our move
toward using React Native for our mobile work around 2016. I joined Artsy as an engineer in November of 2020 (after
<a href="https://medium.com/swlh/how-losing-my-job-helped-me-find-my-way-back-8c8f86552acc">transitioning to engineering from a non-technical role at the
company</a>.) When I joined, I was about a year into React development
and completely new to Relay.</p>

<!-- more -->


<p>I work on the Partner Experience (PX) team at Artsy. We build and maintain software used by our gallery and auction
house partners to sell artwork on Artsy. Although Relay is not new to Artsy, it’s relatively new to our team’s main
repository, Volt. (Volt is Artsy’s CMS used by gallery partners to manage their presences on the platform.) A topic
for another blog post, but Volt’s structure is worth noting here: Volt is a collection of mini React apps injected
into HAML views—our way of incrementally converting the codebase to our new stack.</p>

<p>Relay’s biggest advantage in my eyes is how it tightly couples the client view and API call (in our case, to the
GraphQL layer of our stack, which we call Metaphysics.) In addition to performance and other benefits, colocating a
component with its data requirements creates a pretty seamless developer experience.</p>

<a name="Building.an.Artwork.Checklist"></a>
<h2>Building an Artwork Checklist</h2>

<p>On the PX team, we recently launched a checklist feature aimed at empowering our gallery partners to be more
self-sufficient and find the greatest success possible on Artsy. The checklist prompts galleries to add specific
metadata to artworks that we know (because of our awesome data team) will make the work more likely to sell. The
new feature gathers a list of five high-priority artworks (meaning they are published, for-sale, and by a
top-selling artist) that are missing key pieces of metadata. The checklist prompts users to add the missing
metadata. Users also have the ability to click a button to “snooze” works, which removes them from the list for the
day.</p>

<p><figure class="illustration">
    <img src="https://user-images.githubusercontent.com/9466631/114630150-28886200-9c77-11eb-9f04-461101496ee0.png">
</figure></p>

<p>The feature makes use of <a href="https://redis.io/">Redis</a>, a key-value store used for in-memory cache, to store two lists:</p>

<ol>
<li><code>includeIDs</code> to store the five artworks in the list, so users see a consistent list of artworks whenever they
log in and load the page</li>
<li><code>excludeIDs</code> or “snoozed” IDs which Redis will store for 24 hours and ensure the user does not see</li>
</ol>


<p>When a user presses the “snooze” button, the ID for the artwork is added to the snoozed list in Redis. The list of
<code>includeIDs</code> and the list of <code>excludeIDs</code> are passed down from Rails controllers to our HAML views and then passed
as props into our React <code>HomePageChecklist</code> app. In our Checklist component, we use both the <code>includeIDs</code> and the
<code>excludeIDs</code> as arguments passed to our Relay query to determine what is returned from Metaphysics (Artsy's GraphQL
layer).</p>

<pre><code class="js">fragment ArtworksMissingMetadata_partner on Partner
  @argumentDefinitions(
    first: { type: "Int", defaultValue: 5 }
    after: { type: "String" }
    includeIDs: { type: "[String!]" }
    excludeIDs: { type: "[String!]" }
  ) {
    id
    artworksConnection(
      first: $first
      after: $after
      includeIDs: $includeIDs
      excludeIDs: $excludeIDs
    ) @connection(key: "ArtworksMissingMetadata_partner_artworksConnection", filters: []) {
      edges {
        node {
          ...ArtworksMissingMetadataItem_artwork
        }
      }
    }
  }
</code></pre>

<a name="Problem:.How.to.Change.the.Data.Displayed.When.a.User.Interacts.with.the.Page"></a>
<h2>Problem: How to Change the Data Displayed When a User Interacts with the Page</h2>

<p>The problem we were running into occurs when the user presses “snooze” on an item. We successfully update Redis
with the new snoozed item, but the UI still renders the item on the page. (This is because the response from Relay
becomes stale.) If the user refreshes the page, the list is correct: The up-to-date Redis <code>excludeIDS</code> list will be
passed into our component and used in the Relay query. But without refreshing the page, we need to make sure that
the list in the UI updates when the user snoozes an item.</p>

<p>The initial fix was to use a local state variable to keep track of which items were snoozed. We defined the following variable in the parent
React component that renders the list:</p>

<pre><code class="js">const [localSnoozedItems, setLocalSnoozedItems] = useState([])
</code></pre>

<p>We passed <code>localSnoozedItems</code> and <code>setLocalSnoozedItems</code> down to each of the children items. When the “snooze”
button was pressed on an item, the <code>localSnoozedItems</code> in the parent was updated with the complete list of snoozed
items. The parent then controls which items get rendered. We used the <code>localSnoozedItems</code> list to filter the connection
returned from our Relay query (which remember, is already filtered based on our Redis <code>excludeIDs</code> from Redis.)</p>

<p>This worked, but it definitely did not feel great to have two sources of truth for snoozing: The Redis key and the
local state variable.</p>

<a name="Solution:.Deleting.a.Record.From.the.Relay.Store"></a>
<h2>Solution: Deleting a Record From the Relay Store</h2>

<p>Cue the <a href="https://relay.dev/docs/api-reference/store/">RelayModernStore</a>! I learned that Relay keeps track of the GraphQL
data returned by each query in a store on the client. Each record in the store has a unique ID, and the store can be
changed, added to, and deleted from. There are a couple of helpful blog posts (like
<a href="https://yashmahalwal.medium.com/a-deep-dive-into-the-relay-store-9388affd2c2b">this</a> and
<a href="https://medium.com/entria/wrangling-the-client-store-with-the-relay-modern-updater-function-5c32149a71ac">this</a>) that explain the store and how to
interact with it.</p>

<p>In most of the Relay documentation, blog posts, and Artsy’s uses cases, the store is accessed through an <code>updater</code>
function via <a href="https://relay.dev/docs/guided-tour/updating-data/graphql-mutations/">mutations</a>. <a href="https://relay.dev/docs/guided-tour/updating-data/graphql-mutations/#updater-functions">Updater functions</a>
that return the store in the first argument can optionally be added to Relay mutations. Inside that function, you can access
the store to modify the records you need.</p>

<p>Here's an example:</p>

<pre><code class="js">commitMutation(defaultEnvironment, {
  mutation: graphql`
    mutation SomeMutation {
      ...
    }
  `,
  updater: (store) =&gt; {
    // Do something with the store
  },
})
</code></pre>

<p>In my use case, I was not using a Relay mutation because I did not need to modify anything on the server. Since
Redis is keeping track of our <code>excludeIDs</code> for us, any round trip to the server will be up-to-date. We just need to
modify our local data store.</p>

<p>Relay provides a <a href="https://relay.dev/docs/guided-tour/updating-data/local-data-updates/">separate API method to make local updates</a> to the Relay
store: <code>commitLocalUpdate</code>. <code>commitLocalUpdate</code> takes two arguments: the first is the Relay environment, which you
can easily access from the parent Relay fragment or refetch container. The second is an <code>updater</code> callback function
that returns the store in the first argument. We now have access to the store!</p>

<a name="Deleting.a.Connection.Node.with.ConnectionHandler"></a>
<h2>Deleting a Connection Node with ConnectionHandler</h2>

<p>My main hurdle during this journey was finding an appropriate way to hook into the store for our specific use case—when we do
not require an update to server data.</p>

<p>But to close us out: Let's finish the job and delete the item from the connection in the store.</p>

<p>When an item is snoozed, we call <code>commitLocalUpdate</code>, pass in the Relay environment, and then pass in the <code>updater</code>
function. Once we have access to the store, our goal is to delete this particular item from the
<code>artworksConnection</code>, which is the GraphQL object returned by our original Relay query.</p>

<p>Because we are dealing with connections, we want to use the <a href="https://relay.dev/docs/api-reference/store/#connectionhandler">ConnectionHandler
API</a> provided by Relay. <code>ConnectionHandler.getConnection</code> takes in the
connection's parent record (which we can find using the GraphQL ID added as a field on our query for the
connection) as the first argument and the connection key which can be provided through <a href="https://www.prisma.io/blog/relay-moderns-connection-directive-1ecd8322f5c8">Relay’s @connection
directive</a>.</p>

<p>Once we have the connection, we will use <code>ConnectionHandler.deleteNode</code> which takes the connection as the first
argument and the id to be deleted, which we can also easily access using the GraphQL ID added as a field to the
query for the item.</p>

<p>Bonus: Because <code>commitLocalUpdate</code> works anywhere in Relay land, we got to perform this deletion exactly where the
"snooze" action is happening: in the child item component. (In our previous solution, we had to manage the state of
the children from their parent component, which wasn't as intuitive.)</p>

<pre><code class="js">import { commitLocalUpdate } from "relay-runtime"

commitLocalUpdate(relay.environment, (store) =&gt; {
  const parentRecord = store.get(parentID)

  if (parentRecord) {
    const artworksConnection = ConnectionHandler.getConnection(
      parentRecord,
      "ArtworksMissingMetadata_partner_artworksConnection"
    )
    if (artworksConnection) {
      ConnectionHandler.deleteNode(artworksConnection, id)
    }
  }
})
</code></pre>

<a name="Key.Takeaways"></a>
<h2>Key Takeaways</h2>

<ol>
<li>Relay is great because it colocates a component with its data requirements.</li>
<li>The Relay store allows us to access and modify data that we are using on the client.</li>
<li><code>commitLocalUpdate</code> provides us access to the store if we just need to modify local data and aren’t using a
mutation to update server-side data.</li>
</ol>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Effortless Pagination with GraphQL and Relay? Really!]]></title>
    <link href="https://artsy.github.io/blog/2020/01/21/graphql-relay-windowed-pagination/"/>
    <updated>2020-01-21T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <id>https://artsy.github.io/blog/2020/01/21/graphql-relay-windowed-pagination</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>It's the year 2020. You use a modern front-end stack of <a href="https://relay.dev/">Relay</a>,
<a href="https://graphql.org/">GraphQL</a>, <a href="https://reactjs.org/">React</a> and <a href="https://www.typescriptlang.org/">TypeScript</a>.
You can build an infinite scroll 'feed' type UI totally out of the box with these tools, by mostly putting together
boilerplate (proper <a href="https://facebook.github.io/relay/graphql/connections.htm#sec-Connection-Types">connections</a>,
along with a <a href="https://relay.dev/docs/en/pagination-container">pagination container</a>). You have a design system, and
are rapidly building up a component library. Things are great!</p>

<p>Then you take a look at the latest design comps for a 'browse' type page, and you see that the
<a href="https://medium.com/simple-human/7-reasons-why-infinite-scrolling-is-probably-a-bad-idea-a0139e13c96b">controversial</a>
infinite scroll has been replaced by a more traditional pagination bar.</p>

<p>You know the one. Like the following, from <a href="https://www.amazon.com">Amazon</a>:</p>

<p><img src="/images/2020-01-21-graphql-relay-windowed-pagination/amazon.png"></p>

<p>You start to realize that the cursor-based setup of a connection, along with a Relay pagination container, does not
lend itself to this more traditional UI. For one thing, a user can arbitrarily 'jump' to any page by including a
<code>?page=X</code> query param (typically). For another, the user can only actually see the current page of content, versus
a feed. As you go to sleep and dream of REST, Rails controllers, <a href="https://github.com/kaminari/kaminari">kaminari</a>,
<a href="https://github.com/mislav/will_paginate">will_paginate</a>, and a simpler time, you start to have a vision...</p>

<!-- more -->


<p>To get a good primer of what a GraphQL connection is and why they're so useful, read this
<a href="https://blog.apollographql.com/explaining-graphql-connections-c48b7c3d6976">excellent Apollo blogpost</a>. Seriously.
It's one of the best writeups on this subject out there. I'll assume basic familiarity with connection types from
this point forward.</p>

<p>We prefer to use connections in place of lists almost always. Not only do they provide a preferred cursor-based
pagination API for clients, but their type specification (a map vs a list) is naturally forward-looking. Even if
you do no pagination, a pure list type can't accomodate returning other metadata (such as a <code>totalCount</code>) alongside
the list. Additionally, if your data is very relational and better represented as nodes connected by edges (which
would contain data about the 'join' of the two nodes), the connection type gives one more flexibility than a simple
list. This (and more) is all covered in the aforementioned blog post.</p>

<p>So, let's start by taking a look at our desired pagination UI, and think about what kind of schema/components make
sense.</p>

<p><img src="/images/2020-01-21-graphql-relay-windowed-pagination/pagination.png"></p>

<p>There looks to be several types of appearances we want to show, based on the total size of our list and fixed page
size chosen, as well as the current page. There's also some edge cases of empty lists, or lists that are short
enough to just display all their page numbers. Users can click on any displayed page number to jump to it. There's
a prev/next navigation, which brings the user forward and back one page at a time. Whenever the current page
changes, the URL should update accordingly. For a responsive implementation, we want to hide the page numbers, and
only show the prev/next toggles on small screens.</p>

<p>Wow! Ok, we have our work cut out for us. But wait til you see how easy this is! There'll be links to our actual
production components involved (all open-source) at the end.</p>

<a name="Pagination.Schema"></a>
<h2>Pagination Schema</h2>

<p>Let's tackle the first part of this, which is: how do we adapt the
<a href="https://facebook.github.io/relay/graphql/connections.htm">GraphQL connection spec</a> in order to hold necessary
information that a UI might need? Generally we want the UI's to be as simple as possible, and so if the server
could construct a suitable pagination schema, that would be preferable. The simpler our UI, and the more business
logic and good abstractions made in our GraphQL server, the more portable and reusable this all becomes.</p>

<p>What kind of data does the UI need, in order to render a particular page of contents? Well, for a particular page
we'd need to render the actual number it corresponds to. We'll need to know if this is the current page or not (so
we can distinguish it in the UI from neighboring pages). And, we'll need to know the actual cursor (think:
<a href="https://relay.dev/graphql/connections.htm">opaque string</a>) that corresponds to this page number. It seems likely
we'll need some sort of way to construct cursors from page numbers, on the server.</p>

<p>So, check this out:</p>

<pre><code class="js">// SDL
type PageCursor {
  cursor: String!
  pageNumber: Int!
  isCurrent: Boolean!
}

type PageCursors {
  first: PageCursor
  around: [PageCursor!]!
  last: PageCursor
  previous: PageCursor
}
</code></pre>

<p>This is our pagination schema. Including a field of type <code>pageCursors</code> as a connection-level field, onto a
connection, is sufficient for a UI to incredibly simply 'just render' a correct pagination bar always, and be able
to hook up proper interactions. We can fully construct a simple UI (using Relay, shown in the next section) that
can present and allow for the interactions desired, for windowed pagination.</p>

<p>But, of course we're glossing over the implementation for such a <code>pageCursors</code> type, so let's check that out before
looking at how a client might consume this.</p>

<p>Our backing API's largely still paginate via offsets, and not cursors. That is, they accept page/size or
size/offset style arguments. We use <a href="https://github.com/graphql/graphql-relay-js">graphql-relay-js</a>, which includes
helpers to make sure types and resolvers are compatible with some Relay expectations. So, we use this library to
generate our cursors, and can convert the cursor to an offset. A page of 4 with a size of 10, returns the elements
numbered 30 - 39 in that list. So a page of 4 (and size of 10), is equivalent to an offset of 29 (and size of 10).
We have:</p>

<pre><code class="js">const pageToCursor = (page, size) =&gt; {
  return String((page - 1) * size - 1)
}
</code></pre>

<p>This gives us the offset of the last value of the previous page. While our upstream services are all still
paginating using this size/offset method, the <a href="https://relay.dev/graphql/connections.htm">GraphQL cursor spec</a>
prefers opaque cursors to be used on the client. This allows the actual implementation of pagination to change
upstream while clients remain unaffected. Thus if we ever update our upstream pagination arguments/logic/setup, we
could update this schema implementation accordingly, and clients would continue to be functional.</p>

<p>For inspiration in constructing our <code>first</code>, <code>last</code>, and <code>around</code> groups, we turn to
<a href="https://www.fngtps.com/">Fingertips</a> and their
<a href="https://github.com/Fingertips/peiji-san/blob/6bd1bc7c152961dcde376a8bcb2ca393b5b45829/lib/peiji_san/view_helper.rb#L87">pagination library</a>.
That code goes through the various cases possible (a short list, a long list where the current page is near the
front, middle or end, various degenerate cases, etc.), and returns a proper structure that represents this data. It
can handle all combinations of list sizes, and current position relative to the total size.</p>

<p>In pseudo-code, it looks like:</p>

<pre><code class="js">if emptyList
  around = [1]
else if listIsShort
  around = [1...totalPages]
else if nearBeginning
  around = [1...3]
  last = [totalPages]
else if nearMiddle
  first = [1]
  middle = [currentPage-1, currentPage, currentPage+1]
  last = [totalPages]
else if nearEnd
  first = [1]
  around = [last-1, last, last+1]
</code></pre>

<p>Our full implementation of that method can be found
<a href="https://github.com/artsy/metaphysics/blob/205592be7f59970cf80313972ceb95bb1579c31f/src/schema/v2/fields/pagination.ts#L96">here</a>.</p>

<p>For a real-life example, check out
<a href="https://metaphysics-staging.artsy.net/v2?query=%7B%0AartworksConnection(first%3A5%2C%20after%3A%20%22YXJyYXljb25uZWN0aW9uOjE0%22)%20%7B%0A%20%20pageInfo%20%7B%0A%20%20%20%20hasNextPage%0A%20%20%20%20endCursor%0A%20%20%7D%0A%20%20pageCursors%7B%0A%20%20%20%20first%20%7B%0A%20%20%20%20%20%20cursor%0A%20%20%20%20%20%20page%0A%20%20%20%20%20%20isCurrent%0A%20%20%20%20%7D%0A%20%20%20%20last%20%7B%0A%20%20%20%20%20%20cursor%0A%20%20%20%20%20%20page%0A%20%20%20%20%20%20isCurrent%0A%20%20%20%20%7D%0A%20%20%20%20around%20%7B%0A%20%20%20%20%20%20cursor%0A%20%20%20%20%20%20page%0A%20%20%20%20%20%20isCurrent%0A%20%20%20%20%7D%0A%20%20%20%20previous%20%7B%0A%20%20%20%20%20%20page%0A%20%20%20%20%20%20cursor%0A%20%20%20%20%7D%0A%20%20%7D%0A%7D%7D">this link, corresponding to a page number of 4</a>.
You can adjust the arguments to see how the output changes based on where you are in the list. Try putting
different cursor values in! It looks like:</p>

<p><img src="/images/2020-01-21-graphql-relay-windowed-pagination/graphiql.png"></p>

<p>Let's look at a couple of other pieces of data requested here. One of these is a <code>previous</code> page cursor. This is to
support that action (the prev/next toggles) in the UI. However, we don't need a custom <code>next</code> item to support that
behavior. That's because we tend to use
<a href="https://facebook.github.io/relay/graphql/connections.htm#sec-Forward-pagination-arguments">forward-style pagination arguments</a>
with connections, which means the connection will already return the data needed for that action (remember, you can
implement a scrolling infinite scroll feed that always takes you to the next page right out of the box).
Specifically, the <code>hasNextPage</code> and <code>endCursor</code> are those fields from the
<a href="https://facebook.github.io/relay/graphql/connections.htm#sec-undefined.PageInfo.Fields">GraphQL <code>pageInfo</code> object</a>
which give you that information.</p>

<a name="Companion.UI.Component"></a>
<h2>Companion UI Component</h2>

<p>Ok, now that we have a connection and corresponding fields that provide the needed data, let's take a look at a
simple React component that can render this:</p>

<pre><code class="js">const Page = ({pageCursor: { page, cursor }}) =&gt; {
  return (
    &lt;Button onClick={() =&gt; onClick(cursor)}&gt;
      {page}
    &lt;/Button&gt;
  )
}

// Show page 1 if `first` is present, and append with dots
// Show everything in `around`
// Show last page if present, and prepend with dots
//
// Show previous toggle, active if present
// Show next toggle, active if next page exists
return (
  &lt;&gt;
    {&lt;Button disabled={!previous} onClick={() =&gt; onClick(previous.cursor)}&gt;Previous&lt;/Button&gt;}
    {first &amp;&amp; (&lt;&gt;&lt;Page pageCursor={first} /&gt;...&lt;/&gt;)}
    {around.map(page =&gt; &lt;Page pageCursor={page}&gt;)}
    {last &amp;&amp; (&lt;&gt;...&lt;Page pageCursor={last} /&gt;&lt;/&gt;)}
    {&lt;Button disabled={!hasNextPage} onClick={() =&gt; onNext()}&gt;Next&lt;/Button&gt;}
  &lt;/&gt;
)
</code></pre>

<p>That's basically it, visually speaking! The data provided by our GraphQL server is sufficient to render what's
needed. You can see such a UI component in our design system
<a href="https://github.com/artsy/palette/blob/f882d32c3fdc6e7f81915c2922e3824bd26791e7/packages/palette/src/elements/Pagination/Pagination.tsx">here</a>.
It looks very similar to the above code. Of note, is since this is a simple UI component, it is vanilla React. It
is not a Relay component. It requires an <code>onClick</code> and <code>onNext</code> to be passed as props.</p>

<a name="Relay.Integration.Step.I"></a>
<h2>Relay Integration Step I</h2>

<p>Now, let's take a look at how we can build a Relay container that will use the above UI component. First, let's
build a Relay-wrapped component of the above UI component. This is a fragment container, and lists all the fields
needed:</p>

<pre><code class="js">fragment Pagination_pageCursors on PageCursors {
  around {
    cursor
    page
    isCurrent
  }
  first {
    cursor
    page
    isCurrent
  }
  last {
    cursor
    page
    isCurrent
  }
  previous {
    cursor
    page
  }
}
</code></pre>

<p>As a fragment container, this doesn't have the ability to fetch anything by itself. We want to pass in an <code>onClick</code>
and <code>onNext</code> prop from a parent, as well as the <code>hasNextPage</code> and <code>endCursor</code> data. Check out
<a href="https://github.com/artsy/reaction/blob/c6d630f8c3213f47c5124f63eda13fbb9d8f497b/src/Components/v2/Pagination.tsx">this component</a>
in our library to see how we take that vanilla React component mentioned above, and use the above fragment to make
a Relay fragment container out of it.</p>

<p>Now, we need to decide what kind of parent container is appropriate, and how this fragment container will be used.</p>

<a name="Relay.Integration.Step.II"></a>
<h2>Relay Integration Step II</h2>

<p>This is going to be confusing, but for this step, we use a
<a href="https://relay.dev/docs/en/refetch-container">refetch container</a> in order to present our paginated collection view,
rather than the aptly-named <a href="https://relay.dev/docs/en/pagination-container">Relay pagination container</a>. The
latter is more suited for an infinite scroll feed view (presenting all content already fetched, only adjacent pages
in a particular direction are able to be scrolled to, etc.) vs. the windowed pagination we are trying to
accomplish. The refetch container is a much more natural fit for our use case, despite the naming.</p>

<p>That fragment looks like:</p>

<pre><code class="js">fragment ConnectionResults_query on Query {
  someConnection(first: $first, after: $after) {
    pageInfo {
      hasNextPage
      endCursor
    }
    pageCursors {
      ...Pagination_pageCursors
    }
    ...OtherStuffForYourView
  }
}
</code></pre>

<p>We include our <code>pageCursors</code> fragment, as well as the <code>hasNextPage</code> and <code>endCursor</code> from the <code>pageInfo</code> object. We
need to provide the <code>onClick</code> and <code>onNext</code> callbacks as well. Since this component will have access to a
<a href="https://relay.dev/docs/en/refetch-container#refetch"><code>relay</code> prop</a> since it is a refetch container, those look
like:</p>

<pre><code class="js">handleNext = () =&gt; {
  if (hasNextPage) this.handleClick(endCursor)
}

handleClick = (cursor: string) =&gt; {
  this.props.relay.refetch(
    {
      first: PAGE_SIZE,
      after: cursor
    },
    null,
    error =&gt; {
      /* Update URL, set state, etc. */
    }
  )
}
</code></pre>

<p>The refetch query defined for the container will look like:</p>

<pre><code class="js">query SomeConnectionQuery($first: Int, $after: String) {
  ...ConnectionResults_query @arguments(first: $first, after: $after)
}
</code></pre>

<p>We're pretty much done, this is all just Relay boilerplate at this point.</p>

<p>Putting it all together, our refetch container winds up rendering a fully functional pagination component in one
line:</p>

<pre><code class="js">&lt;Pagination onClick={handleClick} onNext={handleNext} pageCursors={props.pageCursors} /&gt;
</code></pre>

<p>That's it! Any connection can have this pagination functionality added to it very simply. You include the page
cursor schema on the server for that type (we have a
<a href="https://github.com/artsy/metaphysics/blob/205592be7f59970cf80313972ceb95bb1579c31f/src/schema/v2/fields/pagination.ts#L160">factory method</a>
to help us do that automatically for any connection type). Then, following the above steps, you can quickly build a
Relay refetch container that displays and seamlessly paginates any list.</p>

<p>You can see an example of this in numerous places on the <a href="https://www.artsy.net">Artsy</a> website. Head on over to
our <a href="https://www.artsy.net/collect">Artworks browse experience</a> and have fun filtering and searching/browsing
through all accessible works! The pagination controls and functionality on this page, and others, are built using
the technique described in this post.</p>

<a name="Examples"></a>
<h2>Examples</h2>

<p>Since our <a href="https://github.com/artsy/metaphysics">GraphQL orchestration layer</a>, our
<a href="https://github.com/artsy/palette">design system</a> and
<a href="https://github.com/artsy/reaction">UI component and app library</a> are all open source, here's links to our actual
production implementation of the above:</p>

<ul>
<li><a href="https://github.com/artsy/metaphysics/blob/205592be7f59970cf80313972ceb95bb1579c31f/src/schema/v2/fields/pagination.ts">Pagination schema in GraphQL</a></li>
<li><a href="https://github.com/artsy/palette/blob/f882d32c3fdc6e7f81915c2922e3824bd26791e7/packages/palette/src/elements/Pagination/Pagination.tsx">React UI component</a></li>
<li><a href="https://github.com/artsy/reaction/blob/c6d630f8c3213f47c5124f63eda13fbb9d8f497b/src/Components/v2/Pagination.tsx">Relay FragmentContainer wrapping of the above</a></li>
<li><a href="https://github.com/artsy/reaction/blob/c6d630f8c3213f47c5124f63eda13fbb9d8f497b/src/Apps/Search/Routes/Artists/SearchResultsArtists.tsx">Relay RefetchContainer full example</a></li>
</ul>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Better GraphQL Error Handling I - Using Custom Directives]]></title>
    <link href="https://artsy.github.io/blog/2020/01/13/graphql-custom-directives/"/>
    <updated>2020-01-13T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <id>https://artsy.github.io/blog/2020/01/13/graphql-custom-directives</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>This will be the first in a series of posts about how we used advanced GraphQL tooling and functionality to better
handle errors occurring during query resolution, and better equip clients to reason about such errors.</p>

<p>The goal is to describe our current approach, but also do a deep dive into specific ways we've extended our
<a href="https://github.com/artsy/metaphysics">GraphQL server</a> to help us accomplish that. If you are an interested GraphQL
user, you may find this useful, even if some of the larger context specifically around how we are using it to help
standardize error handling doesn't apply.</p>

<!-- more -->


<a name="Introduction.and.Initial.Context"></a>
<h2>Introduction and Initial Context</h2>

<p>At Artsy, we use GraphQL as our API language of choice. In particular,
<a href="https://artsy.github.io/blog/2018/05/08/is-graphql-the-future/">as</a>
<a href="https://artsy.github.io/blog/2016/06/19/graphql-for-mobile/">we've described</a>
<a href="https://artsy.github.io/blog/2016/11/02/improving-page-speed-with-graphql/">before</a>, we have an orchestration
layer speaking GraphQL, which is what our front-end clients talk to. The GraphQL orchestration layer wraps up
access to several backend services, which are made accessible via a combination of data loaders and
<a href="https://www.apollographql.com/docs/apollo-server/features/schema-stitching/">schema stitching</a>.
<a href="https://www.apollographql.com/docs/apollo-server/federation/introduction/">Apollo Federation</a> is another tool
people are using to bring together disparate backends when using GraphQL in an orchestration layer.</p>

<p>Now, consider the following query, which is a realistic one you might see when accessing a 'product' page.</p>

<pre><code class="javascript">{
  artwork(id: "andy-warhol-skull") {
    mainContentStuff
    biographicalData
    userReviews {
        ...
    }  # Accesses a back-end reviews service
    ...
  }
}
</code></pre>

<p>Part of the <a href="https://graphql.github.io/graphql-spec/">GraphQL spec</a> advises that one should return a 2XX status
code, even if there are exceptions raised when resolving your query. A non-2XX status code from a GraphQL server
would indicate an error with the server itself. Errors that occur during query resolution can be consolidated and
placed in the <code>errors</code> key of the response. This is all
<a href="https://graphql.github.io/graphql-spec/draft/#sec-Errors">advised by the spec</a>, and so is found in most GraphQL
implementations.</p>

<p>Given that this query likely backs a product page, some questions about possible error handling behavior that
immediately arise:</p>

<ul>
<li>If there are multiple fields erroring, which error (if any) is reported to the user?</li>
<li>How does the UI decide whether an error is recoverable? That is, if the <code>mainContentStuff</code> field for a view has
errored, that's probably not recoverable, and appropriate feedback should be displayed. But, if user reviews are
unavailable at this time, it's likely you might still want to render the main view, but with that section
appropriately handled. Is there a generic way to handle this?</li>
</ul>


<a name="Using.a.Directive.to.Eliminate.Ambiguity"></a>
<h2>Using a Directive to Eliminate Ambiguity</h2>

<p>We decided to allow our UI components to declare, using a GraphQL directive, one and only one field in a query to
optionally be the 'principal field'. That is, this is the field that, if there are any errors resolving it, should
result in an entire view rendering an appropriate error state. For web, this means a non-2XX status code and
resulting error page. Any errors occurring in field resolution of non-principal fields should still result in a 2XX
to the user, and the UI should be able to gracefully recover from the missing data. Since we use
React/Relay/GraphQL, and GraphQL queries are colocated with UI components, a GraphQL directive is particularly
useful.</p>

<p>Rewriting the above query, we might do something like:</p>

<pre><code class="javascript">{
  artwork(id: "andy-warhol-skull") {
    mainContentStuff @principalField
    biographicalData
    userReviews {
        ...
    }  # Accesses a back-end reviews service
    ...
  }
}
</code></pre>

<p>This would mean that any errors occuring in resolving <code>mainContentStuff</code> would result in either a 500 status code
and error page to the user, or possibly a more specific error and status code. However, any errors occurring in
resolving user reviews or other fields, would not cause a 500 and error page. Instead, there would be a 200 and the
UI would render. This means that our UI components should generally be defensive about their incoming props being
<code>null</code> (which is likely what you'd see when the corresponding field errors during query resolution). Using
TypeScript and
<a href="https://www.typescriptlang.org/docs/handbook/release-notes/typescript-2-0.html">strict null checking</a> can help
make your UI bulletproof to these sorts of issues.</p>

<p>With this context, let's look at how we implement a custom <code>@principalField</code> GraphQL directive. Future posts in
this series talking about custom GraphQL functionality will likely skip this intro section.</p>

<a name="Implementing.a.Custom.GraphQL.Directive"></a>
<h2>Implementing a Custom GraphQL Directive</h2>

<p>First, we have a new directive that we'd like to add to our schema. That is, we'd like a client to be able to
specify <code>@principalField</code> alongside any field, and have that query be validated correctly by the server. You can
<a href="https://metaphysics-staging.artsy.net/?query=%7B%0Aartwork(id%3A%22andy-warhol-skull%22)%20%40nonExistentDirective%7B%0A%20%20id%0A%7D%7D">see for yourself</a>
how <a href="https://github.com/graphql/graphql-js">graphql-js</a> and
<a href="https://github.com/graphql/express-graphql">express-graphql</a> respond when an unknown directive is specified. Your
GraphQL server implementation may look slightly different.</p>

<p>Turns out, that's pretty easy to do in <code>graphql-js</code>. We declare a variable of type <code>GraphQLDirective</code>, which
operates on a <code>DirectiveLocation.FIELD</code> location:</p>

<pre><code class="javascript">const PrincipalFieldDirective = new GraphQLDirective({
  name: "principalField",
  locations: [DirectiveLocation.FIELD]
})
</code></pre>

<p>and then when we create our schema, we pass this in as <code>directives</code>. Since this will overwrite the
<a href="https://www.apollographql.com/docs/apollo-server/schema/directives/">default directives</a>, we need to append ours.</p>

<p>Something like:</p>

<pre><code class="javascript">import { specifiedDirectives } from "graphql"

new GraphQLSchema({
  directives: [...specifiedDirectives, PrincipalFieldDirective],
  query: ...
  ...
})
</code></pre>

<p>In terms of the SDL for your schema, this is equivalent to the following line:</p>

<pre><code>directive @principalField on FIELD
</code></pre>

<p>That's it! You've successfully added a new directive to your schema. At this point, your GraphQL server will
properly validate and allow a <code>@principalField</code> directive specified by a client alongside any field. Now, we do
want to ensure that if this directive is used, it only appears once in your query. We can accomplish this with a
custom GraphQL validation, which we'll cover in the next post.</p>

<p>So now, how should we implement the functionality of this directive? We decided that we want to use the
<a href="https://github.com/graphql/graphql-spec/blob/master/spec/Section%207%20--%20Response.md#response-format">extensions</a>
part of our GraphQL response to carry this data, a free-form map of data up to the implementor, which is a perfect
fit for this type of optional additional information. If an error occurs in a field tagged with the directive, we
want the response to look something like:</p>

<pre><code class="json">{
  "data": {
    ...
  },
  "extensions": {
    "principalField": {
      "error": ...
    }
  }
}
</code></pre>

<p>In <code>express-graphql</code>, we'll need a method appropriate for the
<a href="https://github.com/graphql/express-graphql#options">extensions</a> option. That looks like:</p>

<pre><code class="javascript">const principalFieldDirectiveExtension = ({ documentAST, result }) =&gt; {
  const path = getPrincipalFieldDirectivePath(documentAST)
  if (path.length) {
    const error = result.errors.find(e =&gt; isEqual(e.path, path))
    if (error) return { principalField: error }
  }
}
</code></pre>

<p>If there is a field designated with the principal field directive, and there is an error at that same path, we'll
return that information, otherwise do nothing.</p>

<p>That's it! We have one additional helper we need to write, <code>getPrincipalFieldDirectivePath</code>. This builds an array
of all the fields encountered to get to one tagged with our directive. It matches the way the
<a href="https://graphql.github.io/graphql-spec/June2018/#sec-Errors">path of an error</a> is constructed by the server, which
enables us to determine if a particular error was associated with a field tagged with the directive.</p>

<p>That looks like:</p>

<pre><code class="javascript">import { visit, BREAK, DocumentNode } from "graphql"

export const getPrincipalFieldDirectivePath = (documentNode: DocumentNode): string[] =&gt; {
  const path: string[] = []
  visit(documentNode, {
    Field: {
      enter(node) {
        const name = (node.alias || node.name).value
        path.push(name)
      },
      leave() {
        path.pop()
      }
    },
    Directive(node) {
      if (node.name.value === "principalField") {
        return BREAK
      }
    }
  })

  return path
}
</code></pre>

<p>This uses a <a href="https://graphql.org/graphql-js/language/#visit">GraphQL visitor</a> to traverse our query, and build up
an array of field names. We can exit early with that path if we encounter our directive.</p>

<a name="Example.Query"></a>
<h2>Example Query</h2>

<p>Let's take a look at how you can use this in practice, in order to help standardize when and with what status a UI
can inform the user of an error.</p>

<p>Something like:</p>

<pre><code>{
  artwork(id: "andy-warhol-skull") @principalField {
    userReviews {
      notes
    }
    contents
    ...
  }
}
</code></pre>

<p>results in:</p>

<pre><code class="json">{
  "data": {
    "artwork": null
  },
  "extensions": {
    "principalFieldError": {
      "httpStatusCode": 404
    }
  }
}
</code></pre>

<p>and the UI can immediately return an appropriate message to the user, if the artwork is not found. If fetching the
artwork is successful, but there's an issue with the reviews, the response will look like:</p>

<pre><code class="json">{
  "data": {
    "artwork": {
      "userReviews": null,
      "contents": ...
    }
  }
}
</code></pre>

<p>We can make sure that our UI components (likely Relay containers) corresponding to <code>userReviews</code> are defensive
about that incoming prop being <code>null</code>. Most likely a zero state ("No Reviews Found"), or just skipping the section
entirely, is appropriate.</p>

<a name="Conclusion"></a>
<h2>Conclusion</h2>

<p>In this way, we can standardize on and remove ambiguity about how a UI handles one or more errors in query
resolution and exactly when such an error should be propagated and made user-facing. We can help ensure that our
UI's are resilient to errors occurring in a leaf.</p>

<p>In the next post, we'll look at how we can write a GraphQL validation rule to ensure that a client specifies at
most one field with the <code>@principalField</code> directive. After that, we'll take a look at how you can successfully
parse and support GraphQL query resolution errors occurring in a variety of contexts such as during stitching.
Putting this altogether, we hope you will come away with a better understanding of how to extend your GraphQL
server with your own custom behaviors, and in particular how we've used these to better log/propagate/present the
potential errors occurring during a query.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[From TSLint to ESLint, or How I Learned to Lint GraphQL Code]]></title>
    <link href="https://artsy.github.io/blog/2019/01/29/from-tslint-to-eslint/"/>
    <updated>2019-01-29T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <id>https://artsy.github.io/blog/2019/01/29/from-tslint-to-eslint</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>At the beginning of January we discovered an interesting note in <a href="https://github.com/Microsoft/TypeScript/issues/29288">TypeScript's roadmap</a> about linting:</p>

<blockquote><p>In a survey we ran in VS Code a few months back, the most frequent theme we heard from users was that the linting
experience left much to be desired. Since part of our team is dedicated to editing experiences in JavaScript, our
editor team set out to add support for both TSLint and ESLint. However, we noticed that there were a few
architectural issues with the way TSLint rules operate that impacted performance. Fixing TSLint to operate more
efficiently would require a different API which would break existing rules (unless an interop API was built like
what wotan provides).</p>

<p>Meanwhile, ESLint already has the more-performant architecture we're looking for from a linter. Additionally,
different communities of users often have lint rules (e.g. rules for React Hooks or Vue) that are built for
ESLint, but not TSLint.</p>

<p>Given this, our editor team will be focusing on leveraging ESLint rather than duplicating work. For scenarios
that ESLint currently doesn't cover (e.g. semantic linting or program-wide linting), we'll be working on sending
contributions to bring ESLint's TypeScript support to parity with TSLint. As an initial testbed of how this works
in practice, we'll be switching the TypeScript repository over to using ESLint, and sending any new rules
upstream.</p></blockquote>

<p>At Artsy we've been using TSLint for a few years now; it's worked well for us, and we've even written our own
<a href="https://github.com/relay-tools/tslint-plugin-relay">custom rules</a>. However, given the vastness of the JS ecosystem
and how fast it moves, it's easy to recognize this announcement as an exciting moment for tooling simplicity.</p>

<!-- more -->


<p>To give an example, anyone who has built a culture around Airbnb's
<a href="https://github.com/airbnb/javascript">JavaScript style guide</a> will instantly recognize the conundrum they're in
when migrating to TypeScript:</p>

<p><img width="100%" alt="a reddit user discovers their linting rules no longer work" src="https://user-images.githubusercontent.com/236943/51884369-d845b380-233b-11e9-9d2f-102cc8a3a78b.png"></p>

<p>This means that teams maintaining legacy JavaScript codebases will no longer have to <em>also</em> maintain
<a href="https://github.com/palantir/tslint-react">two</a> <a href="https://github.com/yannickcr/eslint-plugin-react">versions</a> of often nearly <a href="https://github.com/prettier/tslint-plugin-prettier">identical</a>
<a href="https://github.com/prettier/prettier-eslint">rule-sets</a>. All of the aggregate culture that builds up around linting can now be shared in a
forward and backward facing way, making the often-daunting process of migrating a codebase from JavaScript to
TypeScript a much easier sell.</p>

<p>With this in mind we wanted to give the new officially-sanctioned <a href="https://github.com/typescript-eslint/typescript-eslint">typescript-eslint</a> project a
spin and document our findings.</p>

<a name="Setup"></a>
<h3>Setup</h3>

<p>To get started, install the necessary dependencies:</p>

<pre><code class="sh">$ yarn install -D eslint typescript @typescript-eslint/eslint-plugin
</code></pre>

<p>Then create a new <code>.eslintrc.js</code> and add a bit of setup:</p>

<pre><code class="js">module.exports = {
  parser: "@typescript-eslint/parser",
  plugins: ["@typescript-eslint"],
  extends: ["eslint:recommended", "plugin:@typescript-eslint/recommended"],
  parserOptions: {
    ecmaVersion: 6,
    project: "./tsconfig.json",
    sourceType: "module"
  }
}
</code></pre>

<p>Note that <code>parserOptions.project</code> points to your <code>tsconfig.json</code> file:</p>

<pre><code class="json">{
  "compilerOptions": {}
}
</code></pre>

<p>Next, add a bit of TypeScript to a file</p>

<pre><code class="sh">$ echo "export const foo: any = 'bar'" &gt; index.ts
</code></pre>

<p>and run the linter:</p>

<pre><code class="sh">$ yarn eslint . --ext .ts,.tsx

~/index.ts
  1:12  warning  Unexpected any. Specify a different type  @typescript-eslint/no-explicit-any

✖ 1 problem (0 errors, 1 warnings)
</code></pre>

<p>Very nice!</p>

<p>Now lets expand the example a bit and add something more sophisticated, which in Artsy's use-case is commonly
GraphQL:</p>

<pre><code class="sh">$ yarn add -D eslint-plugin-graphql graphql-tag apollo
</code></pre>

<p>Update <code>tsconfig.json</code> and let it know we'll be using <code>node</code> for imports:</p>

<pre><code class="json">{
  "compilerOptions": {
    "moduleResolution": "node"
  }
}
</code></pre>

<p>In <code>.eslintrc.js</code> add these rules (while noting the addition of <code>graphql</code> to <code>plugins</code> and
<code>graphql/template-strings</code> under <code>rules</code>):</p>

<pre><code class="js">const path = require("path")

module.exports = {
  parser: "@typescript-eslint/parser",
  plugins: ["@typescript-eslint", "graphql"],
  extends: ["eslint:recommended", "plugin:@typescript-eslint/recommended"],
  parserOptions: {
    ecmaVersion: 6,
    project: "./tsconfig.json",
    sourceType: "module"
  },
  rules: {
    "graphql/template-strings": [
      "error",
      {
        schemaJsonFilepath: path.resolve(__dirname, "./schema.json"),
        tagName: "graphql"
      }
    ]
  }
}
</code></pre>

<p>For GraphQL to know what to lint, we'll need a schema. Thankfully the
<a href="https://etmdb.com/graphql">Ethiopian Movie Database</a> has our back :)</p>

<pre><code class="sh">$ yarn apollo service:download --endpoint https://etmdb.com/graphql
  ✔ Loading Apollo Project
  ✔ Saving schema to schema.json
✨  Done in 2.18s.
</code></pre>

<p>Back in <code>index.ts</code>, add this bit of code:</p>

<pre><code class="js">import graphql from "graphql-tag"

export const MovieQuery = graphql`
  query MoveQuery {
    allCinemaDetails(before: "2017-10-04", after: "2010-01-01") {
      edges {
        nodez {
          slug
          hallName
        }
      }
    }
  }
`
</code></pre>

<p>And run the linter:</p>

<pre><code class="sh">$ yarn eslint . --ext .ts,.tsx

~/index.ts
  7:9  error  Cannot query field "nodez" on type "CinemaDetailNodeEdge". Did you mean "node"?  graphql/template-strings

✖ 1 problem (1 error, 0 warnings)
</code></pre>

<p>Ahh yes, I meant <a href="https://i.redd.it/tfugj4n3l6ez.png"><code>node</code></a>.</p>

<a name="Bonus:.VSCode.Integration"></a>
<h3>Bonus: VSCode Integration</h3>

<p>As developers, we like our tools to work for us, and in 2019 the tool that <em>seems</em> to do that best just happens to
be a brilliant open source product from Microsoft. There were a couple unexpected configuration issues when we were
setting this up, but thankfully they're easy fixes.</p>

<pre><code class="sh">$ mkdir .vscode &amp;&amp; touch .vscode/settings.json
</code></pre>

<p>Then add a couple settings:</p>

<pre><code class="json">{
  "editor.formatOnSave": true,
  "eslint.autoFixOnSave": true,
  "eslint.validate": [
    {
      "language": "javascript",
      "autoFix": true
    },
    {
      "language": "javascriptreact",
      "autoFix": true
    },
    {
      "language": "typescript",
      "autoFix": true
    },
    {
      "language": "typescriptreact",
      "autoFix": true
    }
  ],
  "tslint.enable": false
}
</code></pre>

<p>Format on save, fix on save, <em>autofix</em> on save, tell ESLint to recognize <code>.ts</code> (and <code>.tsx</code>, for the React folks)
then disable <code>tslint</code> so that <code>eslint</code> can do its thing:</p>

<p><img width="698" alt="eslint displaying graphql error in VSCode IDE" src="https://user-images.githubusercontent.com/236943/51884366-d380ff80-233b-11e9-8128-6c39e210dd31.png"></p>

<p>Now ESLint will show you right where your GraphQL error is from within VSCode. Pretty sweet.</p>

<p>Be sure to read <a href="https://eslint.org/blog/2019/01/future-typescript-eslint">The future of TypeScript on ESLint</a> for more details.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[GraphQL: Union vs. Interface]]></title>
    <link href="https://artsy.github.io/blog/2019/01/14/graphql-union-vs-interface/"/>
    <updated>2019-01-14T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <id>https://artsy.github.io/blog/2019/01/14/graphql-union-vs-interface</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>At Artsy we’ve been moving towards GraphQL for all of our new services. Acknowledging GraphQL is a relatively new
technology, we faced some challenging questions as we were developing one of our most recent services.</p>

<p>Naively as my first attempt to define GraphQL types and schemas, I naturally tried to map our database models to
GraphQL types. While this may work for lot of cases, we may not be utilizing some of the useful features that come
with GraphQL that can make the consuming of our data a lot easier.</p>

<a name="GraphQL:.Interface.or.Union."></a>
<h2>GraphQL: Interface or Union?</h2>

<p>Think of the case where we are trying to expose search functionality and the result of our search can be either a
<code>Book</code> , <code>Movie</code> or <code>Album</code>. One way to think about this is to have our search query return something like:</p>

<!-- more -->


<pre><code class="js">search(term: "something") {
  books {
    id
    title
    author
  }
  movies {
    id
    title
    director
  }
  albums {
    id
    name
  }
}
</code></pre>

<p>While ☝️ works, we can’t rank the result based on relevance in one result set. Ideally, we would return one result
set that can have different types in it. A naive approach for this could be to only return one type in the results:</p>

<pre><code class="js">search(term: "something") {
  results {
    id
    name
    author   // when a book
    director // when a movie
    title    // when a movie/book
  }
}
</code></pre>

<p>We could have a single object that has all these values as optional properties:</p>

<pre><code class="js">type Result {
  id: ID!
  name: String!

  // All of the optional data, available as nullable types
  author: String
  director: String
  title: String
}
</code></pre>

<p>But returning these Result objects would be very messy on the server and for clients, plus it would undermine using
GraphQL's type system.</p>

<p>There are two main solutions in the GraphQL toolkit for this problem:
<a href="https://graphql.org/learn/schema/#union-types">Unions</a> and
<a href="https://graphql.org/learn/schema/#interfaces">Interfaces</a>.</p>

<a name="Union"></a>
<h3>Union</h3>

<p>GraphQL interfaces are useful to solve problems like above where we want to have the returned type possibly from
different types.</p>

<p>For this to work, we can define a <code>Union</code> type that can resolve to either one of <code>Book</code>, <code>Movie</code> or <code>Album</code> and
then each type can have its own set of fields.</p>

<p>In <code>graphql-ruby</code> you can define Unions with:</p>

<pre><code class="ruby">class Types::Movie &lt; Types::BaseObject
  field :id, ID, null: false
  field :title, String, null: false
  field :director, String, null: false
end

class Types::Book &lt; Types::BaseObject
  field :id, ID, null: false
  field :title, String, null: false
end

class Types::Album &lt; Types::BaseObject
  field :id, ID, null: false
  field :name, String, null: false
end

class SearchResultUnionType &lt; Types::BaseUnion
  description 'Represents either a Movie, Book or Album'
  possible_types Book, Movie, Album
  def self.resolve_type(object, _context)
    case object
    when Movie then Types::Movie
    when Book then Types::Book
    when Album then Types::Album
    else
      raise "Unknown search result type"
    end
  end
end
</code></pre>

<p>With the above change you can now query for search results and use specific fragments for different result types:</p>

<pre><code class="js">query {
  search(term: "something") {
    ... on Movie {
      __typename
      id
      title
    }
    ... on Book {
      __typename
      id
      title
    }
    ... on Album {
      __typename
      id
      name
    }
  }
}
</code></pre>

<pre><code class="json">{
  "data": [
    {
      "__typename": "Movie",
      "id": 1,
      "title": "Close-Up"
    },
    {
      "__typename": "Album",
      "id": 2,
      "name": "Dark Side Of The Moon"
    }
  ]
}
</code></pre>

<a name="Interface"></a>
<h3>Interface</h3>

<p>Unions are useful when we are trying to group different types together in one field. Now let’s think of the case
where we are trying to expose models of the same Type that can have different fields populated.</p>

<p>For example a music <code>Instrument</code> can have strings or not. If it has strings we want to mention how many strings it
has in <code>numberOfStrings</code> field. For any non-string instrument this field would be <code>null</code> in the database.</p>

<p>One way to do this is to have the <code>Instrument</code> Type always have <code>numberOfStrings</code> and in the case of non-string
instruments return <code>nil</code>. Sample result for this would be:</p>

<pre><code class="json">{
  "data": [
    {
      "id": 1,
      "name": "Guitar",
      "numberOfStrings": 6
    },
    {
      "id": 2,
      "name": "Drums",
      "numberOfStrings": null
    }
  ]
}
</code></pre>

<p>The above solution would work, but it will add extra work on the clients to decide if <code>numberOfStrings</code> is even
applicable to this current instrument or not.</p>

<p>The more GraphQL approach for this would be to use an <code>Interface</code>. We can define a generic <code>Instrument</code> interface and
have all the common fields between all instruments defined there. Then we can have each specific category of
instruments define its own special fields and then access those specific fields using fragments.</p>

<p>In <code>graphql-ruby</code> you can define an Interface with:</p>

<pre><code class="ruby">module Types::InstrumentInterface
  include Types::BaseInterface

  description 'A Musical Instrument'
  graphql_name 'Musical Instrument'

  field :id, ID, null: false
  field :name, String, null: false
  field :category, String, null: false

  definition_methods do
    def resolve_type(object, _context)
      case object.category
      when "string" then Types::StringInstrument
      when "drums" then Types::DrumInstrument
      else
        raise 'Unknown instrument type'
      end
    end
  end
end
</code></pre>

<p>Then we can have our specific types implementing this interface.</p>

<pre><code class="ruby">class Types::StringInstrument &lt; Types::BaseObject
  implements Types:: InstrumentInterface

  field :number_of_strings, Integer, null: false
end
</code></pre>

<p>For types that don’t have any extra field, they can just reuse everything from interface.</p>

<pre><code class="ruby">class Types::DrumInstrument &lt; Types::BaseObject
  implements Types:: InstrumentInterface
end
</code></pre>

<p>This way the query for getting instruments can look like</p>

<pre><code class="ruby">query {
  instruments {
    id
    name
    category
    ... on StringInstrument {
       numberOfStrings
    }
  }
}
</code></pre>

<p>Sample response can look like</p>

<pre><code class="json">{
  "data": [
    {
      "id": 1,
      "name": "Guitar",
      "category": "StringInstrument",
      "numberOfStrings": 6
    },
    {
      "id": 2,
      "name": "Drums",
      "category": "StringInstrument"
    }
  ]
}
</code></pre>

<p>One issue we found after doing the above was, since this way we don’t reference <code>StringInstrument</code> and <code>DrumInstrument</code>
types anywhere in our schema, they actually don’t end up showing in the generated schema. For them to show up we
have to add them as <code>orphan_types</code> in the interface. So the interface definition will look like:</p>

<pre><code class="ruby">module Types::InstrumentInterface
  include Types::BaseInterface

  description 'A Music Album'
  graphql_name 'Album'

  field :id, ID, null: false
  field :name, String, null: false
  field :category, String, null: false

  ## Changes
  orphan_types Types::StringInstrument, Types::DrumInstrument

  definition_methods do
    def resolve_type(object, _context)
      case object.category
      when "string" then Types::StringInstrument
      when "drums" then Types::DrumInstrument
      else
        raise 'Unknown instrument type'
      end
    end
  end
end
</code></pre>

<a name="Conclusion"></a>
<h2>Conclusion</h2>

<p>The biggest learning experience for us was realizing that with GraphQL we have the option to decouple our database
modeling with how the data is exposed to consumers. This way when designing our persistence layer, we can focus on
the needs of that layer and then separately think about what's the best way to expose the data to the outside world.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
