<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: people | Artsy Engineering]]></title>
  <link href="http://artsy.github.io/blog/categories/people/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://artsy.github.io/"/>
  <updated>2018-12-16T10:16:31+00:00</updated>
  <id>http://artsy.github.io/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[My First Week On Call]]></title>
    <link href="http://artsy.github.io/blog/2018/05/30/my-first-week-on-call/"/>
    <updated>2018-05-30T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <id>http://artsy.github.io/blog/2018/05/30/my-first-week-on-call</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>As I write this, I have completed my first ever engineering on-call rotation at Artsy, so naturally I had to write a blog post about some of the things I learned.</p>

<!-- more -->


<p>A year ago, I would have been terrified to be one of two engineers responsible for handling everything from re-sending automated emails to fixing total site outages, but <a href="https://ashfurrow.com/blog/perspective-of-the-polyglot/">I have grown a lot</a> so being on-call was only <em>regular</em>-level intimidating. And indeed, with supportive documentation and a good partner, I didn't experience any situations where I felt truly lost about what to do next.</p>

<p>But I did learn a few things. So let's discuss a few things that weren't immediately obvious to me.</p>

<a name="Ignore.My.Instinct.to.Fix.Things.Right.Away"></a>
<h2>Ignore My Instinct to Fix Things Right Away</h2>

<p>This sounds really counterintuitive, right? I mean, a server is down, let's reboot it so it's up again! It's got a little red X next to it in AWS, let's make it a green checkmark again! I want that checkmark!</p>

<p>But that's not always the best course of action. Sometimes, fixing something right away would deprive us of the opportunity to figure out <em>why</em> it broke in the first place. For example: we had Rails servers running out of disk space, and rebooting those servers would have refreshed their drives and fixed the problem, but one of our platform engineers asked me to wait so they could ssh in and examine the contents of the filesystems. In the mean time, the load balancer had already routed traffic around the servers, so there was no need to rush to fix anything.</p>

<p>My instinct to fix things right away was at odds with the team's desire to understand why something broke.</p>

<a name="What.is.an.Incident..Even."></a>
<h2>What is an Incident, Even?</h2>

<p>One thing became really clear to be, really quickly: people have many different, valid perspectives on what an "incident" is. Our support documentation goes into detail about what our responsibilities as on-call engineers are responsible for, and what should be routed through product teams to be prioritized, but my support partner and I still hit cases where we weren't quite sure if we should take action.</p>

<p>Sometimes, issues of critical importance were brought to our #incidents Slack channel, but weren't <em>really</em> incidents, from an Engineering perspective. We erred on the side of helping our colleagues, but it's difficult. I want to help people! But I also have responsibilities. Balancing the two is a skill every engineer has to develop, and being on-call highlighted the importance of balance in a new way for me.</p>

<p>My first ever jobs were retail, where I helped rural Canadians learn to use their first ever cell phones, and IT helpdesks; both taught me how to handle support requests in a way that makes the other person feel like things are going to be okay. I had to reapply those skills when on-call because sometimes what people were bringing to my attention fell outside the scope of an "incident". Consider the response:</p>

<blockquote><p>What you've reported isn't an incident, talk to your PM.</p></blockquote>

<p>... and contrast it with:</p>

<blockquote><p>This falls outside the scope of immediate support, so I've opened a ticket for you. You can talk to the team PM about prioritization.</p></blockquote>

<p>This kind of reply also aligns with Artsy's <a href="https://github.com/artsy/meta/blob/master/meta/what_is_artsy.md#artsy-values">values</a> of <strong>Positive Energy</strong> and <strong>People are Paramount</strong>. Everyone working at Artsy is here to make art a bigger part of culture, and that shared understanding helped.</p>

<a name="We.Need.to.Improve.our.Automated.Alerts"></a>
<h2>We Need to Improve our Automated Alerts</h2>

<p>For a few months now, Artsy Engineering has been discussing how to consolidate our automated alerts. I somehow got it in my head that anything in our #alerts channel needed immediate engineer attention, when in fact, our #alerts channel is often noisy. By the final day of my rotation, I learned that not everything needed immediate attention.</p>

<p>That's a bit of a problem. There are alerts that need immediate intervention ("the API servers are all down") and there are alerts that need no intervention ("this server is responding slowly, oh wait, it's back to normal, never mind"), and then there are the tricky ones: the ones that need <em>eventual</em> intervention ("gosh, our image processing API out of disk space for the third time in a month, we need to look into that"). Figuring out how to sort mid-level, important-but-not-urgent automated alerts from critical ones will be a critical part of our long-term support process.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Fully Automated Standups]]></title>
    <link href="http://artsy.github.io/blog/2018/05/07/fully-automated-standups/"/>
    <updated>2018-05-07T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <id>http://artsy.github.io/blog/2018/05/07/fully-automated-standups</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>When I began working at Artsy four years ago, remotely, I really didn't like the weekly engineering standup. I'd sit in front of my computer and strain to hear a dozen people gathered around a laptop with Google Hangout. They'd discuss implementation details for projects I wasn't familiar with, and then I'd do the same to them (our mobile team was still very separate from our web team). Twenty minutes would pass and I didn't feel like my work experience at Artsy had been enriched in any way.</p>

<p>The first time I came to New York to visit the office – before moving here – I sat down with <a href="https://github.com/dylanfareed">Dylan</a> and <a href="https://github.com/orta">Orta</a>. Dylan ran the weekly standup, and Orta was also not a fan of the meeting. Dylan was clear: if the standup wasn't working for the two of us, then it wasn't working for anyone. So let's fix it together.</p>

<!-- more -->


<p>And we did. We installed new sound-baffling ceiling tiles to help remote workers hear the boardroom more clearly. We restructured updates, moving from individual updates to team updates. We introduced a section for people to ask and offer help. All kinds of changes. I started looking forward to standup.</p>

<p>At Artsy, when you see something that could be improved about the way that we work, you are expected to help improve it. Dylan taught me that lesson, and I still take it to heart.</p>

<p>Last summer, I started taking on more responsibilities for the Artsy Engineering team, including running the weekly standup meeting. It was previously run by a single engineer, <a href="https://github.com/craigspaeth">Craig</a>, who was juggling a lot of team-wide responsibilities. I was happy to help him out and run the meeting, but I had only replaced <em>myself</em> as a single-point-of-failure for standup; even with Orta running things sometimes, the process itself was still as brittle as when Craig was running things alone. After a few months, Orta and I decided to fix things.</p>

<p>Our goal: fully automated standups. No single person should ever be a point-of-failure for our team. We moved through a few distinct steps.</p>

<p>First, we had to document the process of running the standup. This was crucial: standups should be run as a function of the documentation, so that any engineer at Artsy can run an effective standup. The docs should not only help the engineer run the meeting, but help them feel <em>capable</em> of running the meeting. And once documentation is in place, anyone can help improve the docs (and consequently, improve the process). The current <a href="https://github.com/artsy/meta/blob/master/meta/open_standup.md">docs are open source</a>.</p>

<p>Next, we had to get other engineers running the meeting. We split up the responsibilities of the meeting into two roles: a talking part, and a note-taking part. Both are integral, and different people gravitate towards differently roles. Splitting things up not only made running the meeting easier, but it made running the meeting more appealing to newcomers.</p>

<p>Once the meeting was a two-person responsibility, we started bringing on other engineers to help. I would ask around to see who was interested in helping running a meeting, giving choice of role to the other person. After each meeting, I'd ask the person about how we could improve the docs. Each week, the docs got better and better.</p>

<p>The next phase was moving to having standup run entirely by other engineers. I had a list of engineers who had never run a standup, and worked down the list to get as many engineers having run a meeting as possible. I made <a href="https://github.com/artsy/meta/pull/21">this pull request</a> making it clear that running the standup meeting is a responsibility that every member of the team <em>shares</em>.</p>

<p>Eventually, I felt we were ready to move to a self-perpetuating standup. At the end of each standup, we would solicit volunteers to run next week's meeting. Fully-automated standups! We'd done it! Things were working, though we did recently decide to <a href="https://github.com/artsy/meta/pull/32">integrate the standup schedule into our new support on-call schedule</a>; the engineers beginning their rotation were responsible for running the standup. This eliminated the kind of awkward "okay who wants to do this next week?" part of our meeting.</p>

<p>At each step, we improved the process. Through effective documentation and positive energy, we reduced the <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Bus_factor">bus factor</a> for our engineering team's management. And more importantly, I think, we made it clear to every Artsy engineer that managing our team and improving how we work is a responsibility we have, together.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[What it Feels Like to Work in a Supportive Environment for Female Engineers]]></title>
    <link href="http://artsy.github.io/blog/2017/09/29/supportive-environment-for-female-engineers/"/>
    <updated>2017-09-29T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <id>http://artsy.github.io/blog/2017/09/29/supportive-environment-for-female-engineers</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>With the often overwhelming and downright discouraging reality that the tech industry isn’t a diverse and inclusive environment, I felt compelled to share what a productive, empathetic, and nurturing environment for female and female-identifying engineers looks like.</p>

<p>I have just shipped a post over on the Life at Artsy blog about how: Our culture of empathy, our hiring process and our company values provide a competitive advantage. This all contributes to ensuring that all engineers regardless of gender feel valued.</p>

<p><a href="https://medium.com/artsy-blog/what-it-feels-like-to-work-in-a-supportive-environment-for-female-engineers-3c994a001007">Read on at the Life at Artsy Blog →</a></p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[DevSwap: An Experiment in Randomizing Teams]]></title>
    <link href="http://artsy.github.io/blog/2017/09/11/DevSwap/"/>
    <updated>2017-09-11T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <id>http://artsy.github.io/blog/2017/09/11/DevSwap</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>A few weeks ago, every engineer at Artsy went to work for a different team for two full days. We called it DevSwap. In this post, I'll go over why and how we did it.</p>

<!-- more -->


<p>If you’ve read about Artsy's <a href="http://artsy.github.io/blog/2016/03/28/artsy-engineering-organization-stack/">Engineering Team</a> before, you might know that we organize ourselves into product teams that serve different parts of our business. Today, Artsy employs 26 engineers, spread across four product teams — Publishing, Auctions, Collector GMV, and Partner Success. We also have a Platform team that is responsible for systems, infrastructure, and data, among other things. Across these teams, we share systems and apps. To stay cohesive with one another, we also have what we call “practices,” which are cross-team groups that meet and discuss shared tech.</p>

<p>Around two years ago, we didn't have product teams. Back then, most engineers worked in a variety of stacks. As our business models changed, so did the way we organized ourselves. Interestingly, the number of engineers has not changed drastically, but the way we work has. We have greater focus now that we are organized into product teams with specific business goals, but that means there aren't as many opportunities to work in other stacks.</p>

<p>Earlier this summer, the engineering leads received some feedback from our engineers about wanting more cross-team collaboration and knowledge sharing. In our weekly engineering-wide meeting, we get to hear what features each team is working on, but it can sometimes feel like there's missing context. Within our practices, there is a better sense of the details, but usually the work itself is deeply nested in another team.</p>

<p>We brainstormed several ideas related to knowledge sharing and cross-team collaboration. What stood out the most was that being in product teams meant fewer opportunities to work in other parts of the business. This led to the question: What would happen if we redistributed ourselves into entirely new teams?</p>

<a name="Setup"></a>
<h2>Setup</h2>

<p>Over the course of a few weeks, the engineer leads devised a plan for DevSwap. Here are some questions we asked ourselves:</p>

<ul>
<li>How can we become closer as a team while learning something new?</li>
<li>How can we keep ourselves as engineers nimble, flexible, and full-stack?</li>
<li>How can we reduce risk in our systems by spreading knowledge?</li>
<li>How can we have fun before summer is over?</li>
</ul>


<p>For the first iteration, we decided to spend two full business days swapping. Every engineer  worked with a different team. Each team contained the same number of people as the original team. The leads of each team stayed to onboard, provide support and facilitate work.</p>

<p>The Monday before DevSwap, we had an engineering-wide meeting to go over some guidelines and pick teams. Here are the guidelines we shared:</p>

<ul>
<li>DevSwap will last 2 days. 🕑</li>
<li>Product managers have been notified so don't worry about your regular work. Hopefully a new member will pick some up for you 😄.</li>
<li>If possible, try and sit by your new team and if not, coordinate meeting times with remote members. 📞</li>
<li>See this as a pairing opportunity! 👫</li>
<li>In terms of work, it's business as usual. Your new lead will give you guidance. 💼</li>
</ul>


<p>In this meeting, we also had our leads "pitch" their teams. The goal of this was to get people excited about joining new teams and to get a sense of what projects they might work on. To choose the actual teams, each engineer picked their top three choices and we drew names out of a bucket. If their first choice was already full, we would place them in their next available choice. The following Monday and Tuesday, we were all writing code for different teams.</p>

<a name="So.what.happened."></a>
<h2>So what happened?</h2>

<p>Our EU engineers kicked off DevSwap on Monday, tackling both the struggle of learning new stacks and being remote (our headquarters is located in NYC). Leads mitigated the latter problem by prepping EU folks on Friday so they had some direction come Monday morning.</p>

<p>There was lots of Slack-ing, Screenhero-ing, and pairing. It was wonderful to see people interact in a new environment with new goals, even if it was temporary. Some got to learn about <em>how</em> teams operate and learned about issue prioritization and even attended meetings with stakeholders.</p>

<p>Some people worked on modernizing codebases with projects like <a href="https://github.com/artsy/positron/pull/1225">server-side hot file swapping</a> and the introduction of a GraphQL endpoint to our consignments app. Others worked on building features like <a href="https://github.com/artsy/aprb/pull/104/files">setting up Slack notifications</a> when we receive customer feedback and adding ElasticSearch indexing to projects. We learned new languages <a href="https://github.com/artsy/eigen/pull/2412">by building features</a> and updated <a href="https://github.com/artsy/metaphysics/pull/702">many</a> <a href="https://github.com/artsy/positron/pull/1235">docs</a>.</p>

<p>All work aside, the fact that we were having conversations with each other about the details of the technology while gaining a fresh perspective of someone else's experience was valuable.</p>

<a name="Feedback.from.Engineers"></a>
<h2>Feedback from Engineers</h2>

<p>I learned a lot and had fun, but I wondered what everyone else thought. At the end of the second day, I sent out a survey to all 26 engineers and received 14 responses. Here are some of those results:</p>

<p>Did you get a chance to collaborate with someone you don't normally work with?</p>

<iframe width="600" height="371" seamless frameborder="0" scrolling="no" src="https://docs.google.com/spreadsheets/d/e/2PACX-1vQoAQpvGiq2-5EJWz__vS0n4Iw9r3rY_eSEaPqKQzUlPnObnono-RFS4qLSjrmGTqGnbMOoQsA1L9WX/pubchart?oid=942845256&amp;format=interactive"></iframe>


<p><br>
Did you gain a better understanding of a piece of Artsy Engineering you don't normally interact with?</p>

<iframe width="600" height="371" seamless frameborder="0" scrolling="no" src="https://docs.google.com/spreadsheets/d/e/2PACX-1vQoAQpvGiq2-5EJWz__vS0n4Iw9r3rY_eSEaPqKQzUlPnObnono-RFS4qLSjrmGTqGnbMOoQsA1L9WX/pubchart?oid=543941925&amp;format=interactive"></iframe>


<p><br>
If we were to swap again in 6 months, how long should it last?</p>

<iframe width="600" height="371" seamless frameborder="0" scrolling="no" src="https://docs.google.com/spreadsheets/d/e/2PACX-1vQoAQpvGiq2-5EJWz__vS0n4Iw9r3rY_eSEaPqKQzUlPnObnono-RFS4qLSjrmGTqGnbMOoQsA1L9WX/pubchart?oid=1071239654&amp;format=interactive"></iframe>


<p><br>
<br></p>

<blockquote><p>"Would make the swap slightly longer -- was a short timeframe to get through a project."</p>

<p>"Onboarding took up most of the time. It was hard to get anything beyond that done."</p></blockquote>

<p>One clear piece of feedback was the desire to spend more time on an assigned team. Some engineers had trouble onboarding, setting up projects, and accomplishing meaningful work within the two days. If engineers can't spin up a dev environment within a day, what does that mean for usability? These are solvable problems — we could think about dockerizing apps or having better READMEs. During the session, some folks went back to their old teams to help new members with problems. While this was great, it meant less time for their own learning. One option is to extend the duration of the swap. But by extending it too long, it could remove the hackathon mentality that kept people highly focused. It seems like a combination of tweaking the duration, providing better initial setup, and clearly communicating expectations might help for next time.</p>

<p>We also requested feedback on the leads. Responding to a multiple choice question about what their newly assigned lead did best, most engineers chose "Assisted me when I got stuck" and "Checked in with me frequently." The least chosen answers were "Taught me something new" and "Made the work enjoyable." It's possible that taking more time to prepare for new teams (i.e. introduction meetings, dev environment setup workshop) could provide more opportunities for deeper learning.</p>

<p>When we asked if there were any good takeaways that could be applied to your own team, we had some interesting answers.</p>

<blockquote><p>"Partner Success does a 'show &amp; tell' where you just casually mention something you learned, dev/tech related. That was fun. We should do that on [Collector Experience]."</p>

<p>"Finally got to play with Redux in a production app, which I'd be very happy to see implemented in <a href="https://github.com/artsy/positron">Positron</a>."</p>

<p>"I've been thinking a lot about GraphQL and what it could mean to the [Partner Success] team. Also thinking about what it means for Kinetic and how our projects talk to Gravity."</p></blockquote>

<p>Finally, what did people like most?</p>

<blockquote><p>"Working with people that I normally don't get a chance to work with on daily basis and also working on the areas of our systems. The fact that now each engineer knows how to setup and run another part of our system by itself is a huge win."</p>

<p>"The tight time period forces projects to be very granular. It also forces repo set-up time to be minimized (e.g., via setup/bootstrap scripts, docker, etc.)."</p>

<p>"I liked feeling like I was able to figure out a codebase that was completely new to me and add value even in the short time that we had to work with. It made me feel like something intimidating was actually within my reach and that made me feel smart. :)"</p>

<p>"I wasn't sure if we should expect to get much accomplished but was pleasantly surprised to ship a small but useful feature."</p>

<p>"Awesome idea, it feels great to be part of the team that takes risks like this to increase teamwork and knowledge share among engineers and give engineers chance to get out of their comfort zone."</p></blockquote>

<p>Despite a few issues with onboarding and timing, it seems that most people found DevSwap to be valuable. This feedback gives us a lot to consider when planning the next one. We hope to bring it back soon!</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Artsy's Engineering Organization Stack, 2016]]></title>
    <link href="http://artsy.github.io/blog/2016/03/28/artsy-engineering-organization-stack/"/>
    <updated>2016-03-28T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <id>http://artsy.github.io/blog/2016/03/28/artsy-engineering-organization-stack</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<div style="max-width: 50%; text-align: center; float: right; padding: 0 0 10px 10px; line-height: 1;"><img src="/images/2016-03-28-artsy-engineering-organization-stack/stack.jpg"><br><font size="2px"><em>The Artsy Engineering Organization "Stack" in 2012<br>from <a target="_blank" href="http://code.dblock.org/2011/07/12/sitting-is-killing-you-move-to-new-york.html">"Sitting is Killing You? Move to New York"</a></em></font></div>


<p>Artsy has now grown past 140 team members and our Engineering organization is a nimble 25. We've recently performed a large organizational change (I highly recommend reading <a href="https://www.artsy.net/article/robert-lenne-the-secret-s-to-company-re-orgs">"The Secret(s) to Company Re-Orgs"</a>), so this is a good time to describe our updated Engineering organization, starting from the top - Artsy as a company and business.</p>

<!-- more -->


<a name="The.Company"></a>
<h2>The Company</h2>

<p>Artsy’s mission is to make all the world’s art accessible to anyone with an Internet connection. We are a resource for art collecting and education. Artsy features the world’s leading galleries, museum collections, foundations, artist estates, art fairs, and benefit auctions, all in one place. Our growing database of 350,000 images of art, architecture, and design by 50,000 artists spans historical, modern, and contemporary works, and includes the largest online database of contemporary art. Artsy is used by art lovers, museum-goers, patrons, collectors, students, and educators to discover, learn about, and collect art.</p>

<a name="The.Artsy.Businesses"></a>
<h2>The Artsy Businesses</h2>

<p>Artsy has 3 businesses: <em>Listings</em>, <em>Marketplace</em> and <em>Content</em>.</p>

<p><strong>Listings</strong>: Artsy <a href="https://www.artsy.net/galleries">gallery partners</a> pay a flat monthly subscription fee to list an unlimited number of artworks for sale, plus a host of other benefits. They do not pay a commission fee on sales made through Artsy.</p>

<p><strong>Marketplace</strong>: In 2015 Artsy expanded into hosting commercial auctions on our platform. Much like our Listings business, we work with top auction houses. The latter pay commissions from sales. Check out <a href="https://www.artsy.net/auctions">current auctions on Artsy</a>.</p>

<p><strong>Content</strong>: We are also working on making Artsy a go-to platform for brands to co-create and distribute content that engages a global arts and culture audience. In 2015 we debuted our first sponsored content feature on Artsy, a <a href="https://www.artsy.net/venice-biennale-2015">series of 11 educational short films about the Venice Biennale in partnership with UBS</a> (if anything, <a href="https://www.artsy.net/article/artsy-editorial-behind-the-venice-biennale-2015-a-short-history-of-the-world-s-most-important-art-exhibition">watch this amazing video</a>).</p>

<a name="A.Product.Engineering.Organization"></a>
<h2>A Product Engineering Organization</h2>

<p>We think of <em>Engineering</em> as a service of the <em>Product</em> organization. Products serve customers and product teams serve businesses. Each product team may contribute to one or several businesses. To make our goals crystal clear, we developed Key Performance Indicators (KPIs) for each business. For example, <em>churn</em> is a KPI for the Listings business - a low churn shows how well we're serving our existing subscribers. Furthermore, we designed each product team to own all necessary resources to accomplish their goals. In some ways, our product teams operate like small start-ups.</p>

<p>Each product team consists of one or more <em>Business People</em>, a <em>Product Owner</em> (often a <em>Product Manager</em>), a <em>Designer</em>, an <em>Engineering Lead</em> and several <em>Engineers</em>.</p>

<p>Our product teams map directly into our businesses and inherit the same KPIs.</p>

<p><strong>Partner Success</strong>: The Partner Success team focuses on products that serve the Listings business. These include our Content Management system and <a href="http://folio.artsy.net">Artsy Folio</a>, an iPad app used by our partners.</p>

<p><strong>Auctions</strong>: The Auctions product team builds all auction systems across web and mobile.</p>

<p><strong>Collector GMV</strong>: GMV stands for <em>Gross Merchandising Volume</em>, a measure of artworks traded on the platform. We have two collector product teams, web and mobile, focused on various customer experiences across all our web and mobile properties.</p>

<p><strong>Publishing</strong>: The publishing team works on the platform used to produce and distribute all our online editorial content.</p>

<a name="Practices"></a>
<h2>Practices</h2>

<p>While there're many advantages of product teams operating independently, it's also very easy to create vertical inefficiencies. Multiple teams could choose to achieve similar outcomes in many different ways, creating a lot of redundant work and making it impossible for team members to move between organizations.</p>

<p>To address this problem we've created a separate <em>Platform Engineering Team</em> and <em>Practices</em>.</p>

<p>The Platform Engineering Team is responsible for systems and shared infrastructure that help product teams work smarter, scale our operations, and much more. Our <em>Design</em> team is similar in nature to Platform Engineering, creating a consistent visual language and user experience across all products.</p>

<p>Our <em>Practices</em>, specifically <em>Web</em> and <em>Mobile</em>, are run by a handful of experienced Engineers working independently and floating between product teams to build features, while evangelizing best practices of making software or our <a href="http://artsy.github.io/open-source">commitment to open-source</a> at the same time. Engineers on product teams may also belong to a practice - mobile engineers on the Auctions team are members of the Mobile practice, but don't report to the Director of Mobile.</p>

<a name="Reporting.Structure"></a>
<h2>Reporting Structure</h2>

<p>We believe that in order to help our team members grow professionally, their manager must understand their work. Engineers report to Engineering Leads in product teams. Engineering and Engineering Practice Leads report to the Head of Engineering. Product Managers report to the Head of Product. Designers report to the Design Lead, who reports to the Head of Product. It's important to note that, while preserving top-down authority and responsibility, we try to practice bottom-up leadership - the job of team leads is to help individual contributors do their best work.</p>

<a name="Conclusion"></a>
<h2>Conclusion</h2>

<p>We have a very complex business, and we think our structure works well for a company that does many things at once. Your mileage may vary, so don't try to apply the same structure in your company just because this works for us! And always remember that evolving an organization is a disruptive process. It may yield better focus and can be transformational to a group. It may also produce the opposite effect, since moving individuals between teams is much more involved than drag-and-dropping a headcount in an organizational chart.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
