<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: jenkins | Artsy Engineering]]></title>
  <link href="http://artsy.github.io/blog/categories/jenkins/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://artsy.github.io/"/>
  <updated>2018-12-16T10:16:31+00:00</updated>
  <id>http://artsy.github.io/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[On-Demand Jenkins Slaves with Amazon EC2]]></title>
    <link href="http://artsy.github.io/blog/2012/07/10/on-demand-jenkins-slaves-with-amazon-ec2/"/>
    <updated>2012-07-10T13:30:00+00:00</updated>
    <id>http://artsy.github.io/blog/2012/07/10/on-demand-jenkins-slaves-with-amazon-ec2</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>The <a href="http://artsy.net">Artsy</a> team faithfully uses <a href="http://jenkins-ci.org">Jenkins</a> for continuous integration. <a href="http://artsy.github.com/blog/2012/05/27/using-jenkins-for-ruby-and-ruby-on-rails-teams/">As we've described before</a>, our Jenkins master and 8 slaves run on Linode. This arrangement has at least a few drawbacks:</p>

<ul>
<li>Our Linode servers are manually configured. They require frequent maintenance, and inconsistencies lead to surprising build failures.</li>
<li>The fixed set of slaves don't match the pattern of our build jobs: jobs get backed up during the day, but servers are mostly unused overnight and on weekends.</li>
</ul>


<p>The <a href="https://wiki.jenkins-ci.org/display/JENKINS/Amazon+EC2+Plugin">Amazon EC2 Plugin</a> allowed us to replace those slaves with a totally scripted environment. Now, slaves are spun up in the cloud whenever build jobs need them.</p>

<!-- more -->


<p>To set up the build slave's Amazon Machine Image (AMI), we started from an <a href="http://cloud-images.ubuntu.com/releases/oneiric/release/">official Ubuntu 11.10</a> (Oneiric Ocelot) AMI, ran initialization scripts to set up our build dependencies (MongoDB, Redis, ImageMagick, Firefox, RVM, NVM, etc.), packaged our modified instance into its own AMI, and then set up the EC2 Plugin to launch instances from this custom AMI.</p>

<p>Our AMI setup steps are captured entirely in a <a href="https://gist.github.com/3085368">GitHub gist</a>, but because our build requirements are specific to our applications and frameworks, most organizations will need to modify these scripts to their own use cases. Given that caveat, here's how we went from base Ubuntu AMI to custom build slave AMI:</p>

<ol>
<li>We <a href="https://console.aws.amazon.com/ec2/home?region=us-east-1#launchAmi=ami-4dad7424">launched</a> an Ubuntu 11.10 AMI <code>4dad7424</code> via the AWS console.</li>
<li>Once the instance was launched, we logged in with the SSH key we generated during setup.</li>
<li><p>We ran the following commands to configure the instance:</p>

<pre><code> curl -L https://raw.github.com/gist/3085368/_base-setup.sh | sudo bash -s
 sudo su -l jenkins
 curl -L https://raw.github.com/gist/3085368/_jenkins-user-setup.sh | bash -s
</code></pre></li>
<li><p>From the "Instances" tab of the AWS Console, we chose the now-configured instance, and from the "Instance Actions" dropdown, selected "Stop", followed by "Create Image (EBS AMI)".</p></li>
</ol>


<p>Next we installed the Amazon EC2 Plugin on our Jenkins master, and entered the following configuration arguments for the plugin. (Replace the AMI ID with your own, the result of Step 4 above.)</p>

<p><img src="Jenkins%20EC2%20Plugin%20configuration" alt="/images/2012-07-10-on-demand-jenkins-slaves-with-amazon-ec2/ec2-plugin-config.png" /></p>

<p>New build slaves began spawning immediately in response to job demand! Our new "Computers" page on Jenkins looks like this:</p>

<p><img src="Jenkins%20computer%20list" alt="/images/2012-07-10-on-demand-jenkins-slaves-with-amazon-ec2/computer-list.png" /></p>

<p>We have the option of provisioning a new build slave via a single click, but so far, this hasn't been necessary, since slaves have automatically scaled up and down with demand. We average around 4-8 build slaves during the day, and 0-1 overnight and on weekends.</p>

<a name="Outcome.and.Next.Steps"></a>
<h2>Outcome and Next Steps</h2>

<p>This arrangement hasn't been in place for long, but we're excited about the benefits it's already delivered:</p>

<ul>
<li>Builds now take a predictable amount of time, since slaves automatically scale up to match demand.</li>
<li>Slaves offer a more consistent and easily maintained configuration, so there are fewer spurious failures.</li>
<li>Despite higher costs on EC2, we hope to spend about the same (or maybe even less) now that we'll need to operate only the master server during periods of inactivity (like nights and weekends).</li>
</ul>


<p>As proponents of <em>automating the hard stuff</em>, we get a real kick out of watching identical slaves spin up as builds trickle in each morning, then disappear as the queue quiets down in the evening. Still, there are a few improvements to be made:</p>

<ul>
<li>Our canonical slave's configuration should be scripted with <a href="http://www.opscode.com/chef/">Chef</a>.</li>
<li>Sharp-eyed readers will notice that our Jenkins master is still a Linode server. It might benefit from the same type of scripted configuration as the slaves.</li>
<li>Cooler still would be for the EC2 plugin to take advantage of Amazon's <a href="http://aws.amazon.com/ec2/spot-instances/">spot pricing</a>. Though not supported at the moment, it would allow us to spend a fraction as much (or spend the same amount, but on more powerful resources).</li>
</ul>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Using Jenkins for Ruby and Ruby-on-Rails Teams]]></title>
    <link href="http://artsy.github.io/blog/2012/05/27/using-jenkins-for-ruby-and-ruby-on-rails-teams/"/>
    <updated>2012-05-27T08:15:00+00:00</updated>
    <id>http://artsy.github.io/blog/2012/05/27/using-jenkins-for-ruby-and-ruby-on-rails-teams</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>The <a href="http://jenkins-ci.org">Jenkins CI</a> project has grown tremendously in the past few months. There're now hundreds of plugins and an amazing engaged community. Artsy is a happy user and proud contributor to this effort with the essential <a href="https://wiki.jenkins-ci.org/display/JENKINS/AnsiColor+Plugin">jenkins-ansicolor plugin</a>, eliminating boring console output since 2011.</p>

<p>We are a continuous integration, deployment and devops shop and have been using Jenkins for over a year now. We've shared our experience at the <a href="http://www.cloudbees.com/juc2012.cb">Jenkins User Conference 2012</a> in <a href="http://www.slideshare.net/dblockdotorg/graduating-to-jenkins-ci-for-rubyonrails-teams">a presentation</a>. This blog post is an overview of how to get started with Jenkins for Ruby(-on-Rails) teams.</p>

<p><img src="Artsy%20Jenkins%20CI" alt="/images/2012-05-27-using-jenkins-for-ruby-on-rails-teams/jenkins.png" /></p>

<!-- more -->


<p>When Artsy had only three engineers, we hesitated to deploy Jenkins. The CI server was written in Java (i.e. wasn't written in Ruby). We feared introducing excessive infrastructure too early. In retrospect, we were not in the business of building CI infrastructure, so not using Jenkins was a mistake. Since we adopted it, Jenkins has been operating painlessly and scaled nicely as our needs continued to grow.</p>

<p>Today, we run a single virtual server on <a href="http://www.linode.com">Linode</a> as our master Jenkins and have 8 Linode slaves. These are all $19 per month plans. Our usage is variable: few builds in the middle of the night and a very high number of builds during the day, so we're planning on trying to build a Jenkins-slave on-demand system on AWS eventually.</p>

<p>Setting up a Jenkins master is straightforward.</p>

<pre><code class="bash">useradd -m jenkins -p [password] -s /bin/bash
addgroup jenkins sudo
wget -q -O - http://pkg.jenkins-ci.org/debian/jenkins-ci.org.key | sudo apt-key add –
sudo sh -c 'echo deb http://pkg.jenkins-ci.org/debian binary/ &gt; /etc/apt/sources.list.d/jenkins.list'
sudo aptitude update
sudo aptitude install jenkins
</code></pre>

<p>We change Jenkins port in <code>/etc/default/jenkins</code>, add the machine to DNS and update the Jenkins URL to an externally visible one in the "Manage Jenkins", "Configure System" menu. We enable and use "Matrix-Based Security" with a single user that all developers share and give the user permission to do everything in the same UI. Finally, we configure the Git Plugin with a global username and e-mail from our shared IT account that has Github access, setup a Github Web Hook and SMTP E-Mail notifications. Restarting Jenkins from the command line with <code>sudo service jenkins restart</code> completes the initial setup.</p>

<p>It's also a good idea to setup Jenkins configuration backup with <a href="https://wiki.jenkins-ci.org/display/JENKINS/thinBackup">thinBackup</a>, install <a href="http://wiki.jenkins-ci.org/display/JENKINS/AnsiColor+Plugin">AnsiColor</a> and, of course, enable <a href="http://wiki.hudson-ci.org/display/HUDSON/ChuckNorris+Plugin">Chuck Norris</a>.</p>

<p>A typical Ruby development environment includes <a href="https://rvm.io/">RVM</a>, a working GIT client and a Github SSH key. We install these under our <code>jenkins</code> user manually on the first slave Linode and then clone slaves when we need more. RVM setup includes entries in <code>~/.bash_profile</code>, so a Jenkins job for a Ruby project can load that file and execute commands, including <code>rake</code>.</p>

<pre><code class="bash">#!/bin/bash
source ~/.bash_profile
rvm use 1.9.2
gem install bundler
bundle install
bundle exec rake
</code></pre>

<p>Our default Ruby project Rake task is <code>test:ci</code>. We run Jasmine and Capybara tests using a real browser, so we need to redirect all visible output to an X-Windows Virtual Frame Buffer (<a href="http://www.xfree86.org/4.0.1/Xvfb.1.html">XVFB</a>). This can be done by setting an <code>ENV</code> variable inside a Rake task. Our test target also <a href="http://artsy.github.com/blog/2012/05/15/how-to-organize-over-3000-rspec-specs-and-retry-test-failures/">organizes our tests in suites</a>.</p>

<pre><code class="ruby">namespace :test do
  task :specs, [ :display ] =&gt; :environment do |t, args|
   ENV['DISPLAY'] = args[:display] if args[:display]
   Rake::Task['spec:suite:all'].invoke
  end
      
  task :jasmine, [ :display ] =&gt; :environment do |t, args|
    ENV['DISPLAY'] = args[:display] if args[:display]
    system!("bundle exec rake jasmine:ci")
  end
    
  task :all, [ :display ] =&gt; :environment do |t, args|
    Rake::Task['assets'].invoke
    Rake::Task['test:jasmine'].invoke(args[:display])
    Rake::Task['test:specs'].invoke(args[:display])
  end
      
  task :ci do
    Rake::Task['test:all'].invoke(":99")
  end
      
end
</code></pre>

<p>A successful CI test run will trigger a deployment to a staging environment on Heroku.</p>

<pre><code class="ruby">namespace :deploy do
  task :staging =&gt; :environment do
    system!("bundle exec heroku maintenance:on --app=app-staging")
    system!("git push git@heroku.com:app-staging.git origin/staging:master")
    system!("bundle exec heroku maintenance:off --app=app-staging")
  end
end
</code></pre>

<p>You'll notice that we execute system commands with <code>system!</code>. Unlike the usual <code>system</code> method, our wrapper raises an exception when a command returns a non-zero error code to abort execution.</p>

<pre><code class="ruby">def system!(cmdline)
  logger.info("[#{Time.now}] #{cmdline}")
  rc = system(cmdline)
  "failed with exit code #{$?.exitstatus}" if (rc.nil? || ! rc || $?.exitstatus != 0)
end
</code></pre>

<p>Our production deployment task is also a Jenkins job.</p>

<pre><code class="ruby">namespace :deploy do
  task :production =&gt; :environment do
    system!("git push git@heroku.com:app-production.git origin/production:master")
  end
end
</code></pre>

<p>We don't want any downtime on our production environment, so we don't turn Heroku maintance on. Our staging deployment task also includes copying production data to staging, so we chose to enable maintenance to avoid people hitting the test environment while it's being built and may be in a half-baked state.</p>

<p>Finally, we also run production daily cron-like tasks via Jenkins. It gives us email notifications, console output and the ability to manually trigger them. Centralizing operations in the same environment as CI creates truly continuous integration, deployment and operations.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
