<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: automation | Artsy Engineering]]></title>
  <link href="http://artsy.github.io/blog/categories/automation/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://artsy.github.io/"/>
  <updated>2018-12-16T10:16:31+00:00</updated>
  <id>http://artsy.github.io/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Being a Better Programmer When You're Actually Lazy.]]></title>
    <link href="http://artsy.github.io/blog/2016/03/02/Lazily-Automation/"/>
    <updated>2016-03-02T12:09:00+00:00</updated>
    <id>http://artsy.github.io/blog/2016/03/02/Lazily-Automation</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I juggle a bunch of projects, both in Artsy and in the Open Source community. If you don't work with me directly, you'd be mistaken for believing that I was an organized person. I'm pretty far from that, and <a href="https://github.com/artsy/mobile/issues/68">don't really</a> plan on changing that.</p>

<p>However, I work with other people and very strongly believe that programming is mostly a social problem once you're good enough at writing code. It'd be hypocritical of me to not improve the people process side, so I try to automate processes that makes me a better team-mate.</p>

<p>I'm going to cover four things I've worked on lately to improve this: <a href="https://github.com/danger/danger/">Danger</a>, <a href="https://github.com/orta/github-clippers">GitHub-Clippers</a> and improving how I write commits and prefixing my name on branches.</p>

<!-- more -->


<a name="Danger"></a>
<h3>Danger</h3>

<p><a href="https://github.com/danger/danger/">Danger</a> is a tool I co-created with a friend (<a href="https://github.com/krausefx/">Felix Krause</a>), and it's namesake, <a href="https://github.com/dangermcshane">Gem "Danger" McShane</a>. It came out of frustration that we couldn't easily hold ourselves accountable to better team processes. Requiring a code-reviewer to  also remember details like "Add a CHANGELOG Entry" isn't much to ask, but it is "Yet Another Thing To Remember" for both the submitter and reviewer.</p>

<p>It's turning into a really important part of our code-review, and the ideas it generates once we had it in place make it fun to add new rules. It means we can fail fast, and not have to think about process so much. Danger will tell us if we've missed something.</p>

<p><img src="/images/2016-03-02-Lazily-Automation/danger.png" alt="Danger Example" /></p>

<p>I expect to write a more serious post on <a href="https://github.com/danger/danger/">Danger</a> once it's more fleshed out. For now though, the README covers what it does well.</p>

<a name="Clippers"></a>
<h3>Clippers</h3>

<p>In every big team I operate in, other people care about keeping the repo clean of merged branches. I totally respect their opinion, but it's so low on things I care about that I just don't register the "Delete Branch" button on a GitHub pull request. I'd rather be finding a <a href="https://github.com/orta/gifs">good response GIF</a>.</p>

<p>So I created <a href="https://github.com/orta/github-clippers">a Safari Extension</a> that handles automatically deleting branches on specific repos for me. It's not a biggie, it's not fancy, it's under a <a href="https://github.com/orta/github-clippers/blob/master/GitHub-Clippers.safariextension/github_clippers.js">hundred lines of code</a> - but it automates something that annoyed others about my behavior. That counts for something.</p>

<a name="Commit.Automation"></a>
<h3>Commit Automation</h3>

<p>I write <em>reasonable</em> commit messages, they're not <a href="http://tbaggery.com/2008/04/19/a-note-about-git-commit-messages.html">amazing</a>, they're <a href="http://www.whatthecommit.com">not terrible</a>. They're just, <a href="https://github.com/artsy/energy/commits/master?author=orta">alright</a>. I wanted to start trying to hold everyone accountable for doing better, so I advocated for copying the person with the <a href="https://github.com/artsy/eigen/commits/master?author=alloy">best commit style</a> on our team.</p>

<p>Their style is to have commits in a format like <code>[Context] Thing I did.</code> - it is much better that <code>Thing I did.</code>. So I looked into how I could automate this, because I would very quickly forget to do this. Here's what I did:</p>

<pre><code class="sh">
// Helper function to get the branch info
function git_branch_info() {
  ref=$(command git symbolic-ref HEAD 2&gt; /dev/null) || \
  ref=$(command git rev-parse --short HEAD 2&gt; /dev/null) || return
  echo "${ref#refs/heads/}"
}

function branch() {
  git checkout master;
  git pull upstream master;
  git checkout -b $1
  git config branch.$1.description $2
}

function commit() {
  local BRANCH=$(git_branch_info)
  local INFO=$(git config branch.$(echo $BRANCH).description)
  git commit -m "[$(echo $INFO)] $argv"
}

// And if I forget to set my context
function context() {
  local BRANCH=$(git_branch_info)
  git config branch.$(echo $BRANCH).description $1
}
</code></pre>

<p>Or if you're a fish user like me, <a href="https://gist.github.com/orta/902d8e576a2b75afe2df">this gist</a>.</p>

<p>I created two shell functions, one that makes a branch that includes a context type. So for example, say I'm working on artwork notifications, I'd start a new branch with <code>$ branch artwork_notifications Notifications</code>. This saves the context as <code>Notifications</code> on the git branch metadata. Then everytime I want to commit my changes, I use <code>$ commit This is the thing I changed.</code> - and it will be prefixed with <code>[Notifications]</code>. It makes it easier for someone looking through the history to have an idea about the context, and makes me feel like I'm improving my process without remembering the context.</p>

<a name="Branch.Prefixes"></a>
<h3>Branch Prefixes</h3>

<p>We use a Makefile in all our projects to try and help automate per-project simple tasks like running <a href="https://github.com/artsy/energy/blob/e5db035225490fb53c65c74a6c1bdd660f305ab6/Makefile#L44">mogenerator</a>, updating <a href="https://github.com/artsy/energy/blob/e5db035225490fb53c65c74a6c1bdd660f305ab6/Makefile#L49">storyboard identifiers</a> and updating <a href="https://github.com/artsy/eigen/blob/12fe9de4d927eea27f4942d15e74b89016a6345f/Makefile#L102-L103">embedded resources</a>.</p>

<p>I also applied some standard make commands in our projects so that I can prefix my <a href="https://github.com/artsy/eigen/blob/10106210196f096a27412a70af61dcae7fda285c/Makefile#L110-L117">branches with my name</a>.</p>

<pre><code class="sh">LOCAL_BRANCH = $(shell git rev-parse --abbrev-ref HEAD)
BRANCH = $(shell echo host=github.com | git credential fill | sed -E 'N; s/.*username=(.+)\n?.*/\1/')-$(shell git rev-parse --abbrev-ref HEAD)

pr:
    if [ "$(LOCAL_BRANCH)" == "master" ]; then echo "In master, not PRing"; else git push upstream "$(LOCAL_BRANCH):$(BRANCH)"; open "https://github.com/artsy/eigen/pull/new/artsy:master...$(BRANCH)"; fi

push:
    if [ "$(LOCAL_BRANCH)" == "master" ]; then echo "In master, not pushing"; else git push upstream $(LOCAL_BRANCH):$(BRANCH); fi

fpush:
    if [ "$(LOCAL_BRANCH)" == "master" ]; then echo "In master, not pushing"; else git push upstream $(LOCAL_BRANCH):$(BRANCH) --force; fi
</code></pre>

<p>This works by some funky shell work to pull out your current branch into <code>LOCAL_BRANCH</code>, then to do the same thing but prefixed with your login name for <code>BRANCH</code>. Then the make commands handle pushing to the server. This means that everyone in the team can provide have logically named branches without having to have their local repo filled with <code>[my_name]-thing</code> branches.</p>

<a name="On-going"></a>
<h2>On-going</h2>

<p>This is a work in progress, as the mobile team grows, we need to add more process when it's appropriate. This <em>doesn't</em> mean that we have to sacrifice speed, and we can continue thinking about the problem at hand rather than devoting energy to process.</p>

<p>It's a time trade-off that has worked out well for me so far, and I'd love to know other people's hacks for having useful process, but automating it so that it's not considered overhead.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Using Jenkins for Ruby and Ruby-on-Rails Teams]]></title>
    <link href="http://artsy.github.io/blog/2012/05/27/using-jenkins-for-ruby-and-ruby-on-rails-teams/"/>
    <updated>2012-05-27T08:15:00+00:00</updated>
    <id>http://artsy.github.io/blog/2012/05/27/using-jenkins-for-ruby-and-ruby-on-rails-teams</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>The <a href="http://jenkins-ci.org">Jenkins CI</a> project has grown tremendously in the past few months. There're now hundreds of plugins and an amazing engaged community. Artsy is a happy user and proud contributor to this effort with the essential <a href="https://wiki.jenkins-ci.org/display/JENKINS/AnsiColor+Plugin">jenkins-ansicolor plugin</a>, eliminating boring console output since 2011.</p>

<p>We are a continuous integration, deployment and devops shop and have been using Jenkins for over a year now. We've shared our experience at the <a href="http://www.cloudbees.com/juc2012.cb">Jenkins User Conference 2012</a> in <a href="http://www.slideshare.net/dblockdotorg/graduating-to-jenkins-ci-for-rubyonrails-teams">a presentation</a>. This blog post is an overview of how to get started with Jenkins for Ruby(-on-Rails) teams.</p>

<p><img src="Artsy%20Jenkins%20CI" alt="/images/2012-05-27-using-jenkins-for-ruby-on-rails-teams/jenkins.png" /></p>

<!-- more -->


<p>When Artsy had only three engineers, we hesitated to deploy Jenkins. The CI server was written in Java (i.e. wasn't written in Ruby). We feared introducing excessive infrastructure too early. In retrospect, we were not in the business of building CI infrastructure, so not using Jenkins was a mistake. Since we adopted it, Jenkins has been operating painlessly and scaled nicely as our needs continued to grow.</p>

<p>Today, we run a single virtual server on <a href="http://www.linode.com">Linode</a> as our master Jenkins and have 8 Linode slaves. These are all $19 per month plans. Our usage is variable: few builds in the middle of the night and a very high number of builds during the day, so we're planning on trying to build a Jenkins-slave on-demand system on AWS eventually.</p>

<p>Setting up a Jenkins master is straightforward.</p>

<pre><code class="bash">useradd -m jenkins -p [password] -s /bin/bash
addgroup jenkins sudo
wget -q -O - http://pkg.jenkins-ci.org/debian/jenkins-ci.org.key | sudo apt-key add –
sudo sh -c 'echo deb http://pkg.jenkins-ci.org/debian binary/ &gt; /etc/apt/sources.list.d/jenkins.list'
sudo aptitude update
sudo aptitude install jenkins
</code></pre>

<p>We change Jenkins port in <code>/etc/default/jenkins</code>, add the machine to DNS and update the Jenkins URL to an externally visible one in the "Manage Jenkins", "Configure System" menu. We enable and use "Matrix-Based Security" with a single user that all developers share and give the user permission to do everything in the same UI. Finally, we configure the Git Plugin with a global username and e-mail from our shared IT account that has Github access, setup a Github Web Hook and SMTP E-Mail notifications. Restarting Jenkins from the command line with <code>sudo service jenkins restart</code> completes the initial setup.</p>

<p>It's also a good idea to setup Jenkins configuration backup with <a href="https://wiki.jenkins-ci.org/display/JENKINS/thinBackup">thinBackup</a>, install <a href="http://wiki.jenkins-ci.org/display/JENKINS/AnsiColor+Plugin">AnsiColor</a> and, of course, enable <a href="http://wiki.hudson-ci.org/display/HUDSON/ChuckNorris+Plugin">Chuck Norris</a>.</p>

<p>A typical Ruby development environment includes <a href="https://rvm.io/">RVM</a>, a working GIT client and a Github SSH key. We install these under our <code>jenkins</code> user manually on the first slave Linode and then clone slaves when we need more. RVM setup includes entries in <code>~/.bash_profile</code>, so a Jenkins job for a Ruby project can load that file and execute commands, including <code>rake</code>.</p>

<pre><code class="bash">#!/bin/bash
source ~/.bash_profile
rvm use 1.9.2
gem install bundler
bundle install
bundle exec rake
</code></pre>

<p>Our default Ruby project Rake task is <code>test:ci</code>. We run Jasmine and Capybara tests using a real browser, so we need to redirect all visible output to an X-Windows Virtual Frame Buffer (<a href="http://www.xfree86.org/4.0.1/Xvfb.1.html">XVFB</a>). This can be done by setting an <code>ENV</code> variable inside a Rake task. Our test target also <a href="http://artsy.github.com/blog/2012/05/15/how-to-organize-over-3000-rspec-specs-and-retry-test-failures/">organizes our tests in suites</a>.</p>

<pre><code class="ruby">namespace :test do
  task :specs, [ :display ] =&gt; :environment do |t, args|
   ENV['DISPLAY'] = args[:display] if args[:display]
   Rake::Task['spec:suite:all'].invoke
  end
      
  task :jasmine, [ :display ] =&gt; :environment do |t, args|
    ENV['DISPLAY'] = args[:display] if args[:display]
    system!("bundle exec rake jasmine:ci")
  end
    
  task :all, [ :display ] =&gt; :environment do |t, args|
    Rake::Task['assets'].invoke
    Rake::Task['test:jasmine'].invoke(args[:display])
    Rake::Task['test:specs'].invoke(args[:display])
  end
      
  task :ci do
    Rake::Task['test:all'].invoke(":99")
  end
      
end
</code></pre>

<p>A successful CI test run will trigger a deployment to a staging environment on Heroku.</p>

<pre><code class="ruby">namespace :deploy do
  task :staging =&gt; :environment do
    system!("bundle exec heroku maintenance:on --app=app-staging")
    system!("git push git@heroku.com:app-staging.git origin/staging:master")
    system!("bundle exec heroku maintenance:off --app=app-staging")
  end
end
</code></pre>

<p>You'll notice that we execute system commands with <code>system!</code>. Unlike the usual <code>system</code> method, our wrapper raises an exception when a command returns a non-zero error code to abort execution.</p>

<pre><code class="ruby">def system!(cmdline)
  logger.info("[#{Time.now}] #{cmdline}")
  rc = system(cmdline)
  "failed with exit code #{$?.exitstatus}" if (rc.nil? || ! rc || $?.exitstatus != 0)
end
</code></pre>

<p>Our production deployment task is also a Jenkins job.</p>

<pre><code class="ruby">namespace :deploy do
  task :production =&gt; :environment do
    system!("git push git@heroku.com:app-production.git origin/production:master")
  end
end
</code></pre>

<p>We don't want any downtime on our production environment, so we don't turn Heroku maintance on. Our staging deployment task also includes copying production data to staging, so we chose to enable maintenance to avoid people hitting the test environment while it's being built and may be in a half-baked state.</p>

<p>Finally, we also run production daily cron-like tasks via Jenkins. It gives us email notifications, console output and the ability to manually trigger them. Centralizing operations in the same environment as CI creates truly continuous integration, deployment and operations.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
