<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: architecture | Artsy Engineering]]></title>
  <link href="http://artsy.github.io/blog/categories/architecture/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://artsy.github.io/"/>
  <updated>2018-12-16T10:16:31+00:00</updated>
  <id>http://artsy.github.io/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[A History of Artsy's Web Frontend]]></title>
    <link href="http://artsy.github.io/blog/2018/10/04/artsy-frontend-history/"/>
    <updated>2018-10-04T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <id>http://artsy.github.io/blog/2018/10/04/artsy-frontend-history</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>As Artsy Engineering grows in 2018, we have so many newcomers looking for context: they want to understand the
systems they'll be working in day-to-day. Awesome! But it's not enough to understand the systems themselves, it's
often helpful to understand the <em>history</em> of how we ended up where we are.</p>

<p>Frontend web development has changed a <em>lot</em> during Artsy's existence, and it continues to advance at a blistering
pace. It's easy to get caught up in the churn of frameworks and languages and tools, so I want to use this post as
an opportunity to contextualize each transition that Artsy's web presence has made over the past seven years. We've
changed technologies, but we've tried to do so with care and attention. Documenting these decisions is important
(and is ideally done <a href="https://ashfurrow.com/blog/contemporaneous-blogging/">contemporaneously</a>), but even with the best documentation, <a href="https://github.com/artsy/artsy.github.io/pull/489#discussion_r221301472">sometimes our own documentation
is unclear to us</a>.</p>

<p>In an effort to help contextualize our web frontend (which is <a href="https://github.com/artsy/force">open source</a>), this blog post will document
the major transitions that Artsy's web presence has made over the past seven years. Let's begin!</p>

<!-- more -->


<a name="Backbone...CoffeeScript"></a>
<h2>Backbone + CoffeeScript</h2>

<p>Artsy as you know it today began as a standard Rails application. We ran <code>git init</code> in January 2011, which coupled
our backend API to our web frontend, but since our frontend was just a fancy user interface for our API, this
worked for over two years. The web app itself was a kind of simplified MVC – controller logic lived inside the
views and models dealt with backend communication and notifying the view of state changes. For CSS, we used the
SASS CSS preprocessor. The Rails backend served initial pages that were then populated with follow-up API calls
made on the client-side. At a <em>very</em> high level, this isn't <em>that</em> different from what we do today with React.</p>

<p>Our site was built with a framework called <a href="http://backbonejs.org">Backbone</a>, which was really well-suited for our needs at the time.
From their documentation:</p>

<blockquote><p>Philosophically, Backbone is an attempt to discover the minimal set of data-structuring (models and collections)
and user interface (views and URLs) primitives that are generally useful when building web applications with
JavaScript. In an ecosystem where overarching, decides-everything-for-you frameworks are commonplace, and many
libraries require your site to be reorganized to suit their look, feel, and default behavior — Backbone should
continue to be a tool that gives you the <em>freedom</em> to design the full experience of your web application.</p></blockquote>

<p>As an outsider to the web at that time, I can't comment too heavily on Backbone. It seems like the freedom
(emphasis theirs) that they describe is a freedom from tangled jQuery code everywhere. I think our definition of
freedom on the web frontend has evolved since then, but that's just my feeling.</p>

<p>The other key component to our web frontend was <a href="https://coffeescript.org">CoffeeScript</a>. According to its documentation, "CoffeeScript is
a little language that compiles into JavaScript", which was pretty important at the time. JavaScript in 2011 was
very different from JavaScript today. The CoffeeScript docs also state that "JavaScript has always had a gorgeous
heart", which I'm not sure I'd agree with to be honest, but the CoffeeScript project really shows how a handful of
engineers working to improve something they care about can change an entire industry. While I don't think
contemporary JavaScript would have gotten as good as it has without CoffeeScript, it's a bit anachronistic to see
it used today.</p>

<p>Our goal as a (very small!) engineering team at the time was to keep our moving parts to a minimum.
Rails+SASS+CoffeeScript+Backbone helped us achieve that goal, and we couldn't have gotten this far without the help
of those projects.</p>

<a name="Ezel..amp..Friends"></a>
<h2>Ezel &amp; Friends</h2>

<p>In November 2013, we split our web frontend from the API backend. You can read
<a href="2013_review">all the details in this blog post</a>, but the story is summarized nicely as "moving from a single
monolithic application to modular Backbone apps that run in Node and the browser and consume our external API."
This move from monolith to modular systems continues to influence day-to-day work on the Artsy Engineering team.</p>

<p>We had already started moving away from a typical Rails app by moving our API to <a href="https://github.com/ruby-grape/grape">Grape</a> in order to support an
iOS application. The monolith also had some clear drawbacks including severe page load times, maintaining
duplicated backend and frontend UI templates, slow test suites, and poor developer productivity. We took the
project of building our mobile web frontend, m.artsy.net (still known as "martsy" internally) as an opportunity to
address these problems.</p>

<p>We built our new site with <a href="https://github.com/ruby-grape/grape">Node.js</a> since it allowed us to share and consolidate our server/client rendering
code. We split out areas of concern into separate "apps", with their own bundled CSS/JS to help page load times. We
server-side rendered above-the-fold content and used client-side JS to load the rest, which helped SEO and user
experience. We took a <a href="http://getbem.com/introduction/">BEM</a>-like approach to our CSS, which helped developer productivity. Our technical
decisions were driven primarily by our desire to create great user experiences.</p>

<p>And because we are an open source by default organization, we collected these approaches into an open source
project called <a href="https://github.com/artsy/ezel">Ezel</a>. While our main app used this Ezel approach, other new web apps – CMS systems for our
partners, auction-management systems for our admins, etc – were built on new internal tools to share assets and
code across the apps. We experimented a lot; we got pretty good at sharing resources across codebases. Most of our
web projects started on Heroku before moving to heavier-duty deployments as needed. Our frontend mindset at the
time (2015) was focused on getting to a stable, predictable stack. However... we started experimenting with React
around the same time.</p>

<p>CoffeeScript and Backbone were still working for us, and we still use them in production in many systems. However,
the state of the art in web development moved on. When I joined the auctions team and helped maintain one of our
CoffeeScript+Backbone apps, I was <em>very</em> confused about how data flowed from one part of the app to another, across
languages, with a lot of magic happening. I think that's typical in these kinds of apps – "convention over
configuration" is a good mantra <em>if</em> you can expect that incoming engineers are familiar with the conventions.
That's just not the case anymore.</p>

<p>By 2016, we had <a href="http://artsy.github.io/blog/2015/04/08/creating-a-dynamic-single-page-app-for-our-genome-team-using-react/">experimented with React</a> and followed up with <a href="http://artsy.github.io/blog/2016/08/09/the-tech-behind-live-auction-integration/">another app built with the
technology</a>. React (and Redux) were very well-suited for our realtime auction bidding UI, and would later
prove helpful in our <a href="https://github.com/artsy/positron">editorial CMS</a>. These experiences helped prove the technology was ready for
production use <em>and</em> convinced us that React was great at reducing the complexities of building user interfaces
(the realtime nature of our auctions product was particularly well-suited for Redux's state management; it was our
first from-scratch React app).</p>

<p>When the Artsy business require us to make changes to how we build software, like splitting up our monolith, we try
to take full advantage of those changes to improve how we work, which means evaluating new tools. Adopting Node.js
and Ezel wouldn't make sense today, but at the time, they helped us scale up Artsy's business without the same
scaling up of our engineering resources. Ezel helped us do more with less, which is still an important criteria we
use for evaluating new tools.</p>

<a name="React"></a>
<h2>React</h2>

<p>By 2017, the divisions between our mobile frontend and web frontend teams had been totally dissolved (as they
should – the division between mobile and web developers is a false dichotomy). Our <a href="http://artsy.github.io/blog/2017/04/14/artsy-technology-stack-2017/">2017 tech stack
post</a> discusses this in depth, but our goal was really to unify the paradigm that frontend engineers
at Artsy use to build user interfaces, whether that's on mobile or web. React and React Native were our answer to
that challenge.</p>

<p>On the web side of things, however, Artsy had another challenge. Sure, React is great, and sure, it's how we want
to build user interfaces, but how do we get there? We're not fans of large rewriting projects, so we opted for what
we call an "incremental revolution" approach. We built a library called <a href="https://github.com/artsy/stitch">Stitch</a> that would let us mount React
components inside our existing app. Using this approach, we could migrate to React component-by-component. We've
been using Stitch in production for over a year and have been very happy with its approach; you can read more
details of integrating it into our main frontend app <a href="http://artsy.github.io/blog/2017/09/05/Modernizing-Force/">in this blog post</a>.</p>

<p>Today, principal React work takes place in <a href="https://github.com/artsy/reaction">a shared components repo</a>. We share these components across
several of our web apps using Stitch. We have been pretty pleased with the results! But our dive into React is only
just beginning. The community is moving quickly to figure out what best practices make sense in the React paradigm,
and we're a part of that. We are evaluating technologies like <a href="https://www.styled-components.com">styled-components</a> and <a href="https://jxnblk.com/styled-system/">styled-system</a> to create
a universal design system within Artsy. The area is under very active development, so I'll save details for a
future blog post.</p>

<p>I can't go too much further without talking about GraphQL. v1 of our API (REST) is still in use around much of
Artsy and, despite the best efforts of some of our engineers, v2 of our API (<a href="http://stateless.co/hal_specification.html">HAL</a>) hasn't gained significant
internal use yet. Instead, we found ourselves building a <a href="https://graphql.org">GraphQL</a> server to orchestrate API calls to our
existing APIs. This confers many benefits, which I describe from a mobile perspective in some detail <a href="https://ashfurrow.com/blog/the-spirit-of-moya/">here</a>.
The key thing to understand about our GraphQL server, <a href="https://github.com/artsy/metaphysics/">which is open source</a>, is that it is under the
stewardship of our frontend engineers, not our platform engineers. That's not to say that our platform team isn't
involved with its development – in fact, they've been key to scaling it up – but Artsy frontend engineers created
the server to help us build better UIs, and while the technology is still very new, we continue to see it pay
dividends.</p>

<p>Okay so remember earlier when I said that we dissolved our mobile team? Well, I was on that team and it wasn't like
our mobile engineers all learned how Artsy does web – we brought our culture and tools with us and, together with
our web colleagues, have built an integrated engineering team that's greater than the sum of its parts. One thing
that was important to mobile engineers was type safety, so we had to have a conversation about JavaScript.</p>

<p>On its own, JavaScript can't guarantee type safety. We investigated two options: <a href="http://www.typescriptlang.org">TypeScript</a> and <a href="https://flow.org">Flow</a>. <a href="http://artsy.github.io/blog/2017/02/05/Front-end-JavaScript-at-Artsy-2017/">This
blog post</a> goes into detail about our decision, but tl;dr we chose TypeScript. We have been building (and
helping to build) tools <a href="https://github.com/relay-tools/relay-compiler-language-typescript">relay-compiler-language-typescript</a> to take full advantage of interoperability
between TypeScript types and GraphQL types through <a href="https://facebook.github.io/relay/">Relay</a>, as well as using Babel 7 to migrate existing projects
to TypeScript incrementally, which you can read about in more detail <a href="https://artsy.github.io/blog/2017/11/27/Babel-7-and-TypeScript/">here</a>. It's all very exciting – you
can read more on how Relay and GraphQL interoperate <a href="http://artsy.github.io/blog/2018/07/25/Relay-Networking-Deep-Dive/">in this blog post</a>.</p>

<p>We started building software in React not because it was trendy, but because it helped our engineering team deliver
more value to the business. It's been a huge success, but not without its costs. We've tried to mitigate those
costs by using tools like Stitch to migrate apps to React incrementally, and through spreading knowledge of how our
stack through internal knowledge-sharing like <a href="http://artsy.github.io/series/javascriptures/">JavaScriptures</a>. While the transition to React has had its costs,
<em>not</em> moving would also be costly, too.</p>

<hr />

<p>Since I joined Artsy, I've seen us continually investing in tooling that helps us build better software. The
results of this culture-of-continuous-improvement speak for themselves: with fewer than 30 engineers total, we
support a growing company with a suite of software built for many canvasses <em>and</em> we have an outsized impact on the
software industry relative to our size. Our frontend web stack is just one facet of our evolving technology –
there's lots of exciting stuff on the backend, too (<a href="https://github.com/artsy/hokusai">for example...</a>). Through my research for this blog
post, I learned a lot about what drives technological decisions on our team. From humble beginnings as a Rails app,
to CoffeeScript and Bootstrap, to React and GraphQL, Artsy Engineering has evolved our frontend software to achieve
a quality worthy of art – both from the user's perspective and from the developer's. I'm very excited about what's
coming next, and I can't wait to share it with you. Have a great day!</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[The Tech Behind Live Auction Integration]]></title>
    <link href="http://artsy.github.io/blog/2016/08/09/the-tech-behind-live-auction-integration/"/>
    <updated>2016-08-09T11:30:00+00:00</updated>
    <id>http://artsy.github.io/blog/2016/08/09/the-tech-behind-live-auction-integration</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>In late June, the <a href="https://www.artsy.net/auctions/">Artsy auctions</a> team launched our Live Auction Integration (LAI) product. It allows people to participate online in live sales held at auction houses <a href="https://www.artsy.net/auction-partnerships">that partner with Artsy</a>. It was a big project, begun in December, involving both brand new software and extensive integration work with the rest of our systems. This is the first in what will be a series of blog posts discussing the engineering work we did to get a complex product from inception to launch in such a brief time window, with a go-live deadline set in stone weeks in advance. In this, I’ll dig into what we shipped on a high level, as well as some of the overarching technical decisions.</p>

<!-- more -->


<p>LAI raised challenges that were novel to our engineering team. The product is a real-time experience from the perspectives of the bidder and the auction house. Producing that experience requires a complex human + computer system. There are two main flows of information: from auction house to bidder, and vice versa. These are mediated by our systems and staff as follows:</p>

<ul>
<li>As bids occur in the auction house sale room, an Artsy operator working on-site inputs that activity into a web interface so that online participants can keep track of what’s happening.</li>
<li>As online participants place bids, our system records those as “prospective bids”, and an Artsy bidding clerk on site at the auction house bids on their behalf in the auction house. As those bids are recognized, they are reflected back to all participants, through the prior flow.</li>
</ul>


<p>To make this easier to visualize:</p>

<p><img src="/images/2016-08-09-the-tech-behind-live-auction-integration/Artsy%20Live%20Auction%20Integration%20flow.png" alt="Artsy Live Auction Integration Flow" /></p>

<p>This needs to happen in a tight loop to allow online bidders to be competitive with those in the room and via auction house phone clerks. The architecture and UX of the LAI product were optimized for that goal. In addition, we built the system to integrate with live events hosted by our partners. As the events are outside our direct control, there are many, many ways things can deviate from this idealized flow. We had to carefully account for these situations.</p>

<p>Where possible, we leveraged our existing auctions technology. But we took the opportunity to upgrade that technology in some places and chose new approaches in others. Meanwhile, we were running the busiest Artsy auction season to date, and we had to ensure that we weren’t disrupting our existing stack. Below, I discuss the pieces of the end-to-end product.</p>

<a name="The.Live.user.experience"></a>
<h1>The Live user experience</h1>

<p>When the live auction actually begins, participants and Artsy staff interact with the system with front-end software developed from scratch. Web users (desktop and mobile) and staff use a new, dedicated Artsy Live web application, which is implemented in a project we call Prediction. iOS Artsy App users can also participate with newly developed UX within that app.</p>

<a name="The.web.app:.Prediction"></a>
<h2>The web app: Prediction</h2>

<p>Our bidder and operator web interfaces are implemented in an application we call Prediction, a <a href="https://medium.com/@mjackson/universal-javascript-4761051b7ae9#.ev1yd3juy">universal</a> <a href="https://facebook.github.io/react/">React</a>+<a href="http://redux.js.org/">Redux</a> JavaScript app, served from an <a href="http://expressjs.com/">Express</a> server. Using React allowed us to completely share our view layer code for pre-rendering in the server and making updates in the client.</p>

<p><img src="/images/2016-08-09-the-tech-behind-live-auction-integration/Prediction%20Bidder%20Screenshot.png" alt="Prediction Bidder UI" /></p>

<p>Keeping our state management and transition code organized with Redux allowed us to achieve a massive amount of reuse of model and controller code between our web interfaces. To solve Redux's <a href="http://stackoverflow.com/q/34570758/807674">async</a> and <a href="http://stackoverflow.com/q/34299460/807674">data conveyance</a> “problems", we built an integration layer for React and Redux called <a href="https://github.com/artsy/react-redux-controller">React Redux Controller</a>.</p>

<p><img src="/images/2016-08-09-the-tech-behind-live-auction-integration/Prediction%20Operator%20Screenshot.png" alt="Prediction Operator UI" /></p>

<p>We found the React+Redux approach to model-view-controller app development to be a major win in what it gave us for maintainability, code reuse, easy testability, and the ability to reason about our code.</p>

<a name="The.iOS.native.app:.Eigen"></a>
<h2>The iOS native app: Eigen</h2>

<p>For users of the Artsy iOS app, known to our engineering team as <a href="https://github.com/artsy/eigen">Eigen</a>, a touch-optimized LAI experience was coded in Swift. It shares the same app with existing Objective-C code as well as <a href="https://facebook.github.io/react-native/">React Native</a> code used for other aspects of the iOS experience. We considered using React Native for this, but we decided to go with more familiar technology to contain the risk.</p>

<p><img src="/images/2016-08-09-the-tech-behind-live-auction-integration/Eigen%20Bidder%20Screenshot.png" alt="Eigen Bidder UI" /></p>

<p>Both of these applications interact with our central Artsy back-end service to pull in artist, artwork, and sale metadata when the user enters the auction. These queries are mediated by a <a href="http://graphql.org/">GraphQL</a> middleware service we call <a href="https://github.com/artsy/metaphysics">Metaphysics</a> (also discussed <a href="/blog/2016/06/19/graphql-for-mobile/">here</a>), which vastly simplified the fetching process in the front-end services. But from that point forward, the apps interact with a brand new auction state management system over a bidirectional <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/WebSocket">WebSocket</a> API for live updating.</p>

<a name="The.auction.state.management.service:.Causality"></a>
<h1>The auction state management service: Causality</h1>

<p>The other recently launched piece of software delivered for LAI was a new auction state management system we call Causality. It processes bids and other auction events, computes the derived state of a sale, and hosts the bidirectional WebSocket API.</p>

<p>Causality was developed in Scala, using the <a href="http://doc.akka.io/docs/akka/current/intro/what-is-akka.html">Akka</a> technology suite for distributed computing. At its core is an append-only storage engine, based on <a href="http://doc.akka.io/docs/akka/current/scala/persistence.html">Akka Persistence</a>, with a small library we developed called <a href="https://github.com/artsy/atomic-store">Atomic Store</a> that allowed us to achieve strict consistency, at the cost of maximal throughput -- a trade-off that is explored in the readme of that project.</p>

<p>Lastly, Causality has an <a href="http://doc.akka.io/docs/akka/current/scala/http/introduction.html">Akka HTTP</a>-based API layer, with a WebSocket server implemented using <a href="http://doc.akka.io/docs/akka/current/scala/stream/stream-introduction.html">Akka Streams</a>. Asynchronous updates generated in the event processing logic are published across the cluster using <a href="http://doc.akka.io/docs/akka/current/scala/distributed-pub-sub.html">Akka Distributed Pub/Sub</a>, and they are merged into the WebSocket outflow.</p>

<a name="Pre-bidding..tooling..and.other.concerns"></a>
<h1>Pre-bidding, tooling, and other concerns</h1>

<p>In addition to accepting bids placed during a live sale, we also allow users to place bids before the event begins. In practice, this is almost the same workflow as our existing timed auction experience. For this reason, we chose to leverage all of our existing technology. The work of preparing our preexisting tech for LAI involved widespread modifications to our front-end UI, messaging services, admin tooling, and monitoring to make them appropriate for a live sale, as well as a reliable handoff of responsibility from these preexisting front- and back-end services to the new ones at the time the sale goes live.</p>

<p>We relied on our automated test suites, as well as thorough manual testing by the entire Artsy auctions team, to ensure that this handoff functioned smoothly under various circumstances. We will eventually eliminate this duplication. But this will require delicate refactoring of our preexisting tooling, which we will take on, even as we execute a fall auction season significantly busier than the last.</p>

<a name="Reflection"></a>
<h1>Reflection</h1>

<p>In the process of architecting our LAI product, we had to make some tough decisions in the face of new challenges. Chief among these were the decisions on where on the spectrum of bleeding-edge technology versus tried-and-true choices to land, for many of our subcomponents. Bleeding-edge tech often offers more elegant and performant solutions, but at the cost of learning curve and risk of immaturity. We also had to carefully prioritize functionality. Choosing wisely throughout the process was critical to shipping on time. The rationale behind these decisions and their outcomes will be the result of future pieces.</p>

<p>To close, I want to express huge thanks to the auctions product &amp; engineering team for putting in long hours to design, implement, and troubleshoot the software; the auctions arts team for providing the domain knowledge and operational feedback; and our broader Artsy engineering team, at least half of whom directly contributed code to this effort.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Cocoa Architecture: Dependencies]]></title>
    <link href="http://artsy.github.io/blog/2015/09/18/Cocoa-Architecture-Dependencies/"/>
    <updated>2015-09-18T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <id>http://artsy.github.io/blog/2015/09/18/Cocoa-Architecture-Dependencies</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>As a part of going through the design patterns we've found in the creation of the Artsy iOS apps, I'd like to talk a bit about some of
the way in which we decide our apps dependencies.</p>

<p>It's easy to think of your dependencies as being things in your Podfile, but it's a bit more nuanced than that. The tools you use for development, deployment, testing and external integrations are all things in which you depend on others to make your app work. I'd like to look into the hows and the whys of the decisions we've made.</p>

<!-- more -->


<hr />

<p>The mobile team of is a collection of smart people; we aim to work with people who have different opinions, and different backgrounds. This means we often don't agree on project direction but moving forwards is about finding compromise. Every technical project within Artsy has a de-facto leader, and they get to make the call at the end of the day.</p>

<p>This means that dependencies and priorities change per-project, because a different developer has more influence on the end result. There isn't a singular "Artsy Mobile" way.</p>

<a name="Implicit.Dependencies"></a>
<h3>Implicit Dependencies</h3>

<p>Thinking on the largest macro scope, I think these are our biggest dependencies:</p>

<ul>
<li>Xcode</li>
<li>iOS SDK</li>
<li>Swift</li>
<li>CocoaPods</li>
<li>Individual Pods</li>
<li>Fastlane</li>
</ul>


<p>Some of these are mandatory, mainly Xcode and the iOS SDK. Talk to someone at Facebook however and they'll tell you even that can become a <a href="http://facebook.github.io/react-native/">much weaker dependency</a> than you'd think. For us though, we still create native apps that eventually get built via <code>xcodebuild</code> either via Xcode/AppCode/Vim as a part of our individual build processes.</p>

<p>The dependencies provided by Apple are the daily trade-off in order to build apps that are competitive. Apple ships a new SDK each year, developers need to ship new builds. If you can keep pace, then you can get your app in-front of millions of potentially paying customers.</p>

<a name="Leveraging.OSS"></a>
<h3>Leveraging OSS</h3>

<p>So, allow me to don my best flame-proof suit and answer the intent of the question that was originally asked of us? <em>What qualities do we look for in OSS dependencies?</em></p>

<p>This question is interesting because we're not just shipping an app in the dark, every app we have is open source and available for inspection. Our choices with OSS dependencies become our implicit public recommendations, why else would we be using them?</p>

<p>To to give the simplest TLDR; I created the <a href="https://guides.cocoapods.org/making/quality-indexes">CocoaPods Quality Indexes</a>. The Quality Indexes (QIs) are a series of metrics that are applied programmatically to every library which generate a single number that <a href="http://cocoapods.org">cocoapods.org</a> uses for search ranking. These are based on conversations within Artsy, and as many contributors as I could during the course of a year. Here are a few QIs that matter a lot to me:</p>

<ul>
<li>The library is popular, this is measured in GitHub stars.</li>
<li>Great README, has a CHANGELOG and uses internal appledoc/headerdoc.</li>
<li>The project has test coverage.</li>
</ul>


<p>If you're interested in the reasoning behind these, I'd recommend reading the <a href="https://guides.cocoapods.org/making/quality-indexes">full guide for the metrics</a>.</p>

<p>If I could determine that a project was a good dependency via code - I wouldn't be writing apps, I'd be a millionaire, who has moved on to working in politics or cryptography in Denmark. So what are the key metrics that not Turing-compatible?</p>

<a name="Can.We.Take.Over."></a>
<h4>Can We Take Over?</h4>

<p>We're a pretty versatile bunch of developers, even with our focus on native iOS development. Being able to understand a foreign codebase when debugging a problem, in order to <a href="http://dictionary.reference.com/browse/grok">grok</a> if a bug lies in our code or a libraries is essential.</p>

<p>Being blocked because you don't understand how to create an assembly trampoline for message passing on 64 bit processors sucks. Relying on someone else to provide a fix in their spare time, is a nice way to strain a relationship.</p>

<p>There have been times when we've taken over libraries completely, which has worked out well for everyone involved. Examples being <a href="https://cocoapods.org/pods/NAMapKit">NAMapKit</a> and <a href="https://cocoapods.org/pods/Specta">Specta</a>/<a href="https://cocoapods.org/pods/Expecta">Expecta</a>. It can be a matter of providing small incremental work on the project, or just being someone with a vision <a href="http://orta.io/rebase/oss-management/">for the project</a>.</p>

<a name="Features.vs.Hidden.Dependencies"></a>
<h4>Features vs Hidden Dependencies</h4>

<p>A dependency can offer you shortcuts to features, new ways to do things or a way to interface with externalities. When you look at the README you get to see all of the best parts of a library, the reasons why it's worth trying, the easy installation instructions. You don't get to see some of uglier issues under the surface, that only become exposed once you look a bit harder.</p>

<p>These can be subtle for example, using Fastlane introduces a lot of dependencies.</p>

<pre><code class="sh">~/dev/scratch ⏛  cat Gemfile
gem 'fastlane'

~/dev/scratch ⏛  bundle install
[...]
Bundle complete! 1 Gemfile dependency, 73 gems now installed.
</code></pre>

<p>There's a trade-off here, Fastlane provides a great programmable API to a bunch of really annoying time-consuming tasks. There isn't a system similar to CocoaPods' subspecs which lets a library consumer choose to use a subset of a dependency graph, so instead everyone gets <code>slack-notifier</code> regardless of if you need it.</p>

<p>ReactiveCocoa feels quite similar. In exchange for Cocoa-native approach to Functional Reactive Programming you also have:</p>

<ul>
<li>Swizzling dealloc on objects in order to do it's magic KVO-unbinding at runtime.</li>
<li>To pretty much giving up on trying to use the stack trace for understanding flow. Instead you can use their custom dtrace instrument.</li>
<li>Complicated pre-compiler macros that can get tricky to debug.</li>
</ul>


<p>These trade-offs can be happily made in exchange for ReactiveCocoa's well thought out API. Functional Reactive Programming is something that the majority of us are particularly interested in. Since Swift came out, a few Swift-only FRP libraries have been released. So we've been keeping our eyes <a href="https://cocoapods.org/?q=summary%3Areactive">on the alternatives</a>.</p>

<a name="Focus"></a>
<h4>Focus</h4>

<p>Ideally you're bringing in a dependency for one specific task. Something like <a href="https://cocoapods.org/pods/ObjectiveSugar">ObjectiveSugar</a> is a great example of a small focused library. I studied it's API when we first integrated it, and it's not really changed at all since. The library authors have done a great job of ensuring that Objective Sugar stays on-topic.</p>

<a name="Community.Relationships"></a>
<h4>Community Relationships</h4>

<p>The amount of energy you have to put into using certain dependencies, in an engaging way like we do, also means you have to interact with external people. This is often the case with OSS, so we’re used to that and quite good at it. Sometimes, however, people and their opinions don’t match, it’s a fact of life, and in these cases it can be worth choosing to not use a certain dependency.</p>

<p>One such example has been ReactiveCocoa. While they are free to make whatever decisions they like, we feel that we’ve wasted energy on supporting their dependencies in CocoaPods that took away from our already constraining time-budget. Our interactions consume and creates energy that we don't want to be associated with. This makes us want to engage less with the community at whole, which is really not something we want. So that, combined with our opinion on the framework itself (as aforementioned) means we’re looking at alternatives.</p>

<p>This contrasts sharply with working on Fastlane, where we're willing to take the dependency graph in part because working with <a href="https://krausefx.com">Felix Krause</a> is such a pleasure. We've sent PRs,  helped out on <a href="https://github.com/KrauseFx/fastlane/pull/173">documentation</a> and provided advice on how we would/are using Fastlane. I actively feel guilty that we're still not deploying to the App Store using Fastlane because of this relationship.</p>

<a name="Project.Maturity"></a>
<h4>Project Maturity</h4>

<p>We got burned by working with Swift too early, but coming back at Swift 2.0 feels good. We just started introducing Swift into our Objective-C codebases, as it's looking like the tooling has matured.</p>

<p>We spent a good chunk of time over the last 6 months discussing and testing out React Native as an approach for building apps. It's turning into an amazing platform, but for us it's not mature enough to start building apps with it as a foundation.</p>

<a name="Not.All.Dependencies.are.Third.Party"></a>
<h2>Not All Dependencies are Third Party</h2>

<p>We ship a lot of our internal code as Pods. The rubric we use for deciding on when to externalise code is "would we want this in more than 2 apps" at the moment. This is an easy choice for libraries as fundamental as a fonts, or colours schemes. It becomes a more nuanced choice when it comes to <a href="https://github.com/ashfurrow/Forgeries">a class or two</a>, or <a href="https://github.com/orta/ar_dispatch">some functions</a>.</p>

<p>Creating a library that gets popular can also turn into an unexpected time-sink, we've been supporting <a href="https://cocoapods.org/pods/ARAnalytics">ARAnalytics</a> for 4 years now and nearly all features for the last 3 years have come from external developers. Ensuring that they don't break the build, making monthly releases and keeping documentation up to date takes time. <a href="https://cocoapods.org/pods/Moya">Moya</a> has consumed multiple weekends in a row of our time.</p>

<p>Ensuring that we are good stewards for the code we release as a separate consumable library is important to our team values. We've not had to deprecate a library, though I look forwards to doing that to <a href="https://cocoapods.org/pods/ORStackView">ORStackView</a> at some point when everyone is building for iOS9+.</p>

<a name="Nuance"></a>
<h3>Nuance</h3>

<p>There are no simple answers to "should you use a certain dependency". The CocoaPods QIs can give you a sense of what libraries are worth looking into, then you can load up a demo for the library by running <code>pod try [Podname]</code> to dig around and get a feel for how the library works. These decisions end up being quite personal.</p>

<p>We work with external dependencies because we enjoy:</p>

<ul>
<li>Working with other people.</li>
<li>Making improvements for the entire community, instead of just ourselves.</li>
<li>Not having to re-invent the wheel.</li>
</ul>


<p>For us, it's nearly always win-win.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Cocoa Architecture: Dropped Design Patterns]]></title>
    <link href="http://artsy.github.io/blog/2015/09/01/Cocoa-Architecture-Dropped-Design-Patterns/"/>
    <updated>2015-09-01T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <id>http://artsy.github.io/blog/2015/09/01/Cocoa-Architecture-Dropped-Design-Patterns</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>As a part of going through the design patterns we've found in the creation of the Artsy iOS apps, I'd like to talk a bit about some of the patterns that we've had and migrated away from. This is not 100% comprehensive, as there has been a lot of time, and a lot of people involved. Instead I'm going to try and give a birds eye view, and zoom in on some things that feel more important overall.</p>

<p>It's important to preface that I don't believe in perfect code, or am I a fan of big re-writes. We can spot a bad pattern, but not do anything about it. We do have apps to ship, not a codebase to make perfect for the sake of technical purity.</p>

<!-- more -->


<hr />

<a name="NSNotifications.as.a.decoupling.method"></a>
<h2>NSNotifications as a decoupling method</h2>

<p>A lot of the initial codebase for Energy relied on using NSNotifications as a way of passing messages throughout the application. There were notifications for user settings changes, download status updates, anything related to authentication and the corresponding different error states and a few app features. These relied on sending global notifications with very little attempts at scoping the relationship between objects.</p>

<p>NSNotificationCenter notifications are an implementation of the <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Observer_pattern">Observer Pattern</a> in Cocoa. They are a beginner to intermediate programmer's design paradigm dream. It offers a way to have objects send messages to each other without having to go through any real coupling. As someone just starting with writing apps for iOS, it was an easy choice to adapt.</p>

<p>One of the biggest downsides of using NSNotifications are that they make it easy to be lazy as a programmer. It allows you to not think carefully about the relationships between your objects and instead to pretend that they are loosely coupled, when instead they are coupled but via stringly typed notifications.</p>

<p>Loose-coupling can have it's place but without being careful there is no scope on what could be listening to any notification. Also de-registering for interest can be a tricky thing <a href="http://stackoverflow.com/questions/tagged/nsnotification">to learn</a> and the default memory-management behavior is about to change ( <a href="https://developer.apple.com/library/prerelease/mac/releasenotes/Foundation/RN-Foundation/index.html#//apple_ref/doc/uid/TP30000742">for the better</a>.)</p>

<p>We still have a <a href="https://github.com/artsy/energy/blob/702036664a087db218d3aece8ddddb2441f931c8/Classes/Constants/ARNotifications.h">lot of notifications</a> in Energy, however in Eigen and Eidolon there are next to none. We don't even have a specific file for the constants.</p>

<a name="L.define.kARConstant"></a>
<h2>#define kARConstant</h2>

<p>Not much to say here, using <code>#defines</code> as constants was definitely <a href="https://github.com/adium/adium/blob/master/Source/AdiumAccounts.m#L24-L30">in favour</a> when I learned Objective-C. Likely a throw back from C. Using <code>#defines</code> as constants would not use on-device memory to store an unchanging value. This is because a <code>#define</code> uses the pre-compiler to directly change the source code to be the value, whereas using a static constant takes up memory space on the device, which we used to <em>really</em> care about. It's likely that a modern copy of LLVM doesn't assign on device memory unless it needs to, especially for things marked <code>const</code>. Switching to real variables means you can inspect and use in a debugger and use can rely on the type system better.</p>

<p>What this means in practice is what when we would have had something <a href="https://github.com/artsy/eigen/blob/master/Artsy/Views/Table_View_Cells/AdminTableView/ARAnimatedTickView.m#L3">like</a>: <code>#define TICK_DIMENSION 32</code> it should be <a href="https://github.com/artsy/eigen/blob/master/Artsy/View_Controllers/App_Navigation/ARAppSearchViewController.m#L11">migrated to</a> <code>static const NSInteger ARTickViewDimensionSize = 20;</code>.</p>

<a name="Sprinkling.Analytics"></a>
<h2>Sprinkling Analytics</h2>

<p>We took some of the ideas for <a href="http://albertodebortoli.github.io/blog/2014/03/25/an-aspect-oriented-approach-programming-to-ios-analytics/">Aspect oriented programming</a> with <a href="https://cocoapods.org/pods/ARAnalytics#user-content-aspect-oriented-dsl">Analytics</a>.</p>

<p>Where we used to <a href="https://github.com/artsy/energy/blob/master/Classes/Controllers/Popovers/Add%20to%20Album/ARAddToAlbumViewController.m#L271-L282">have this</a>:</p>

<pre><code class="objc">@implementation ARAddToAlbumViewController

- (void)tableView:(UITableView *)tableView didSelectRowAtIndexPath:(NSIndexPath *)indexPath
{
    if (indexPath.row &lt; [self.albums count]) {
        Album *selectedAlbum = ((Album *)self.albums[indexPath.row]);
        ARTickedTableViewCell *cell = (ARTickedTableViewCell *)[self.tableView cellForRowAtIndexPath:indexPath];

        if ([cell isSelected]) {
            [ARAnalytics event:ARRemoveFromAlbumEvent withProperties:@{
                @"artworks" : @(self.artworks.count),
                @"from" : [ARNavigationController pageID]
            }];
            [...]
</code></pre>

<p>We would instead build something <a href="https://github.com/artsy/eigen/blob/master/Artsy/App/ARAppDelegate+Analytics.m#L69">like this</a>:</p>

<pre><code class="objc">@implementation ARAppDelegate (Analytics)

- (void)setupAnalytics
{
    ArtsyKeys *keys = [[ArtsyKeys alloc] init];
    [...]
    [ARAnalytics setupWithAnalytics: @{ [...] } configuration:
    @{
        ARAnalyticsTrackedEvents:
            @[
                @{
                    ARAnalyticsClass: ARAddToAlbumViewController.class,
                    ARAnalyticsDetails: @[
                        @{
                            ARAnalyticsEventName: ARRemoveFromAlbumEvent,
                            ARAnalyticsSelectorName: NSStringFromSelector(@selector(tableView: didSelectRowAtIndexPath:)),
                            ARAnalyticsProperties: ^NSDictionary*(ARAddToAlbumViewController *controller, NSArray *_) {
                                return @{
                                    @"artworks" : @(controller.artworks.count),
                                    @"from" : [ARNavigationController pageID],
                                };
                        },
                        [...]
                    ]
                },
                [...]
</code></pre>

<p>This gives us the ability to not sprinkle analytics code around the app in every file. It keeps the responsibilities of objects simpler and we've been happy with it in Eigen. We've not migrated it into Energy, its dependency on ReactiveCocoa brings too much additional weight. So far we've been applying analytics inline, Energy has much less need for individual analytics throughout the application. If you want to learn more about this pattern check out <a href="http://artsy.github.io/blog/2014/08/04/aspect-oriented-programming-and-aranalytics/">Aspect-Oriented Programming and ARAnalytics</a>.</p>

<a name="Class.Methods.as.the.whole.API"></a>
<h2>Class Methods as the whole API</h2>

<p>For a very long time, I preferred aesthetics of class based APIs. E.g. using only class methods instead instance methods. I think I still do. However, once you start adding tests to a project then they become a bit of a problem.</p>

<p>I'm a big fan of the idea of Dependency Injection within tests. This, roughly <em>TL:DR'd</em>, means passing in any additional context, instead of an object finding the context itself. A common case is a call to <code>NSUserDefaults</code>. It's very likely <em>not</em> the role of your class to know which <code>NSUserDefault</code>s object you're working with, but it's likely that you're making that decision in the method by doing something like <code>[[NSUserDefaults standardUserDefaults] setObject:reminderID forKey:@"ARReminderID"];</code>. Using dependency injection would be allowing that object to come from outside that method. If you're interested in a longer and better, explanation, read this great <a href="https://www.objc.io/issues/15-testing/dependency-injection/">objc.io</a> by <a href="http://qualitycoding.org/about/">Jon Reid</a>.</p>

<p>The problem with a class based API, is that it becomes difficult to inject that object. This doesn't flow well with writing simple, fast tests. You can use a mocking library to fake the class API, but that feels weird. Mocking should be used for things you don't control. You control the object if you're making the API. Having an instance'd object means being able to provide different versions with different behaviors or values, even better if you can reduce the behavior to <a href="https://github.com/artsy/eigen/blob/e19ac594bf6240d076e8092d9c56e9876c94444e/Artsy/Networking/Network_Models/ARArtistNetworkModel.h">a protocol</a>.</p>

<a name="Objects.Sneakily.Networking"></a>
<h2>Objects Sneakily Networking</h2>

<p>When you have a complicated application, there can be a lot of places you can perform networking. We've had it in models, view controllers and views. Basically throwing the idea of purity in MVC out of the system. We started to recognise a pattern in eigen, we were not doing a good job of keeping our networking well abstracted. If you want to see the full story check out the <a href="https://github.com/Moya/Moya">moya/Moya README</a>.</p>

<p>One attempt to at trying to fix this pattern by creating a different type of networking client I've just referenced, <a href="https://github.com/Moya/Moya">Moya</a>.</p>

<p>The other was to abstract any networking performed into a separate object. If you've heard of Model-View-ViewModel (<a href="http://www.teehanlax.com/blog/model-view-viewmodel-for-ios/">MVVM</a>) then this is a similar premise for networking instead of views. Network Models give us a way to abstract the networking into a set of behaviors. The extra abstraction means that you think "I want the things related to <em>x</em>" instead of "send a GET to address <em>x</em> and turn it into <em>y</em>."</p>

<p>Network models also make it extremely easy to swap behavior out in tests. In eigen, we have our asynchronous networking <a href="https://github.com/artsy/eigen/pull/575">run synchronously in tests</a> but we still use the network models to be able to provide <a href="https://github.com/artsy/eigen/blob/master/Artsy_Tests/View_Controller_Tests/Artist/ARArtistViewControllerTests.m#L29-L40">whatever data we want to expect</a> from the server in our tests.</p>

<a name="Subclassing.more.than.twice"></a>
<h2>Subclassing more than twice</h2>

<p>As projects evolve it can become very easy to subclass <em>x</em> in order to provide a "similar but a little bit different" behavior. Perhaps you need to <a href="https://github.com/artsy/eigen/blob/e19ac594bf6240d076e8092d9c56e9876c94444e/Artsy/View_Controllers/Web_Browsing/ARTopMenuInternalMobileWebViewController.m#L58">override some methods</a>, or add a <a href="https://github.com/artsy/eigen/blob/e19ac594bf6240d076e8092d9c56e9876c94444e/Artsy/View_Controllers/Web_Browsing/AREndOfLineInternalMobileWebViewController.h#L5">specific behavior</a>. Like the <a href="http://ezinearticles.com/?The-Boiled-Frog-Phenomenon&amp;id=932310">urban myth</a> of a frog being slowly boiled, you end up with a difficult to understand codebase as expected behavior mutates depending on how deep the hierarchy goes.</p>

<p>One pattern for handling this is <a href="http://stackoverflow.com/questions/9710411/ios-grasping-composition">class composition</a>. This is the idea that instead of having one object do multiple things, you allow a collection of objects to work together. Providing more space for each object to conform to the Single Responsibility Principle (<a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Single_responsibility_principle">SRP</a>.) If you're interested in this, you may also be interested in the <a href="https://developer.apple.com/library/ios/documentation/General/Conceptual/CocoaEncyclopedia/ClassClusters/ClassClusters.html">class clusters</a> pattern.</p>

<p>A good example of this comes <a href="https://github.com/artsy/energy/blob/aa97d90cf37932d4c0f49ea4c4d31f7e491f16a6/Classes/Controllers/Top%20View%20Controller/ARTopViewToolbarController.m">from Energy</a>, our root view controller <code>ARTopViewController</code> used to control its own toolbar items. Over 4 years this became difficult to manage, and a lot of extra code in the view controller. By abstracting out the implementation details of managing the toolbar items into it's <a href="https://github.com/artsy/energy/blob/aa97d90cf37932d4c0f49ea4c4d31f7e491f16a6/Classes/Controllers/Top%20View%20Controller/ARTopViewToolbarController.m">own class</a> we were able to allow the <code>ARTopViewController</code> to state what it wanted by not how it was done.</p>

<a name="Configuration.Classes.over.Inter-Class.Communication"></a>
<h2>Configuration Classes over Inter-Class Communication</h2>

<p>A one of the most important aspects of Energy is to <a href="http://folio.artsy.net">email artworks</a>. So there is a lot of code around configuring the email you want to send, and then generating HTML from those settings. This started out pretty simple as we had very few app-wide settings. Over time, deciding what we need to show in terms of settings and how they affected the email became very complicated.</p>

<p>The part that eventually became a strong enough code-smell to warrant a re-write was the view controller which allowed a partner to choose what information to send would pass details individually to an object that would generate the HTML. I found it difficult to write simple tests for the class' behavior. Initially I would mock the email composer, then inspect the methods that were called. This felt wrong, as you shouldn't really be mocking classes you own. Given the importance of the functionality that classes provide our application, ideas on ways to improve the section of code stayed on my mind for a long time.</p>

<p>The fix came to me during Justin Searls' talk <a href="https://speakerdeck.com/searls/sometimes-a-controller-is-just-a-controller">Sometimes a Controller is Just a Controller</a> - specifically slide <a href="https://speakerdeck.com/searls/sometimes-a-controller-is-just-a-controller?slide=55">55</a>. Justin talks about objects that <em>either hold and describe a value or perform useful behavior, never both</em>.</p>

<p>I took this advice and re-evaluated the relationship between settings view controller and composer object. Before the change, the settings view controller would configure the composer directly. Now, the settings view controller creates a configuration object and the composer consumes it. This made it <em>significantly</em> easier to write tests for both objects, as they have very obvious inputs and outputs in the form of a <a href="https://github.com/artsy/energy/blob/aa97d90cf37932d4c0f49ea4c4d31f7e491f16a6/Classes/Util/Emails/AREmailSettings.h">AREmailSettings</a>. The <a href="https://github.com/artsy/energy/blob/aa97d90cf37932d4c0f49ea4c4d31f7e491f16a6/ArtsyFolio%20Tests/Util/AREmailComposerTests.m">AREmailComposerTests</a> in particular become much more elegant.</p>

<a name="Direct.use.of.Responder.Chain"></a>
<h3>Direct use of Responder Chain</h3>

<p>Before I worked at Artsy, I was a <a href="http://i.imgur.com/Am9LjED.gif">Mac developer</a>, I've been doing that since before iOS existed, so this influences my code style. One of the great parts of the Cocoa toolchain is the <a href="https://developer.apple.com/library/ios/documentation/EventHandling/Conceptual/EventHandlingiPhoneOS/event_delivery_responder_chain/event_delivery_responder_chain.html">responder chain</a>, a well documented way of passing methods up a known chain of objects. It solves a common problem with complicated view structures. You could have a button that is generated at runtime deep inside a view hierarchy and you would like the view controller to handle it being tapped. You could use a long chain of delegate methods, or use a <a href="https://twitter.com/unimp0rtanttech/status/555828778015129600">private method</a> to get the reference to the view controller instance. On the Mac usage of the responder chain is a common pattern, on iOS it is used rarely.</p>

<p>We have this problem with our Artwork view controller in Eigen. There are buttons that are many <a href="https://speakerdeck.com/orta/ios-at-artsy?slide=38">stack views deep</a> that need to pass a message back to the view controller. When we first hit this the issue I immediately used the responder chain, you write a <a href="https://github.com/artsy/eigen/blob/e19ac594bf6240d076e8092d9c56e9876c94444e/Artsy/Views/Artwork/ARArtworkActionsView.m#L85">line of code</a> like: <code>[bidButton addTarget:self action:@selector(tappedBidButton:) forControlEvents:UIControlEventTouchUpInside];</code> where the <code>self</code> is referring to the view. This would send the message <code>tappedBidButton:</code> up the responder chain where it is reacted upon by the <a href="https://github.com/artsy/eigen/blob/e19ac594bf6240d076e8092d9c56e9876c94444e/Artsy/View_Controllers/Artwork/ARArtworkViewController+ButtonActions.m#L114">ARArtworkViewController</a>.</p>

<p>I had to explain the premise of the responder chain to almost everyone touching this area of the code base. This is great in terms of the <a href="https://xkcd.com/1053/">"lucky 10,000"</a> but  means that the pattern is unintuitive to those who have not previously heard of it. There was one more issue, the lack of coupling means that renaming selectors via refactoring can break the chain.</p>

<p>The way that we reduced the cognitive load was via a protocol, all of the actions that the responder chain will use are mapped inside <a href="https://github.com/artsy/eigen/blob/e19ac594bf6240d076e8092d9c56e9876c94444e/Artsy/Views/Artwork/ARArtworkActionsView.h#L10-L20">ARArtworkActionsViewButtonDelegate</a>-like protocols. It's a bit of a white-lie given that there is no direct relationship using the protocol in the app, but it makes the relationship more obvious. We use a class extension that <a href="https://github.com/artsy/eigen/blob/e19ac594bf6240d076e8092d9c56e9876c94444e/Artsy/View_Controllers/Artwork/ARArtworkViewController+ButtonActions.h#L11">conforms to these types of protocols</a> to keep the actions all kept in one place.</p>

<a name="Wrap-up"></a>
<h3>Wrap-up</h3>

<p>There are many design patterns, and they all come with trade-offs. Over time, our opinions on what is "good code" changes, this is great. It's important that as developers we understand that being able to change our minds is one of the most vital skills we have in our toolchain. This means being open to opinions outside of your usual sphere of influence and to maybe bring some good ideas from them. It's great to be passionate about an aspect of how we craft applications, but from my perspective, the best programmers choose pragmatism over idealism.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Cocoa Architecture: Hybrid Apps]]></title>
    <link href="http://artsy.github.io/blog/2015/08/24/Cocoa-Architecture-Hybrid-Apps/"/>
    <updated>2015-08-24T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <id>http://artsy.github.io/blog/2015/08/24/Cocoa-Architecture-Hybrid-Apps</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>As a part of going through the design patterns we've found in the creation of the Artsy iOS apps, I'd like to talk a bit about <em>Hybrid Applications</em>. A hybrid application refers to an app that uses native code and web content intertwined. Our flagship iOS app, <a href="https://github.com/artsy/eigen">eigen</a> is a hybrid app, and it seems to get more and more hybrid-y each release. Let's talk a little bit about the pros and cons of this approach.</p>

<!-- more -->


<hr />

<a name="What.is.a.Hybrid.App"></a>
<h1>What is a Hybrid App</h1>

<p>Above is the widest possible definition above, so let's dig in as this can be a contentious. There is a whole spectrum of which an app can be classed as a hybrid app. This ranges from more or less web-tech everywhere to 100% native code like Objective-C / Swift.</p>

<p>A great example of the furthest to the web-side is <a href="https://atom.io">ATOM</a>, the text editor. It's on the extreme side because all of the user interface is built using HTML + CSS, and almost all of the app is in javascript. The trade-off for them is that their developers can easy write cross-platform code, that will work reliably with technology that the vast majority of programmers use. This vastly reduces the barrier to entry for contributors and gives ATOM a really large community of programmers to draw from with respect to extending the app.</p>

<p>An example of a purely native application would be <a href="https://github.com/artsy/energy/">Energy</a>. It's over a hundred thousand plus lines of Objective-C. Yet under the hood, there's definitely some web-tech there. Prior to iOS7 <code>UILabel</code>s, <code>UITextField</code>s and <code>UITextField</code>s <a href="http://www.objc.io/issues/5-ios7/getting-to-know-textkit/">used WebKit for rendering</a>. Not to mention that when a Partner sends an email via Energy, the editor is a <code>UIWebView</code>. However, from the app developer's perspective they are creating native interactions that are consistent with the rest of the operating system's behavior.</p>

<a name="Eigen"></a>
<h1>Eigen</h1>

<p>When we started building Eigen, it was very obvious that we had a Sisyphean task ahead of us. We wanted to take the core ideas of the Artsy website,  <em>The Art World Online</em>, and convert it into mobile, <em>The Art World in Your Pocket</em>.</p>

<p>That's not impossible, but the mobile team was a fraction of the Artsy development team. Any new features added to the website would need a mobile equivalent, and given the speed in which web developer's can ship, we'd need to outnumber them to stand a chance at keeping up.</p>

<p>So, we opted for building a highly integrated mobile website at the same time, it would use the same design language as the iOS app and can act as a way for Android devices to access Artsy.</p>

<a name="Techniques.for.Doing.It.Well"></a>
<h1>Techniques for Doing It Well</h1>

<p>So we'll be talking about our <a href="https://github.com/artsy/eigen/blob/6bb44a01c1b23fb8e92c645c3091fd33725743c3/Artsy/View_Controllers/Web_Browsing/ARInternalMobileWebViewController.m">ARInteralMobileViewController</a> - which currently relies on <code>UIWebView</code> but is in <a href="https://github.com/artsy/eigen/pull/606">the process of</a> migrating to <code>WKWebkit</code>.</p>

<ul>
<li><p>Scroll like an <a href="https://github.com/artsy/eigen/blob/6bb44a01c1b23fb8e92c645c3091fd33725743c3/Artsy/View_Controllers/Web_Browsing/ARExternalWebBrowserViewController.m#L39">iOS app</a> by setting the web view's <code>scrollView.decelerationRate = UIScrollViewDecelerationRateNormal</code>.</p></li>
<li><p>Use a simple design language to avoid the <a href="http://tvtropes.org/pmwiki/pmwiki.php/Main/UncannyValley">uncanny valley</a>. Care about using the same <a href="https://github.com/artsy/Artsy-UILabels">typographical rules</a> on everything including tabs, buttons and switches.</p></li>
<li><p>Take over navigation. This means pushing a <a href="https://github.com/artsy/eigen/blob/6bb44a01c1b23fb8e92c645c3091fd33725743c3/Artsy/View_Controllers/Web_Browsing/ARInternalMobileWebViewController.m#L180">new view controller</a> on the navigation stack every time a user intends to change context.</p></li>
<li><p>Take over common OS features. We take over <a href="https://github.com/artsy/eigen/blob/master/Artsy/View_Controllers/Web_Browsing/ARInternalMobileWebViewController.m#L184-L190">social sharing</a>  instead of letting the web site send you to an external page, offering a native share sheet instead.</p></li>
</ul>


<a name="Downsides"></a>
<h1>Downsides</h1>

<p>When you choose developer ease over user experience it's important to take into consideration some of the downsides.</p>

<ul>
<li><p>Localisation is difficult. Cocoa offers a great localisation APIs. We can't use them, otherwise half of our app is correctly localised and the rest isn't.</p></li>
<li><p>Conforming to the operating system's Human Interface Guidelines is difficult, as you're relying less on foundations built with this in mind.</p></li>
<li><p>Web tech is slower, and threading APIs are generally poor. A difficulty here is that you are also complicating the technical stack upon which your app sits above. When relying on web-tech in a Mac app, it's common for that trade-off to show itself in excessive memory usage over time.</p></li>
</ul>


<a name="Evolution"></a>
<h1>Evolution</h1>

<p>One of the most interesting developments this year in the Cocoa world is Facebook's <a href="https://cocoapods.org/pods/React">react-native</a>, a bridge between web technology and native code that doesn't rely on using the <a href="http://www.quirksmode.org/dom/intro.html">traditional DOM</a> - freeing it from a lot of the common problems found in highly web-based apps.</p>

<p>We're pretty optimistic about it on the mobile team. We're not quite willing to jump head-first into a <a href="http://artsy.github.io/blog/2014/11/13/eidolon-retrospective/">pre-1.0 technology</a> again, but it shows a lot of promise.</p>

<p>The fact that we were able to ship an app at all was because we could build the parts that meant the most to us native, then rely on web technologies to cover the rest of the ground. By being pragmatic in our approach to using web tech, we have the chance to stand on the shoulders of giants.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
