<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: Rails | Artsy Engineering]]></title>
  <link href="http://artsy.github.io/blog/categories/rails/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://artsy.github.io/"/>
  <updated>2013-12-18T12:56:57-05:00</updated>
  <id>http://artsy.github.io/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Artsy]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Bootstrapping JSON Data with Rails and Backbone.js]]></title>
    <link href="http://artsy.github.io/blog/2013/04/13/bootstrapping-json-data-with-rails-and-backbone-js/"/>
    <updated>2013-04-13T12:21:00-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://artsy.github.io/blog/2013/04/13/bootstrapping-json-data-with-rails-and-backbone-js</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>The <a href="http://artsy.net">artsy.net website</a> is a Backbone.js application that talks to a server-side RESTful Grape API sitting on top of a Rails app which serves minimal HTML markup. The latter includes such things as a page title, along with links to JavaScript and stylesheet packages. A page loads, scripts run, data is fetched from the API. The result is merged into a HAMLJS template and rendered client-side.</p>

<p>Building this kind of one-page apps allows for clean separation between the presentation and API layers. The downside is that it will slow page render times - fetching data after page load means waiting for an AJAX request to complete before displaying anything.</p>

<p>There're many solutions to this problem, all involving some kind of server-side rendering. You could, for example, share views and JavaScript between client and server. This would be a major paradigm shift for a large application like ours and not something we could possibly maneuver in a short amount of time.</p>

<p>Without changing the entire architecture of the system, how can we bootstrap JSON data server-side and avoid the data roundtrip on every page load?</p>

<!-- more -->


<h3>Model Repository</h3>

<p>First, we need to keep track of our objects on the client. We've implemented a simple data repository. It ensures that the same model is passed around instead of instantiating new models each time. This helps prevent unnecessary trips to the server, and makes sure events are bound to the same model instance.</p>

<p>``` coffeescript
App.Repository =</p>

<p>  # Gets a model from the repository or fetches it from the server.
  getOrFetch: (id, options) ->
    model = @get(id)
    if model?
      options?.success? options, model
      model
    else
      model = new @model({ id: id })
      model.fetch options
      @add model
    model</p>

<h1>Function to extend a collection in to a repository</h1>

<p>App.Repository.extend = (collectionClass) ->
  collection = new collectionClass
  repository = _.extend collection, App.Repository
  repository.collectionClass = collectionClass
  repository
```</p>

<p>Objects of the same type are stored together in a repository collection.</p>

<p>``` coffeescript
class App.Collections.Artists extends Backbone.Collection</p>

<p>  model: App.Models.Artist
  App.Repositories.Artists = App.Repository.extend @</p>

<pre><code>
### Fetching Data

A view requires data before it can be rendered. For example, navigating to [artsy.net/artist/hendrik-kerstens](http://artsy.net/artist/hendrik-kerstens) (a Dutch photographer who obsessively took pictures of his daughter in all kinds of artificial setups for 20 years) will call the following.

``` coffeescript
class App.Views.ArtistView extends Backbone.View

  render: -&gt;

    App.Repositories.Artists.getOrFetch @options.artistId,
      success: (artist) =&gt;
        @$el.html(JST['templates/artist/show']({ artist: artist }))
</code></pre>

<h3>Bootstrapping Data</h3>

<p>Since our implementation sits on top of a Rails app, we can now bootstrap the data in a server-side Rails view without any JavaScript code changes. The following example lives in <code>app/views/artists/_bootstrap.html.haml</code>.</p>

<p><code>javascript
:javascript
  var json = $.parseJSON("#{j @artist.to_json}")
  App.Repositories.Artists.add(new App.Models.Artist(json));
</code></p>

<p>You must encode JSON data inside a Rails template, otherwise unicode characters like U+2028 become actual line-endings. This has been discussed <a href="http://stackoverflow.com/questions/2965293/javascript-parse-error-on-u2028-unicode-character">here</a> and <a href="http://stackoverflow.com/questions/9691611/print-valid-non-escaped-json-in-a-view-with-rails">here</a>. The <code>j</code> above is an alias for <code>escape_javascript</code>.</p>

<p>The Rails view layout calls <code>yield :javascript</code> and the <code>show.html.haml</code> template includes the bootstrapped data as a partial.</p>

<p><code>haml
= content_for :javascript do
  = render partial: "artists/bootstrap"
</code></p>

<p>The generated HTML includes the escaped JSON representation of the artist, which will be parsed client-side when the page loads and inserted into <code>App.Repositories.Artists</code>. The <code>App.Views.ArtistView</code> will no longer need to fetch the data from the server with an AJAX call.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[How To Redirect Bang Hash Urls]]></title>
    <link href="http://artsy.github.io/blog/2012/03/06/how-to-redirect-bang-hash-urls/"/>
    <updated>2012-03-06T09:02:00-05:00</updated>
    <id>http://artsy.github.io/blog/2012/03/06/how-to-redirect-bang-hash-urls</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Sometimes you type a hash-bang URL too fast, bang first.</p>

<p>Consider <code>http://artsy.net/!#/log_in</code>. Rails will receive <code>/!</code> as the file path, resulting in a 404, File Not Found error. The part of the URL after the hash is a position within the page and is never sent to the web server.</p>

<p>It's actually pretty easy to handle this scenario and redirect to the corresponding hash-bang URL.</p>

<p>The most straightforward way is to create a file called <code>!.html</code> in your <code>public</code> folder and use JavaScript to rewrite the URL with the bang-hash.</p>

<p><code>html public/!.html
&lt;html&gt;
 &lt;head&gt;
 &lt;/head&gt;
 &lt;body&gt;
  Click &lt;a href="#" onclick="return window.redirect();"&gt;here&lt;/a&gt; if you're not redirected ...
  &lt;script language="javascript"&gt;
    window.redirect = function() {
      window.location = '/#!' + window.location.hash.substring(1)
      return false;
    }
    window.redirect();
  &lt;/script&gt;
 &lt;/body&gt;
&lt;/html&gt;
</code></p>

<p>You can also do this inside a controller with a view or layout. Start by trapping the URL in your <code>ApplicationController</code>.</p>

<p><code>ruby app/controllers/application_controller.rb
if request.env['PATH_INFO'] == '/!'
  render layout: "bang_hash"
  return
end
</code></p>

<p>The layout can have the piece of JavaScript that redirects to the corresponding hash-bang URL.</p>

<p><code>ruby app/views/layouts/bang_hash.html.haml
!!!
- ie_tag(:html) do
  %body
    :javascript
      window.location = '/#!' + window.location.hash.substring(1)
</code></p>

<p>You can try this on <a href="http://artsy.net/!#/log_in" target="_blank">http://artsy.net/!#/log_in</a>. Watch it flip the bang-hash into a hash-bang and redirect to our login page. The redirect page could also be a good place to put an easter egg ;)</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[10x Rack and Rails Output Compression with Rack::Deflater]]></title>
    <link href="http://artsy.github.io/blog/2012/02/24/10x-rack-and-rails-output-compression-with-rack-deflater/"/>
    <updated>2012-02-24T16:05:00-05:00</updated>
    <id>http://artsy.github.io/blog/2012/02/24/10x-rack-and-rails-output-compression-with-rack-deflater</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>You can quickly reduce the amount of data transferred from your Rack or Rails application with <a href="https://github.com/rack/rack/blob/master/lib/rack/deflater.rb">Rack::Deflater</a>. Anecdotal evidence shows a reduction from a 50Kb JSON response into about 6Kb. It may be a huge deal for your mobile clients.</p>

<p>For a Rails application, modify config/application.rb or config/environment.rb.</p>

<p><code>ruby config/application.rb
Acme::Application.configure do
  config.middleware.use Rack::Deflater
end
</code></p>

<p>For a Rack application, add the middleware in config.ru.</p>

<p><code>ruby config.ru
use Rack::Deflater
run Acme::Instance
</code></p>

<!-- more -->


<p>Note that the order of the middleware is very important. For example, we also use Rack::JSONP that adds automatic JSONP support to our API. It must be invoked before Rack::Deflater or it will attempt to wrap compressed content. Rack middleware is executed in reverse order [<a href="http://verboselogging.com/2010/01/20/proper-rack-middleware-ordering">source</a>].</p>

<p><code>ruby config/application.rb
  config.middleware.use Rack::Deflater
  config.middleware.use Rack::JSONP
</code></p>

<p>A couple of handy RSpec tests to add to your application. You will need to modify this code with a valid API path and expected response.</p>

<p>``` ruby spec/api/rack_deflater_spec.rb
require 'spec_helper'</p>

<p>describe Rack::Deflater do
  it "produces an identical eTag whether content is deflated or not" do
    get "/api/acme"
    response.headers["Content-Encoding"].should be_nil
    etag = response.headers["Etag"]
    content_length = response.headers["Content-Length"].to_i
    get "/api/acme", {}, { "HTTP_ACCEPT_ENCODING" => "gzip" }
    response.headers["Etag"].should == etag
    response.headers["Content-Length"].to_i.should_not == content_length
    response.headers["Content-Encoding"].should == "gzip"
  end
  it "deflates JSONP content" do
    get "/api/acme?callback=parseResponse", {}, { "HTTP_ACCEPT_ENCODING" => "deflate" }
    response.headers["Content-Encoding"].should == "deflate"
    inflated_response_body = Zlib::Inflate.new(-Zlib::MAX_WBITS).inflate(response.body.to_s)
    inflated_response_body.should == "parseResponse(...)"
  end
end
```</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
