<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: energy | Artsy Engineering]]></title>
  <link href="http://artsy.net/categories/energy/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://artsy.net/"/>
  <updated>2015-08-20T17:38:40-04:00</updated>
  <id>http://artsy.net/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Cocoa Architecture: ARSwitchboard]]></title>
    <link href="http://artsy.net/blog/2015/08/18/Cocoa-Architecture:-Switchboard-Pattern/"/>
    <updated>2015-08-18T20:00:00-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://artsy.net/blog/2015/08/18/Cocoa-Architecture:-Switchboard-Pattern</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>As a part of going through the design patterns we've found in the creation of the Artsy iOS apps, I'd like to introduce the Switchboard pattern. This evolved quite naturally out of <a href="/blog/2015/08/15/Cocoa-Architecture:-Router-Pattern/">ARRouter</a> when applied to generating view controllers instead of API requests.  <!-- more --></p>

<hr />

<h1>Where we started</h1>

<p>In what must be one of my best named commits, <code>b9ff28</code> aka <em>"CREATING THE VOID"</em> introduced an <code>ARSwitchboard</code> to Eigen. Aside from this being the commit where I could finally write <code>[ARVoidViewController theVoid]</code> it added support for tapping an Artwork on the home-screen and going to another view controller.</p>

<p>We knew up-front that we needed to emulate the website's URL schemes, so we needed to come up with a way to support two ways of loading up a view controller. Here's what it looked like:</p>

<pre><code class="objc">@implementation ARSwitchBoard

+ (void)setupRouter {
    artsyHosts = [NSSet setWithObjects:@"art.sy", @"artsyapi.com", @"artsy.net", nil];

    [RCRouter map:@"/artwork/:id" to:self with:@selector(loadArtworkFromURL:)];
}

+ (void)navigateToURL:(NSURL *)url {
    if([self isInternalURL:url] &amp;&amp; [RCRouter canRespondToRoute:url.path]) {
        [RCRouter dispatch:url.path];
    } else {
//        [self openInternalBrowser:url];
    }
}

+ (BOOL)isInternalURL:(NSURL *)url {
    NSString * host = url.host;
    if(host &amp;&amp; [host hasPrefix:@"www"]) {
        host = [host substringFromIndex:3];
    }

    return (host &amp;&amp; [artsyHosts containsObject:host]);
}

#pragma mark -
#pragma mark Artworks

+ (void)loadAttachmentCollection:(AttachmentCollection *)collection {
    [[ARVoidViewController theVoid] loadArtworkViewWithAttachmentCollection:collection];
}

+ (void)loadArtwork:(Artwork *)artwork {
    AttachmentCollection * collection = [AttachmentCollection collectionWithItems:@[artwork] andIndex:0];
    [self loadAttachmentCollection:collection];
}

+ (void)loadArtworkFromURL:(NSDictionary *)options {
    [[ARVoidViewController theVoid] loadArtworkViewWithID:options[@"id"]];
}

@end
</code></pre>

<p>It shows the pattern's humble origins quite well. The <code>ARSwitchboard</code> provides an API that any object can call, and it will handle presenting the view controller. Offering an API that can either use arbitrary URLs or model objects.</p>

<h2>Where the pattern evolved</h2>

<p>I initially wrote this during my "Class methods look prettier" stage. Our <code>ARSwitchboard</code> has evolved into using instance methods, and it uses a sharedInstance. This makes writing tests for the routing extremely simple for <a href="https://github.com/artsy/energy/blob/master/ArtsyFolio%20Tests/Util/ARSwitchboardTests.m">easy use cases</a>, and possible <a href="https://github.com/artsy/eigen/blob/2eb00a8050a69ab2e05ffeb11a2bbdcbadf9fb7e/Artsy_Tests/App_Tests/ARSwitchBoardTests.m">for the complex</a>.</p>

<p>The pattern was established pretty well by the time it was integrated <a href="https://github.com/artsy/energy/blob/a35969d232d8309fd2aedaae35f2dbdf6d505004/Classes/Util/App/ARSwitchBoard.m">into Energy</a>. Some of it's highlights are:
- The sharedInstance is <a href="https://github.com/artsy/energy/blob/a35969d232d8309fd2aedaae35f2dbdf6d505004/Classes/Util/App/ARSwitchBoard.m#L20-L31">set up</a> with some of the other singletons, from that point on it only acts on properties it owns.
- It deals with setting up entire <a href="https://github.com/artsy/energy/blob/a35969d232d8309fd2aedaae35f2dbdf6d505004/Classes/Util/App/ARSwitchBoard.m#L229-L259">view hierarchies</a>. Not just pushing another view on to a <code>UINavigationController</code>.</p>

<h2>Internal Routing</h2>

<p>We try to make all view controllers that could represent a URL have two initializers; one that accepts a full model object and another that works off an ID. This means that we can provide as much context as we can initially, but can generate everything at runtime if you've come from a push notification or from another app.</p>

<p>We use an internal routing tool to do the heavy-lifting here, currently this is <a href="https://cocoapods.org/pods/JLRoutes">JLRoutes</a> which we use to map URLs to blocks and dictionaries.</p>

<h2>Difficulties</h2>

<p>With Eigen we're trying to map the whole data-set of Artsy into a single app, which likely an architecture post of it's own. However, one of the issues we're having that really strains this metaphor is ambiguity in the routing system. For us this crops up in two places:
- The URL <a href="https://github.com/artsy/eigen/pull/534">routing structure</a> you're mapping against can change.
- When one route could have <a href="https://github.com/artsy/eigen/blob/2eb00a8050a69ab2e05ffeb11a2bbdcbadf9fb7e/Artsy/App/ARSwitchBoard.m#L156">many types</a> of data.</p>

<p>Handling routes that changes is something we ended up building an <a href="https://github.com/artsy/echo/blob/master/app/api/v1/presenters/route_presenter.rb">API for</a>. It provides a JSON package of routes and names, and Eigen updates its routing internally.</p>

<p>Having one route represent multiple <em>potential</em> view controllers is tricky. We didn't want to introduce asynchronicity to the <code>ARSwitchboard</code>, so we use <a href="https://github.com/artsy/eigen/blob/2eb00a8050a69ab2e05ffeb11a2bbdcbadf9fb7e/Artsy/View_Controllers/Fair/ARProfileViewController.m#L55-L66">polymorphic view controllers</a>. This is a technique where the view controller returned then looks deeper into what it is representing and using child view controllers, embeds the true view controller inside itself.</p>

<h2>Future</h2>

<p>Like all patterns, our <code>ARSwitchboard</code> pattern is evolving. With Eigen we have  a complicated navigation stack, due to supporting app-wide tabs and hosting navigation controllers inside view controllers. This adds additional logic to pretty complicated code when we're dealing with URLs that could be root elements of a tab. So we are planning to eventually move the presentation aspect of the <code>ARSwitchboard</code> into a separate object.</p>

<h2>Alternatives</h2>

<p>We didn't need an <code>ARSwitchboard</code> in Eidolon. Which, so far always seems to be the exception in these architecture pattern posts. Instead we opted for Apple's <a href="http://www.objc.io/issues/15-testing/dependency-injection/#which-di-framework-should-i-use">Dependency Injection tool</a>, Interface Builder + Storyboards. Energy pre-dates Storyboards, and they didn't feel like a good fit for Eigen.</p>

<p>We found storyboards to be a really good replacement to this pattern when you have an established series of steps in your application with some well defined connections.</p>

<p>As an example, our on-boarding process for Eigen probably should have been storyboarded, as it's a series of view controllers pushed incrementally. However given that the rest of Eigen is essentially a web of interconnected view controllers, we'd be abusing the tool.</p>

<h2>Wrap up</h2>

<p>So the Switchboard is a way that we've managed to contain some of the complexity around having web-like abilities to jump between any two view controllers. This pattern makes it easy to stub a switchboard in tests, and to easily test the routing itself.</p>

<p>When I looked through some of the other open source iOS apps to compare the pattern, I couldn't find anything similar. So if you do have something similar, you should probably Open Source your app ;)</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Cocoa Architecture: ARRouter]]></title>
    <link href="http://artsy.net/blog/2015/08/15/Cocoa-Architecture:-Router-Pattern/"/>
    <updated>2015-08-15T00:00:00-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://artsy.net/blog/2015/08/15/Cocoa-Architecture:-Router-Pattern</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I want to talk about a pattern that we've been using for the last few years on the Artsy Mobile team. This pattern pre-dates me joining Artsy by a few weeks, and was introduced into our codebase by <a href="http://90wpm.com">Ben Jackson</a>, this was the <code>ARRouter</code>'s first method:</p>

<pre><code class="objc">  + (NSURL *)newOAuthURLWithUsername:(NSString *)username password:(NSString *)password {
      NSDictionary *params = [[NSDictionary alloc] initWithObjectsAndKeys:
                              username, @"email",
                              password, @"password",
                              ARAuthClientID, @"client_id",
                              ARAuthSecret, @"client_secret",
                              @"credentials", @"grant_type",
                              nil];
      NSString *url_string = [[NSString alloc] initWithFormat:@"%@%@", AROAuthURL, [params queryString]];
      NSURL *url = [ARRouter newURLWithPath:url_string];
      [url_string release];
      [params release];
      return url;
  }
</code></pre>

<p>Yep, that's pre-ARC, pre-Dictionary Literals, memory-managed code. We took this pattern and rolled with it for the next 4 years, this article is about where we've taken it.</p>

<p>Within Eigen, <code>ARRouter</code> is one of our <a href="https://github.com/artsy/eigen/blob/904e8abfc11ce6ea4b6e81f0e02684b755a280c3/Artsy/Networking/ARRouter.m">biggest classes</a>, coming in at almost 1,000 lines of code. Whereas in Energy, it sits at a <a href="https://github.com/artsy/energy/blob/e51529250ede359c781042f222d5836eb9e8a979/Classes/Util/App/ARRouter.m">more reasonable</a> 300 lines. Eidolon does not have an ARRouter, what gives?</p>

<!-- more -->


<hr />

<h2>Pattern Evolution</h2>

<p>We started out with a Router object as being something that can take a model object, and return a <code>NSURL</code> corresponding to a server side end-point.</p>

<p>This worked pretty well, we shipped a 1.0 of Energy with this pattern. However, it become obvious that we were putting a lot of extra knowledge about the type and the parameters of request into classes whose responsibility was not generating a route. For example, user account creation, and user account deletion would use the same <code>NSURL</code> but have different HTTP methods.</p>

<p>We migrated our networking stack to using AFNetworking <code>1.0</code>, and started using CocoaPods instead of manually dragging and dropping code. With this in mind, we improved on the pattern and started returning <code>NSURLRequest</code>s which better encapsulate the server end-point request we were trying to map in the Router.</p>

<p>The pattern evolved when mixed with a <a href="http://cocoadocs.org/docsets/AFNetworking/1.3.4/Classes/AFHTTPClient.html">AFHTTPClient</a> to act as the base URL resolver, allowing us to easily switch between staging and production environments, and as a central point for hosting all HTTP headers. This meant it was trivial to generate authenticated <code>NSURLRequest</code>s.</p>

<p>As it is presently, this pattern is working. We've just wrapped up a new Pod, <a href="https://github.com/artsy/Artsy_Authentication">Artsy Authentication</a>. It's a library that has an <code>ARRouter</code> that behaves <a href="https://github.com/artsy/Artsy_Authentication/blob/master/Pod/Classes/ArtsyAuthenticationRouter.h">exactly like above</a>. We continue to build new apps with the pattern.</p>

<h2>Siblings</h2>

<p>This pattern is standing the test of time, but that doesn't mean we're not actively trying to experiment within the domain. There are three interesting offshoots from our work on <code>ARRouter</code> that are worth talking about.</p>

<h4>Got the Routes like Swagger</h4>

<p>The difference between Eigen's <code>ARRouter</code> and Energy's <code>ARRouter</code> is pretty simple. Eigen's networking scope is an order of magnitude larger. This is a reflection on the varied data that Eigen is interested in, while Energy has a tight scope on specifically Artsy Parter related data.</p>

<p>During the new year of 2015, I explored the <a href="https://github.com/orta/GotTheRoutesLikeSwagger">idea of programmatically generating</a> an <code>ARRouter</code> as a CocoaPod, and then using CocoaPods' subspecs to make it easy to define what collections of end-points you were interested in. This project is based on a standard in which an API is documented, <a href="http://swagger.io">Swagger</a>. This meant as an API consumer, I can generate the types of <code>NSURLRequest</code>s I would require from the API itself. It created files that looked like:</p>

<pre><code class="objc">// Generated by Routes Like Swagger - 31/12/14

@interface ARRouter (User)

/// Retrieve a user by id.
/// @return URLRequest for /api/v1/user/{id}.{format}

- (NSURLRequest *)getUserWithID:(NSString * )slug;

/// Update an existing user.
/// @return URLRequest for /api/v1/user/{id}.{format}

- (NSURLRequest *)updateUserWithID:(NSString * )slug;

... [snip] ...

@end
</code></pre>

<p>This was a pretty nice expansion of the pattern, but overall felt a bit over-engineered and so, it was left as just an experiment.</p>

<h4>Moya</h4>

<p>When we started an entirely fresh application, we noted down all the networking-related pain points felt from Eigen and Energy. The Router pattern was pretty good, but we were finding that we were having problems with the API consuming part of the <code>NSURLRequest</code>s. Mainly, a difficulty in testing, an inconsistency in how we would perform networking and that it didn't feel declarative.</p>

<p>Moya is our attempt at fixing this. I won't go into depth on what Moya is, we've <a href="/blog/2014/09/22/transparent-prerequisite-network-requests/">written articles</a> on this already. The part that is interesting is that it obviates an ARRouter by using a collection of Swift enums - forcing developers to include all necessary metadata an an end-point.</p>

<h4>HAL, and API v2</h4>

<p>The Router pattern relies on the idea that you know all the routes ahead of time, and add support for them as you build out each part of the app. <a href="http://stateless.co/hal_specification.html">HAL, a Hypermedia Application Layer</a> - can be approximated as being a self describing API. dB. wrote about it in <a href="/blog/2014/09/12/designing-the-public-artsy-api/">this blog post</a>.</p>

<p>This means that you ask the API how to get certain bits of data, and it will describe the ways in which you can access it.</p>

<p>Artsy's future APIs are using this, and the Router pattern is, more or less, totally deprecated in this world. This is what an artwork's JSON data looks like in v2:</p>

<pre><code class="json">{
  "id": "4d8b92bb4eb68a1b2c00044a",
  "created_at": "2010-11-15T16:32:38+00:00",
  "updated_at": "2015-08-16T09:26:26+00:00",
  "name": "Jeff Koons",
  "sortable_name": "Koons Jeff",
  "gender": "male",
  "birthday": "1955",
  "hometown": "York, Pennsylvania",
  "location": "New York, New York",
  "nationality": "American",
  "_links": {
    "curies": [
      {
        "name": "image",
        "href": "https://d32dm0rphc51dk.cloudfront.net/Uqad2mGhbNGhAUgb8bUvIA/{rel}",
        "templated": true
      }
  ],
  "thumbnail": {
    "href": "https://d32dm0rphc51dk.cloudfront.net/Uqad2mGhbNGhAUgb8bUvIA/four_thirds.jpg"
  },
  "image:self": {
    "href": "{?image_version}.jpg",
    "templated": true
  },
  "self": {
    "href": "https://api.artsy.net/api/artists/4d8b92bb4eb68a1b2c00044a"
  },
  "permalink": {
    "href": "http://www.artsy.net/artist/jeff-koons"
  },
  "artworks": {
    "href": "https://api.artsy.net/api/artworks?artist_id=4d8b92bb4eb68a1b2c00044a"
  },
  "published_artworks": {
    "href": "https://api.artsy.net/api/artworks?artist_id=4d8b92bb4eb68a1b2c00044a&amp;published=true"
  },
  "similar_artists": {
    "href": "https://api.artsy.net/api/artists?similar_to_artist_id=4d8b92bb4eb68a1b2c00044a"
  },
  "similar_contemporary_artists": {
    "href": "https://api.artsy.net/api/artists?similar_to_artist_id=4d8b92bb4eb68a1b2c00044a&amp;similarity_type=contemporary"
  },
  "genes": {
    "href": "https://api.artsy.net/api/genes?artist_id=4d8b92bb4eb68a1b2c00044a"
  }
  },
  "image_versions": [
    "four_thirds",
    "large",
    "square",
    "tall"
  ]
}
</code></pre>

<p>You can see that via the _links section, curies and self-referential urls, you can build network client which traverses the API without built-in implicit knowledge.</p>

<p>It's a really exciting pattern, and as client developers, we can work on improving standard API clients that work on all HAL APIs. Instead of something specific to Artsy's API. A lot of the most interesting work in the Cocoa space has been done by Kyle Fuller with <a href="https://cocoapods.org/pods/Hyperdrive">Hyperdrive</a>.</p>

<h3>Wrap Up</h3>

<p>Given that we're not writing applications against the v2 API, yet. The Router pattern is working fine for us at Artsy. It can be a really nice way to abstract out a responsibility that may currently be sitting inside a very large API client that might be worth extracting out.</p>

<p>Let us know what you think, send tweets to <a href="https://twitter.com/ArtsyOpenSource">@ArtsyOpenSource</a> on twitter. Ps. it's pronounced "rooter".</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Open Sourcing Energy]]></title>
    <link href="http://artsy.net/blog/2015/08/06/open-sourcing-energy/"/>
    <updated>2015-08-06T13:54:00-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://artsy.net/blog/2015/08/06/open-sourcing-energy</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>The Artsy Mobile team is pretty aggressive in our stance on <a href="http://code.dblock.org/2015/02/09/becoming-open-source-by-default.html">Open Source by Default</a>. We've talked about it at <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=2DvDeEZ0NDw&amp;spfreload=10">conferences</a> <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=SjjvnrqDjpM">around</a> <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=zPbLYWmLPow">the</a> <a href="https://speakerdeck.com/orta/ios-at-artsy">world</a>, in <a href="http://www.objc.io/issues/22-scale/artsy">renowned magazines</a> and on <a href="http://artsy.github.io/blog/2015/04/28/how-we-open-sourced-eigen/">our blog</a>.</p>

<p>It's worth mentioning that we don't just talk externally about Open Source. Internally, the Mobile team runs talks about Open Source for the rest of the Artsy staff. As well, we discuss the tooling and business implications of having our work in public repos. Artsy strives for an open culture, in this case the development team, on the whole, is just further along in the process.</p>

<p>The Open Source app idea started with an experiment in the Summer of 2014, asking, "What does a truly Open Source App look like?" The outcome of that was our Swift Kiosk app, <a href="https://github.com/artsy/eidolon/">Eidolon</a>. Open from day one. We took the knowledge from that and applied it to our public facing app, <a href="https://github.com/artsy/eigen/">Eigen</a>. Open from day 806. That made 2/3rds of our apps Open Source.</p>

<p>I'm going to talk about our final app, <a href="https://github.com/artsy/energy">Energy</a>. Open from day 1433 and ~3500 commits.</p>

<!-- more -->


<hr />

<p><img src="/images/2015-08-01-open-sourcing-energy/ENERGY.png" alt="ENERGY" /></p>

<p>Energy is commonly known as <a href="http://folio.artsy.net">Artsy Folio</a>. It's a tool for Artsy's Partners to showcase their artworks on the go, and quickly email them. Here's a beautiful splash showing it in action.</p>

<p></div></div><a href='http://folio.artsy.net/images/cover-bbf6fdf4.jpg'><img src="http://folio.artsy.net/images/cover-bbf6fdf4.jpg" title="Folio overview" ></a><div class='meta-container'><header>&nbsp;</header></div><div class='date-container'>&nbsp;</div><div class='content-container'><div class='entry-content'></p>

<p>This app comes from the pre-CocoaPods, pre-ARC, pre-UICollectionView and pre-Auto Layout days. It spent 3 years with no tests, but has come up to over 50% code coverage in the last year. It's testing suite is super fast, given that we learned a lot with Eigen's tests we stuck with five main principals:</p>

<ul>
<li>No un-stubbed HTTP requests.</li>
<li>Avoid <code>will</code>s in a test as much as possible.</li>
<li>Never allow access to the main Core Data instance in tests</li>
<li>Dependency Inject anything</li>
<li>Use snapshots to test view controller states</li>
</ul>


<h3>On Opening Folio</h3>

<p>Folio is interesting in that it has competitors. To some extent the Kiosk app does too, but the cost of entry there is really high in comparison. Folio on the other hand, has a handful of competing businesses who exist to <em>only</em> build a Gallery/Museum/Collector portfolio app. In opening the code for Folio, we're not making it easy for people to copy and paste our business, it's very directly tied to Artsy's APIs and <a href="http://www.dylanfareed.com/projects/artsy-cms/">CMS</a>.</p>

<p>I commonly get questions about the process of Open Sourcing an app, so here's what happened after I decided it was time. First, I emailed my intent:</p>

<p></div></div><a href='/images/2015-08-01-open-sourcing-energy/oss-energy-email.png'><img src="/images/2015-08-01-open-sourcing-energy/oss-energy-email.png"></a><div class='meta-container'><header>&nbsp;</header></div><div class='date-container'>&nbsp;</div><div class='content-container'><div class='entry-content'></p>

<p>The concepts I wanted to cover were: "This is a codebase is worthy of art", "We know what we're doing", "This doesn't make it simple for someone to create a business off our product" and "I've managed to get a lot of the source out already." I gave a month or so to ensure that I could have corridor chats with people, in order to be very certain around opinions. We had some discussions in the email thread about ways in which an open source'd Energy would impact the team, and overall the reaction was positive. This wasn't surprising, the non-technical parts of the team are regularly kept up to date on thoughts like this.</p>

<p>After the internal announcement I started looking at the codebase, what should be cleaned up. I don't believe a codebase is ever perfect ( just look at Eigen's <a href="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/artsy/eigen/3f29f61f2b96f516e9ecf407818b82911b268694/HACKS.md">HACKS.md</a> ) but one thing I learned from the launch of Eigen is that we need a lot of beginner docs to help people get started. So I went into Energy's <a href="https://github.com/artsy/energy/tree/master/docs">docs</a> directory and started comparing it to <a href="https://github.com/artsy/eigen/tree/master/docs">Eigen</a>'s.</p>

<p>With the docs ready, we anticipated the repo change as we did <a href="/blog/2015/04/28/how-we-open-sourced-eigen/">with Eigen</a>. This means making sure all loose pull requests were wrapped up. All code comments were audited. Then we used <a href="https://github.com/google/github-issue-mover">github-issue-mover</a> to migrate important issues to the new repo. Then we deleted the <code>.git</code> folder in the app, and <code>git init</code> to create a new repo.</p>

<p>Given that we have three Open source apps now, I wanted to give them a consistent branding when we talk about the apps from the context of the codebase. It's like programming, if you're writing a similar thing 3 times, definitely time to refactor.</p>

<p></div></div><a href='/images/2015-08-01-open-sourcing-energy/oss-design-sketch.png'><img src="/images/2015-08-01-open-sourcing-energy/oss-design-sketch.png"></a><div class='meta-container'><header>&nbsp;</header></div><div class='date-container'>&nbsp;</div><div class='content-container'><div class='entry-content'></p>

<p>Finally, I started working on the announcement blog post. Which you're reading. I'll send a <a href="https://github.com/artsy/artsy.github.com/pull/119">pull request</a> for this blog post, then when it's merged. I'll make one more final look over how everything looks, then make the new Energy repo public.</p>

<h3>On more than just Opening Source</h3>

<p>Eigen, the public facing iOS app, allows people to log in with a trial user account. We also have a known API Key + Secret for the <a href="https://github.com/artsy/eigen/blob/master/Makefile#L41-L42">OSS app</a>. With this, any developer can run a few commands and have a working application to play around in. This makes it easy to look around and see how things are done.</p>

<p>Energy, however, requires you have a Artsy partner account. So opening it up would mean that an OSS developer hits the login screen and is stuck. In developing this app, I've slowly been creating my own partner gallery account based on my paintings and photography. So now when you set up the app to be ran as an OSS app, it will pre-load a known database of artworks and metadata from my test gallery.</p>

<p></div></div><a href='/images/2015-08-01-open-sourcing-energy/ios-sim.png'><img src="/images/2015-08-01-open-sourcing-energy/ios-sim.png"></a><div class='meta-container'><header>&nbsp;</header></div><div class='date-container'>&nbsp;</div><div class='content-container'><div class='entry-content'></p>

<p>Its easy to imagine that Open Sourcing something is an end-point, but from our perspective it is a journey. We want to make sure that anyone can download this app, learn how and why it's structured and then run through the app with a debugger to get a deeper sense of how everything connects. Just releasing the code would have been underwhelming. Instead we're aiming high.</p>

<p>I think that there is no higher compliment to your team and your code than opening it to the public.</p>

<p>You should Open Source your app.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
