<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: hal | Artsy Engineering]]></title>
  <link href="http://artsy.github.io/blog/categories/hal/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://artsy.github.io/"/>
  <updated>2018-12-16T10:16:31+00:00</updated>
  <id>http://artsy.github.io/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Cocoa Architecture: ARRouter]]></title>
    <link href="http://artsy.github.io/blog/2015/08/15/Cocoa-Architecture-Router-Pattern/"/>
    <updated>2015-08-15T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <id>http://artsy.github.io/blog/2015/08/15/Cocoa-Architecture-Router-Pattern</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I want to talk about a pattern that we've been using for the last few years on the Artsy Mobile team. This pattern pre-dates me joining Artsy by a few weeks, and was introduced into our codebase by <a href="http://90wpm.com">Ben Jackson</a>, this was the <code>ARRouter</code>'s first method:</p>

<pre><code class="objc">  + (NSURL *)newOAuthURLWithUsername:(NSString *)username password:(NSString *)password {
      NSDictionary *params = [[NSDictionary alloc] initWithObjectsAndKeys:
                              username, @"email",
                              password, @"password",
                              ARAuthClientID, @"client_id",
                              ARAuthSecret, @"client_secret",
                              @"credentials", @"grant_type",
                              nil];
      NSString *url_string = [[NSString alloc] initWithFormat:@"%@%@", AROAuthURL, [params queryString]];
      NSURL *url = [ARRouter newURLWithPath:url_string];
      [url_string release];
      [params release];
      return url;
  }
</code></pre>

<p>Yep, that's pre-ARC, pre-Dictionary Literals, memory-managed code. We took this pattern and rolled with it for the next 4 years, this article is about where we've taken it.</p>

<p>Within Eigen, <code>ARRouter</code> is one of our <a href="https://github.com/artsy/eigen/blob/904e8abfc11ce6ea4b6e81f0e02684b755a280c3/Artsy/Networking/ARRouter.m">biggest classes</a>, coming in at almost 1,000 lines of code. Whereas in Energy, it sits at a <a href="https://github.com/artsy/energy/blob/e51529250ede359c781042f222d5836eb9e8a979/Classes/Util/App/ARRouter.m">more reasonable</a> 300 lines. Eidolon does not have an ARRouter, what gives?</p>

<!-- more -->


<hr />

<a name="Pattern.Evolution"></a>
<h2>Pattern Evolution</h2>

<p>We started out with a Router object as being something that can take a model object, and return a <code>NSURL</code> corresponding to a server side end-point.</p>

<p>This worked pretty well, we shipped a 1.0 of Energy with this pattern. However, it become obvious that we were putting a lot of extra knowledge about the type and the parameters of request into classes whose responsibility was not generating a route. For example, user account creation, and user account deletion would use the same <code>NSURL</code> but have different HTTP methods.</p>

<p>We migrated our networking stack to using AFNetworking <code>1.0</code>, and started using CocoaPods instead of manually dragging and dropping code. With this in mind, we improved on the pattern and started returning <code>NSURLRequest</code>s which better encapsulate the server end-point request we were trying to map in the Router.</p>

<p>The pattern evolved when mixed with a <a href="http://cocoadocs.org/docsets/AFNetworking/1.3.4/Classes/AFHTTPClient.html">AFHTTPClient</a> to act as the base URL resolver, allowing us to easily switch between staging and production environments, and as a central point for hosting all HTTP headers. This meant it was trivial to generate authenticated <code>NSURLRequest</code>s.</p>

<p>As it is presently, this pattern is working. We've just wrapped up a new Pod, <a href="https://github.com/artsy/Artsy_Authentication">Artsy Authentication</a>. It's a library that has an <code>ARRouter</code> that behaves <a href="https://github.com/artsy/Artsy_Authentication/blob/master/Pod/Classes/ArtsyAuthenticationRouter.h">exactly like above</a>. We continue to build new apps with the pattern.</p>

<a name="Siblings"></a>
<h2>Siblings</h2>

<p>This pattern is standing the test of time, but that doesn't mean we're not actively trying to experiment within the domain. There are three interesting offshoots from our work on <code>ARRouter</code> that are worth talking about.</p>

<a name="Got.the.Routes.like.Swagger"></a>
<h4>Got the Routes like Swagger</h4>

<p>The difference between Eigen's <code>ARRouter</code> and Energy's <code>ARRouter</code> is pretty simple. Eigen's networking scope is an order of magnitude larger. This is a reflection on the varied data that Eigen is interested in, while Energy has a tight scope on specifically Artsy Parter related data.</p>

<p>During the new year of 2015, I explored the <a href="https://github.com/orta/GotTheRoutesLikeSwagger">idea of programmatically generating</a> an <code>ARRouter</code> as a CocoaPod, and then using CocoaPods' subspecs to make it easy to define what collections of end-points you were interested in. This project is based on a standard in which an API is documented, <a href="http://swagger.io">Swagger</a>. This meant as an API consumer, I can generate the types of <code>NSURLRequest</code>s I would require from the API itself. It created files that looked like:</p>

<pre><code class="objc">// Generated by Routes Like Swagger - 31/12/14

@interface ARRouter (User)

/// Retrieve a user by id.
/// @return URLRequest for /api/v1/user/{id}.{format}

- (NSURLRequest *)getUserWithID:(NSString * )slug;

/// Update an existing user.
/// @return URLRequest for /api/v1/user/{id}.{format}

- (NSURLRequest *)updateUserWithID:(NSString * )slug;

... [snip] ...

@end
</code></pre>

<p>This was a pretty nice expansion of the pattern, but overall felt a bit over-engineered and so, it was left as just an experiment.</p>

<a name="Moya"></a>
<h4>Moya</h4>

<p>When we started an entirely fresh application, we noted down all the networking-related pain points felt from Eigen and Energy. The Router pattern was pretty good, but we were finding that we were having problems with the API consuming part of the <code>NSURLRequest</code>s. Mainly, a difficulty in testing, an inconsistency in how we would perform networking and that it didn't feel declarative.</p>

<p>Moya is our attempt at fixing this. I won't go into depth on what Moya is, we've <a href="/blog/2014/09/22/transparent-prerequisite-network-requests/">written articles</a> on this already. The part that is interesting is that it obviates an ARRouter by using a collection of Swift enums - forcing developers to include all necessary metadata an an end-point.</p>

<a name="HAL..and.API.v2"></a>
<h4>HAL, and API v2</h4>

<p>The Router pattern relies on the idea that you know all the routes ahead of time, and add support for them as you build out each part of the app. <a href="http://stateless.co/hal_specification.html">HAL, a Hypermedia Application Layer</a> - can be approximated as being a self describing API. dB. wrote about it in <a href="/blog/2014/09/12/designing-the-public-artsy-api/">this blog post</a>.</p>

<p>This means that you ask the API how to get certain bits of data, and it will describe the ways in which you can access it.</p>

<p>Artsy's future APIs are using this, and the Router pattern is, more or less, totally deprecated in this world. This is what an artwork's JSON data looks like in v2:</p>

<pre><code class="json">{
  "id": "4d8b92bb4eb68a1b2c00044a",
  "created_at": "2010-11-15T16:32:38+00:00",
  "updated_at": "2015-08-16T09:26:26+00:00",
  "name": "Jeff Koons",
  "sortable_name": "Koons Jeff",
  "gender": "male",
  "birthday": "1955",
  "hometown": "York, Pennsylvania",
  "location": "New York, New York",
  "nationality": "American",
  "_links": {
    "curies": [
      {
        "name": "image",
        "href": "https://d32dm0rphc51dk.cloudfront.net/Uqad2mGhbNGhAUgb8bUvIA/{rel}",
        "templated": true
      }
  ],
  "thumbnail": {
    "href": "https://d32dm0rphc51dk.cloudfront.net/Uqad2mGhbNGhAUgb8bUvIA/four_thirds.jpg"
  },
  "image:self": {
    "href": "{?image_version}.jpg",
    "templated": true
  },
  "self": {
    "href": "https://api.artsy.net/api/artists/4d8b92bb4eb68a1b2c00044a"
  },
  "permalink": {
    "href": "http://www.artsy.net/artist/jeff-koons"
  },
  "artworks": {
    "href": "https://api.artsy.net/api/artworks?artist_id=4d8b92bb4eb68a1b2c00044a"
  },
  "published_artworks": {
    "href": "https://api.artsy.net/api/artworks?artist_id=4d8b92bb4eb68a1b2c00044a&amp;published=true"
  },
  "similar_artists": {
    "href": "https://api.artsy.net/api/artists?similar_to_artist_id=4d8b92bb4eb68a1b2c00044a"
  },
  "similar_contemporary_artists": {
    "href": "https://api.artsy.net/api/artists?similar_to_artist_id=4d8b92bb4eb68a1b2c00044a&amp;similarity_type=contemporary"
  },
  "genes": {
    "href": "https://api.artsy.net/api/genes?artist_id=4d8b92bb4eb68a1b2c00044a"
  }
  },
  "image_versions": [
    "four_thirds",
    "large",
    "square",
    "tall"
  ]
}
</code></pre>

<p>You can see that via the _links section, curies and self-referential urls, you can build network client which traverses the API without built-in implicit knowledge.</p>

<p>It's a really exciting pattern, and as client developers, we can work on improving standard API clients that work on all HAL APIs. Instead of something specific to Artsy's API. A lot of the most interesting work in the Cocoa space has been done by Kyle Fuller with <a href="https://cocoapods.org/pods/Hyperdrive">Hyperdrive</a>.</p>

<a name="Wrap.Up"></a>
<h3>Wrap Up</h3>

<p>Given that we're not writing applications against the v2 API, yet. The Router pattern is working fine for us at Artsy. It can be a really nice way to abstract out a responsibility that may currently be sitting inside a very large API client that might be worth extracting out.</p>

<p>Let us know what you think, send tweets to <a href="https://twitter.com/ArtsyOpenSource">@ArtsyOpenSource</a> on twitter. Ps. it's pronounced "rooter".</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
