<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: culture | Artsy Engineering]]></title>
  <link href="http://artsy.github.io/blog/categories/culture/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://artsy.github.io/"/>
  <updated>2018-03-21T23:17:05+00:00</updated>
  <id>http://artsy.github.io/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[C4Q&A: 2]]></title>
    <link href="http://artsy.github.io/blog/2018/01/10/C4Q-QandA-two/"/>
    <updated>2018-01-10T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <id>http://artsy.github.io/blog/2018/01/10/C4Q-QandA-two</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><a href="https://www.c4q.nyc">C4Q is</a> C4Q is a non-for-profit hacker school based in NYC. We've had members of the Artsy team help out by being TAs, running committees and steering the curriculum as Engineers in the industry for many years. In 2017, C4Q reached out to arrange a meetup between Artsy engineers and students who were learning Android and Web development. This year we ran a panel for the other half of the C4Q students who study iOS and Web.</p>

<p>We got an entirely new set of panelists to cover similar topics as <a href="/blog/2017/10/10/C4Q-QandA/">last time</a> - so if you're wondering
what it's like in the industry, and what makes an Artsy engineer. The video is after the link.</p>

<!-- more -->




<center>
<iframe width='100%' height='600' src='https://www.youtube.com/embed/pp0vNokDzaQ' frameborder='0' allowfullscreen></iframe>
</center>


<p>Our twitter links in sitting order: <a href="https://twitter.com/realmrblock">@realmrblock</a>, <a href="https://twitter.com/sweir27">@sweir27</a>, <a href="https://twitter.com/yuki24">@yuki24</a>, <a href="https://twitter.com/cychi1210">@cychi1210</a>, <a href="https://twitter.com/orta">@orta</a>, <a href="https://twitter.com/acjay1">@acjay1</a> let us know if you have any more questions.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[C4Q&A]]></title>
    <link href="http://artsy.github.io/blog/2017/10/10/C4Q-QandA/"/>
    <updated>2017-10-10T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <id>http://artsy.github.io/blog/2017/10/10/C4Q-QandA</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><a href="https://www.c4q.nyc">C4Q is</a> is a non-for-profit hacker school based in NYC. We've had members of the Artsy team help
out by being TAs, running committees and steering the curriculum as Engineers in the industry for many years. C4Q recently
reached out to arrange a meetup between Artsy engineers and students who are learning Android and Web development.</p>

<p>We thought it would be cool to have a talk from dB, our CTO, on what Artsy is and to also host a Q&amp;A panel with our
engineers. For a lot of the students it was their first time meeting a team of engineers, so we anticipated a lot of
question time.</p>

<p>In prepration for the event, I reached out to the internet for ideas on what sort of questions juniors would be interested
in hearing about, and people said they were also interested in hearing what we ended up being asked, and what our answers
were. This post has the youtube video of the opening talk, and our panel's Q &amp; A session.</p>

<p>It was really awesome to talk about how far we've grown as individuals, and what is important in our engineering lives.</p>

<!-- more -->




<center>
<iframe width='100%' height='600' src='https://www.youtube.com/embed/leiKlKXRvuk' frameborder='0' allowfullscreen></iframe>
</center>


<p>Our twitter links:  <a href="https://twitter.com/orta">@orta</a>, <a href="https://twitter.com/craigspaeth">@craigspaeth</a>, <a href="https://twitter.com/kana_abe">@kana_abe</a>, <a href="https://twitter.com/dblockdotorg">@dblockdotorg</a>, <a href="https://twitter.com/xtina_starr">@Xtina_Starr</a> let us know if
you have any more questions.</p>

<p>If you want more, there's also <a href="/blog/2018/01/10/C4Q-QandA-two/">part 2 with different engineers</a>.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[What it Feels Like to Work in a Supportive Environment for Female Engineers]]></title>
    <link href="http://artsy.github.io/blog/2017/09/29/supportive-environment-for-female-engineers/"/>
    <updated>2017-09-29T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <id>http://artsy.github.io/blog/2017/09/29/supportive-environment-for-female-engineers</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>With the often overwhelming and downright discouraging reality that the tech industry isn’t a diverse and inclusive environment, I felt compelled to share what a productive, empathetic, and nurturing environment for female and female-identifying engineers looks like.</p>

<p>I have just shipped a post over on the Life at Artsy blog about how: Our culture of empathy, our hiring process and our company values provide a competitive advantage. This all contributes to ensuring that all engineers regardless of gender feel valued.</p>

<p><a href="https://medium.com/artsy-blog/what-it-feels-like-to-work-in-a-supportive-environment-for-female-engineers-3c994a001007">Read on at the Life at Artsy Blog →</a></p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[DevSwap: An Experiment in Randomizing Teams]]></title>
    <link href="http://artsy.github.io/blog/2017/09/11/DevSwap/"/>
    <updated>2017-09-11T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <id>http://artsy.github.io/blog/2017/09/11/DevSwap</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>A few weeks ago, every engineer at Artsy went to work for a different team for two full days. We called it DevSwap. In this post, I'll go over why and how we did it.</p>

<!-- more -->


<p>If you’ve read about Artsy's <a href="http://artsy.github.io/blog/2016/03/28/artsy-engineering-organization-stack/">Engineering Team</a> before, you might know that we organize ourselves into product teams that serve different parts of our business. Today, Artsy employs 26 engineers, spread across four product teams — Publishing, Auctions, Collector GMV, and Partner Success. We also have a Platform team that is responsible for systems, infrastructure, and data, among other things. Across these teams, we share systems and apps. To stay cohesive with one another, we also have what we call “practices,” which are cross-team groups that meet and discuss shared tech.</p>

<p>Around two years ago, we didn't have product teams. Back then, most engineers worked in a variety of stacks. As our business models changed, so did the way we organized ourselves. Interestingly, the number of engineers has not changed drastically, but the way we work has. We have greater focus now that we are organized into product teams with specific business goals, but that means there aren't as many opportunities to work in other stacks.</p>

<p>Earlier this summer, the engineering leads received some feedback from our engineers about wanting more cross-team collaboration and knowledge sharing. In our weekly engineering-wide meeting, we get to hear what features each team is working on, but it can sometimes feel like there's missing context. Within our practices, there is a better sense of the details, but usually the work itself is deeply nested in another team.</p>

<p>We brainstormed several ideas related to knowledge sharing and cross-team collaboration. What stood out the most was that being in product teams meant fewer opportunities to work in other parts of the business. This led to the question: What would happen if we redistributed ourselves into entirely new teams?</p>

<a name="Setup"></a>
<h2>Setup</h2>

<p>Over the course of a few weeks, the engineer leads devised a plan for DevSwap. Here are some questions we asked ourselves:</p>

<ul>
<li>How can we become closer as a team while learning something new?</li>
<li>How can we keep ourselves as engineers nimble, flexible, and full-stack?</li>
<li>How can we reduce risk in our systems by spreading knowledge?</li>
<li>How can we have fun before summer is over?</li>
</ul>


<p>For the first iteration, we decided to spend two full business days swapping. Every engineer  worked with a different team. Each team contained the same number of people as the original team. The leads of each team stayed to onboard, provide support and facilitate work.</p>

<p>The Monday before DevSwap, we had an engineering-wide meeting to go over some guidelines and pick teams. Here are the guidelines we shared:</p>

<ul>
<li>DevSwap will last 2 days. 🕑</li>
<li>Product managers have been notified so don't worry about your regular work. Hopefully a new member will pick some up for you 😄.</li>
<li>If possible, try and sit by your new team and if not, coordinate meeting times with remote members. 📞</li>
<li>See this as a pairing opportunity! 👫</li>
<li>In terms of work, it's business as usual. Your new lead will give you guidance. 💼</li>
</ul>


<p>In this meeting, we also had our leads "pitch" their teams. The goal of this was to get people excited about joining new teams and to get a sense of what projects they might work on. To choose the actual teams, each engineer picked their top three choices and we drew names out of a bucket. If their first choice was already full, we would place them in their next available choice. The following Monday and Tuesday, we were all writing code for different teams.</p>

<a name="So.what.happened."></a>
<h2>So what happened?</h2>

<p>Our EU engineers kicked off DevSwap on Monday, tackling both the struggle of learning new stacks and being remote (our headquarters is located in NYC). Leads mitigated the latter problem by prepping EU folks on Friday so they had some direction come Monday morning.</p>

<p>There was lots of Slack-ing, Screenhero-ing, and pairing. It was wonderful to see people interact in a new environment with new goals, even if it was temporary. Some got to learn about <em>how</em> teams operate and learned about issue prioritization and even attended meetings with stakeholders.</p>

<p>Some people worked on modernizing codebases with projects like <a href="https://github.com/artsy/positron/pull/1225">server-side hot file swapping</a> and the introduction of a GraphQL endpoint to our consignments app. Others worked on building features like <a href="https://github.com/artsy/aprb/pull/104/files">setting up Slack notifications</a> when we receive customer feedback and adding ElasticSearch indexing to projects. We learned new languages <a href="https://github.com/artsy/eigen/pull/2412">by building features</a> and updated <a href="https://github.com/artsy/metaphysics/pull/702">many</a> <a href="https://github.com/artsy/positron/pull/1235">docs</a>.</p>

<p>All work aside, the fact that we were having conversations with each other about the details of the technology while gaining a fresh perspective of someone else's experience was valuable.</p>

<a name="Feedback.from.Engineers"></a>
<h2>Feedback from Engineers</h2>

<p>I learned a lot and had fun, but I wondered what everyone else thought. At the end of the second day, I sent out a survey to all 26 engineers and received 14 responses. Here are some of those results:</p>

<p>Did you get a chance to collaborate with someone you don't normally work with?</p>

<iframe width="600" height="371" seamless frameborder="0" scrolling="no" src="https://docs.google.com/spreadsheets/d/e/2PACX-1vQoAQpvGiq2-5EJWz__vS0n4Iw9r3rY_eSEaPqKQzUlPnObnono-RFS4qLSjrmGTqGnbMOoQsA1L9WX/pubchart?oid=942845256&amp;format=interactive"></iframe>


<p><br>
Did you gain a better understanding of a piece of Artsy Engineering you don't normally interact with?</p>

<iframe width="600" height="371" seamless frameborder="0" scrolling="no" src="https://docs.google.com/spreadsheets/d/e/2PACX-1vQoAQpvGiq2-5EJWz__vS0n4Iw9r3rY_eSEaPqKQzUlPnObnono-RFS4qLSjrmGTqGnbMOoQsA1L9WX/pubchart?oid=543941925&amp;format=interactive"></iframe>


<p><br>
If we were to swap again in 6 months, how long should it last?</p>

<iframe width="600" height="371" seamless frameborder="0" scrolling="no" src="https://docs.google.com/spreadsheets/d/e/2PACX-1vQoAQpvGiq2-5EJWz__vS0n4Iw9r3rY_eSEaPqKQzUlPnObnono-RFS4qLSjrmGTqGnbMOoQsA1L9WX/pubchart?oid=1071239654&amp;format=interactive"></iframe>


<p><br>
<br></p>

<blockquote><p>"Would make the swap slightly longer -- was a short timeframe to get through a project."</p>

<p>"Onboarding took up most of the time. It was hard to get anything beyond that done."</p></blockquote>

<p>One clear piece of feedback was the desire to spend more time on an assigned team. Some engineers had trouble onboarding, setting up projects, and accomplishing meaningful work within the two days. If engineers can't spin up a dev environment within a day, what does that mean for usability? These are solvable problems — we could think about dockerizing apps or having better READMEs. During the session, some folks went back to their old teams to help new members with problems. While this was great, it meant less time for their own learning. One option is to extend the duration of the swap. But by extending it too long, it could remove the hackathon mentality that kept people highly focused. It seems like a combination of tweaking the duration, providing better initial setup, and clearly communicating expectations might help for next time.</p>

<p>We also requested feedback on the leads. Responding to a multiple choice question about what their newly assigned lead did best, most engineers chose "Assisted me when I got stuck" and "Checked in with me frequently." The least chosen answers were "Taught me something new" and "Made the work enjoyable." It's possible that taking more time to prepare for new teams (i.e. introduction meetings, dev environment setup workshop) could provide more opportunities for deeper learning.</p>

<p>When we asked if there were any good takeaways that could be applied to your own team, we had some interesting answers.</p>

<blockquote><p>"Partner Success does a 'show &amp; tell' where you just casually mention something you learned, dev/tech related. That was fun. We should do that on [Collector Experience]."</p>

<p>"Finally got to play with Redux in a production app, which I'd be very happy to see implemented in <a href="https://github.com/artsy/positron">Positron</a>."</p>

<p>"I've been thinking a lot about GraphQL and what it could mean to the [Partner Success] team. Also thinking about what it means for Kinetic and how our projects talk to Gravity."</p></blockquote>

<p>Finally, what did people like most?</p>

<blockquote><p>"Working with people that I normally don't get a chance to work with on daily basis and also working on the areas of our systems. The fact that now each engineer knows how to setup and run another part of our system by itself is a huge win."</p>

<p>"The tight time period forces projects to be very granular. It also forces repo set-up time to be minimized (e.g., via setup/bootstrap scripts, docker, etc.)."</p>

<p>"I liked feeling like I was able to figure out a codebase that was completely new to me and add value even in the short time that we had to work with. It made me feel like something intimidating was actually within my reach and that made me feel smart. :)"</p>

<p>"I wasn't sure if we should expect to get much accomplished but was pleasantly surprised to ship a small but useful feature."</p>

<p>"Awesome idea, it feels great to be part of the team that takes risks like this to increase teamwork and knowledge share among engineers and give engineers chance to get out of their comfort zone."</p></blockquote>

<p>Despite a few issues with onboarding and timing, it seems that most people found DevSwap to be valuable. This feedback gives us a lot to consider when planning the next one. We hope to bring it back soon!</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Introducing Peril to the Artsy Org]]></title>
    <link href="http://artsy.github.io/blog/2017/09/04/Introducing-Peril/"/>
    <updated>2017-09-04T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <id>http://artsy.github.io/blog/2017/09/04/Introducing-Peril</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Once Danger Ruby was stable enough for everyday use in 2015, it became obvious that running Danger on CI was both a
positive and a negative. On the positive side, Danger has access to all artifacts created during testing - and on the negative
side it takes a long time to get feedback. It was obvious that Danger could <a href="https://github.com/danger/danger/issues/42">run on a server</a>, but it was a big unknown what that could look like.</p>

<p>Eventually, <a href="/blog/2017/06/30/danger-one-oh-again/">I came to the conclusion</a> that we would need a JavaScript replacement of Danger - and so I applied
constraints to Danger JS that made a server-side version of Danger a possibility. It was a stroke of luck that around the
time Danger JS became usable for day to day usage, that GitHub introduced <a href="https://developer.github.com/changes/2016-09-14-Integrations-Early-Access/">GitHub Apps</a> - so I started work on Peril. Peril is server-side Danger. The rest of this post talks about how we use it Artsy today, how you can use it yourself and where it's heading.</p>

<!-- more -->


<p>In December 2016, I built out Peril in a sandbox org: <a href="https://github.com/PerilTest">PerilTest</a>, this gave me the chance to get a lot of things wrong safely. My biggest worry around Peril was leaking data though someone abusing the ability to evaluate a Dangerfile.</p>

<p>In May 2017, I introduced Peril into Artsy's org, GitHub apps have the ability to pick and choose which repos to work with.
I scoped the repos to existing open source projects which I was familiar with (<a href="https://github.com/artsy/emission">Emission</a>, <a href="https://github.com/artsy/reaction">Reaction</a> and <a href="https://github.com/artsy/positron">Positron</a>)
which gave a space to ensure stability and handle production edge-cases.</p>

<p>In August 2017, I created a new Peril instance for CocoaPods. I then finally flipped the switch to turn Peril on for all
repos on the Artsy org and formalized the RFC process for changes. This is where we are now.</p>

<a name="Getting.Set.Up"></a>
<h2>Getting Set Up</h2>

<p>For our Artsy org, I followed and improved the guide: <a href="https://github.com/danger/peril/blob/master/docs/setup_for_org.md">Setup for Org</a>. There are three key components:</p>

<ul>
<li>Creating a GitHub app for your Org</li>
<li>Hosting a Peril server</li>
<li>Making up a Peril settings repo</li>
</ul>


<p>The guide covers the initial setup, but I'd like to cover the third part of our setup.</p>

<a name="How.Artsy.s.Peril.works"></a>
<h2>How Artsy's Peril works</h2>

<p>The Artsy Peril settings are all on <a href="https://github.com/artsy/artsy-danger">artsy/artsy-danger</a>. The Artsy Peril heroku instance has the ENV var
<code>"DATABASE_JSON_FILE"</code> set to <code>"artsy/artsy-danger@peril.settings.json"</code>, so Peril will use <a href="https://github.com/artsy/artsy-danger/blob/master/peril.settings.json">that file</a> as the source of truth for all config. Here's what it is today:</p>

<p></article>
<article class='split-desktop-only'></p>

<div style='flex:1; display: block;'>

```json
{
  "settings": {
    "modules": [
      "danger-plugin-spellcheck", 
      "danger-plugin-yarn", 
      "@slack/client"
    ],
    "env_vars": ["SLACK_RFC_WEBHOOK_URL"]
  },
  "rules": {
    "pull_request": "artsy/artsy-danger@org/all-prs.ts"
  },
  "repos" : {
    "artsy/reaction": {
      "pull_request": "danger/pr.ts"
    },
    "artsy/positron": {
      "pull_request": "dangerfile.ts"
    },
    "artsy/artsy-danger": {
      "issues.opened": "artsy/artsy-danger@danger/new_rfc.ts"
    }
  }
}
```

</div>


<div style='flex:1; display: block; padding:0 20px;'>

<p><code>"settings":</code> These settings which conform to today's <a href='https://github.com/danger/peril/blob/752afeb37e3c1fdec512eb91687747d9a8a29337/source/db/index.ts#L26-L31'>GitHubInstallationSettings</a>, here's the <a href='https://github.com/danger/peril/blob/master/source/db/index.ts'>current version</a>. These are org-wide settings
that require a new deploy of the server to re-create.</p>

<p><code>"rules":</code> These are rules which are applied to every repo that Peril has access to. So in this case, every Pull Request in the org will make Peril run the Dangerfile at <code>"artsy/artsy-danger@org/all-prs.ts"</code>.</p>

<p><code>"repos":</code> These are repo-specific overrides, so a Pull Request to artsy/reaction would trigger both the org-wide Dangerfile, and one on the reaction repo.</p>

</div>


<p></article>
<article class='post'></p>

<a name="Events"></a>
<h2>Events</h2>

<p>A Dangerfile evaluation occurs once a GitHub webhook is sent. In the above examples there are two events that Danger supports:
<code>"pull_request"</code> and <code>"issues.opened"</code>. These are qualifiers that GitHub provide as a <a href="https://developer.github.com/v3/activity/events/types/events">Webhook EventTypes</a>.</p>

<p>There's a lot of them: <code>commit_comment</code>, <code>create</code>, <code>delete</code>, <code>deployment</code>, <code>deployment_status</code>, <code>fork</code>, <code>gollum</code>, <code>installation</code>, <code>installation_repositories</code>, <code>issue_comment</code>, <code>issues</code>, <code>label</code>, <code>marketplace_purchase</code>, <code>member</code>, <code>membership</code>, <code>milestone</code>, <code>organization</code>, <code>org_block</code>, <code>page_build</code>, <code>project_card</code>, <code>project_column</code>, <code>project</code>, <code>public</code>, <code>pull_request</code>, <code>pull_request_review</code>, <code>pull_request_review_comment</code>, <code>push</code>, <code>release</code>, <code>repository</code>, <code>status</code>, <code>team</code>, <code>team_add</code>, <code>watch</code>.</p>

<p>Some of these events also have unique sub-actions too:</p>

<ul>
<li><p>For an <code>issue</code> event there is: <code>assigned</code>, <code>unassigned</code>, <code>labeled</code>, <code>unlabeled</code>, <code>opened</code>, <code>edited</code>,  <code>milestoned</code>, <code>demilestoned</code>, <code>closed</code>, or <code>reopened</code></p></li>
<li><p>For a <code>pull_request</code> event there is: <code>assigned</code>, <code>unassigned</code>, <code>review_requested</code>, <code>review_request_removed</code>, <code>labeled</code>, <code>unlabeled</code>, <code>opened</code>, <code>edited</code>, <code>closed</code>, or <code>reopened</code></p></li>
</ul>


<p>The way that you define rules in Peril gives you the ability to either focus on one action for an event type: <code>"issues.opened"</code> or all actions
on an event: <code>"pull_request"</code>. Once you get your head around this, you start to get a sense of the scope of Peril. At Artsy, we've barely scratched the surface.</p>

<a name="Growth"></a>
<h3>Growth</h3>

<p>I've always advocated that Danger, and Peril should be <a href="http://danger.systems/js/usage/culture.html">applied incrementally</a>. This applies even more when you're
making org changes that affect every developer - at least with Danger you can see the Pull Request that changes
the Dangerfile. With Peril you get none of that.</p>

<p>So, we introduced <a href="https://github.com/artsy/artsy-danger/#rfcs">an RFC process for Peril changes</a>. There's not much to it, if you want to add a rule that
affects everyone then you need to make an issue following a template and then wait a week. If you make a new issue that
includes the title <code>RFC:</code> then Peril sends a slack message to our developer Channel</p>

<p><img src="/images/peril/peril-rfc.png" alt="/images/peril/peril-rfc.png" /></p>

<p>This was simple to build via Peril, I first added the npm module: <code>"@slack/client"</code> to the <code>"modules"</code> array, making it available to a Dangerfile. Then I added an environment variable to Peril for a newly minted Slack Incoming Webhook URL, and exposed it to Dangerfiles via: <code>"env_vars": ["SLACK_RFC_WEBHOOK_URL"]</code>.</p>

<p>Then I added a per-repo rule:</p>

<pre><code class="json">    "artsy/artsy-danger": {
      "issues.opened": "artsy/artsy-danger@danger/new_rfc.ts"
    }
</code></pre>

<p>This means the Dangerfile is only ran on <code>"issues"</code> with an <code>"opened"</code> action. I didn't want the discussion around a rule spamming our slack with webhooks from the other actions. The file <code>danger/new_rfc.ts</code> looks like this:</p>

<pre><code class="ts">import { schedule, danger } from "danger"
import { IncomingWebhook } from "@slack/client"
import { Issues } from "github-webhook-event-types"

declare const peril: any // danger/danger#351

const gh = danger.github as any as Issues
const issue = gh.issue

if (issue.title.includes("RFC:")) {
  var url = peril.env.SLACK_RFC_WEBHOOK_URL || "";
  var webhook = new IncomingWebhook(url)
  schedule( async () =&gt; {
   await webhook.send({
      unfurl_links: false,
      attachments: [{
        pretext: "🎉 A new Peril RFC has been published.",
        color: "good",
        title: issue.title,
        title_link: issue.html_url,
        author_name: issue.user.login,
        author_icon: issue.user.avatar_url
      }]
    })
  })
}
</code></pre>

<p>For events that are not a <code>"pull_request"</code> the <code>danger.github</code> object is the JSON for the event.  You can get TypeScript types available for every GitHub event via the NPM module <a href="https://www.npmjs.com/package/github-webhook-event-types">github-webhook-event-types</a> which makes it much easier to work with.</p>

<a name="Where.to.go.from.here."></a>
<h2>Where to go from here?</h2>

<p>Right now we have <a href="https://github.com/artsy/artsy-danger/issues?utf8=%E2%9C%93&amp;q=is%3Aissue%20RFC">a few RFCs</a>, and I don't spend all day making Peril rules, I've gotta <a href="https://github.com/artsy/emission/pulls?utf8=%E2%9C%93&amp;q=consignments%20">do work y'know</a>. We're going to slowly build out our Peril infrastructure.</p>

<p>I'm interested in exploring two ideas big for peril at the moment:</p>

<ul>
<li><p>What a Peril plugin system looks like: You can include modules which can listen to events and react themselves. An org-wide spellcheck on markdown files could be as easy as including <code>"modules": ["peril-plugin-spellcheck"]</code>.</p></li>
<li><p>What <a href="https://github.com/danger/peril/issues/138">scheduled jobs</a> could look like for Peril: We have a bunch of checks I'd like to make on a a regular occasion, and then passing back feedback via slack or making an issue on the repo.</p></li>
</ul>


<p> For example if a repo has an owner who isn't in Artsy anymore, we should highlight that it needs a new owner.</p>

<p>If you're interested in using Peril in large OSS projects, take a look at how Peril is used in CocoaPods via <a href="https://github.com/CocoaPods/peril-settings">CocoaPods/peril-settings</a>.</p>

<p>If you're interested in using Peril in your org, run through the <a href="https://github.com/danger/peril/blob/master/docs/setup_for_org.md">Setup for Org</a> guide and help improve it when you inevitably have some weird issues.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
