<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: design | Artsy Engineering]]></title>
  <link href="http://artsy.github.io/blog/categories/design/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://artsy.github.io/"/>
  <updated>2018-12-16T10:16:31+00:00</updated>
  <id>http://artsy.github.io/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Where art thou, my error?]]></title>
    <link href="http://artsy.github.io/blog/2018/10/19/where-art-thou-my-error/"/>
    <updated>2018-10-19T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <id>http://artsy.github.io/blog/2018/10/19/where-art-thou-my-error</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><em>Note: This is the text of a presentation given at <a href="https://graphql-finland.fi">GraphQL Finland 2018</a>, as such the
language may in some cases be slightly awkward for a blog post. You can find those slides on
<a href="https://speakerdeck.com/alloy/where-art-thou-my-error">Speaker Deck</a>.</em></p>

<p>GraphQL is still in its early stages and thus these are very exciting times, indeed! Traditionally the GraphQL team
has taken the approach of defining the bare minimum in the specification that was deemed needed and otherwise
letting the community come-up with defining problems and experimenting with solutions for those. One such example
is how metadata about the location in the graph where errors occurred during execution were <a href="https://github.com/facebook/graphql/pull/230">added to the
specification</a>.</p>

<p>This is great in the sense that we still have the ability, as a community, to shape the future of a GraphQL
specification that we all <em>want</em> to use, but on the other hand it also means that we may need to spend significant
amounts of time on thinking about these problems and iterating. Seeing as we all strive to have backwards
compatible schemas, it’s of great importance that we know of the various iterations that people have experimented
with and what the outcome was.</p>

<p>This is our story of thinking about and working with errors, thus far.</p>

<!-- more -->


<p>NOTE: Throughout this talk I’ll use ‘query execution’ to indicate executing a GraphQL document, be it a query or
mutation operation. I have a hard time relating to ‘document execution’, mostly because I don’t see others using
it, but perhaps I’ve just missed it. Come at me, at the bar, and set me straight!</p>

<a name="Errors.vs.errors"></a>
<h2>Errors vs errors</h2>

<p>First of all, I want to take a step back and talk about errors in general. The nomenclature around these can get
confusing, suffice to say that during this session we’ll talk about these two types:</p>

<ul>
<li><p>Errors that occur during query execution, that were unexpected, and <em>could</em> lead to corrupted data. We’ll refer
to these as (top-level) ‘GraphQL errors’, going forward.</p>

<p>These could be due to hardware failures, such as running out of memory or disk space, network failures, or
unexpected upstream data etc.</p>

<p>When these occur, <code>graphql-js</code> will return <code>null</code> for the field that triggered the error and serialize the error
into the top-level <code>errors</code> list, next to the successful response <code>data</code>. (Presumably other implementations
follow this reference implementation.)</p></li>
</ul>


<pre><code class="json">{
  "data": {
    "artwork": {
      "artist": {
        "name": "Vincent van Gogh",
        "leftEarSize": null
      }
    }
  },
  "errors": [
    {
      "message": "An unexpected error occurred",
      "path": ["artwork", "artist", "leftEarSize"]
    }
  ]
}
</code></pre>

<ul>
<li><p>Exceptions to these are errors that are <em>known</em> to occur and are expected to be handled by the user of an API.
We’ll refer to these as ‘exceptions’, going forward.</p>

<p>By default these are treated equally by <code>graphql-js</code> to top-level GraphQL errors, if uncaught.</p></li>
</ul>


<p>We will <strong>not</strong> be speaking about errors that occur <em>outside</em> of query execution, such as network failures reaching
the GraphQL server, parsing a syntactically incorrect document, or passing variables that don’t satisfy the
type-system; as these will all lead to a query being rejected wholesale and are solve-able using traditional means,
such as a <code>4xx</code> HTTP status code or <code>5xx</code> in some cases.</p>

<a name="What.is.the.problem.we...re.trying.to.solve."></a>
<h2>What is the problem we’re trying to solve?</h2>

<p>Because with GraphQL we’re usually requesting data for multiple resources, there may be a situation where some
fields resolve successfully and some may fail. This is also why, when using an HTTP transport layer, the advice is
to always respond with a HTTP 200 (ok) status. Determining how to process the response is left up to the client.</p>

<p>So how <em>do</em> we model errors in such a way that they can be meaningful and in context of their origin?</p>

<ul>
<li><p>What if you want to render partial data?</p>

<ul>
<li><p>Maybe the failed data is unrelated to other components that you were also requesting data for.</p>

<p><img src="/images/2018-10-19-where-art-thou-my-error/partial-data-unrelated-annotated.png" alt="Unrelated component" /></p></li>
<li><p>Or the data that failed was part of a list and other entries can still be rendered just fine.</p>

<p><img src="/images/2018-10-19-where-art-thou-my-error/partial-data-list-annotated.png" alt="Partial list data" /></p></li>
</ul>
</li>
<li><p>Or what if you’d (additionally) like to communicate the error in your interface?</p>

<ul>
<li><p>When the query is in response to a mutation and you’d like to communicate input validation failures.</p>

<p><img src="/images/2018-10-19-where-art-thou-my-error/mutation-validation-error.png" alt="Surface validation error" /></p></li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>


<a name="Possible.solutions"></a>
<h2>Possible solutions</h2>

<a name="Top-level.GraphQL.errors.and.treating.an.entire.response.as.unusable.when.such.errors.exist"></a>
<h3>Top-level GraphQL errors and treating an entire response as unusable when such errors exist</h3>

<p>Some clients, such as Apollo and Relay Classic, have made the decision to reject a response entirely, by default,
if any top-level GraphQL errors exist. This is because clients can really only fully assume that the response data
is incomplete, not whether or not your application could handle that case.</p>

<p>This may be an ok solution when you’re starting out or all the requested data is part of a single holistic view,
but it quickly breaks down when you want a little more than that.</p>

<a name="Top-level.GraphQL.errors.with.extra.metadata"></a>
<h3>Top-level GraphQL errors with extra metadata</h3>

<p>GraphQL errors only have a single field in <a href="https://facebook.github.io/graphql/draft/#sec-Errors">the specification</a> to provide context around the cause of
the error, which is the <code>message</code> field. However, <a href="https://facebook.github.io/graphql/draft/#sec-Response-Format">the specification</a> also defines a top-level
<code>extensions</code> key, which may hold a map of freeform data for the schema implementors to extend the protocol however
they see fit.</p>

<p>Apollo Server 2.0, for instance, <a href="https://blog.apollographql.com/full-stack-error-handling-with-graphql-apollo-5c12da407210">introduced standardized errors</a> you can throw from your
resolvers, which end up being serialized into the <code>extensions</code> map. An example they give is for bad user input:</p>

<pre><code class="js">import { UserInputError } from "apollo-server"

const resolvers = {
  Query: {
    events(root, { zipCode }) {
      // do custom validation for user inputs
      const validationErrors = {}
      if (!isValidZipCode(zipCode)) {
        validationErrors.zipCode = "This is not a valid zipcode"
      }
      if (Object.keys(validationErrors).length &gt; 0) {
        throw new UserInputError("Failed to get events due to validation errors", { validationErrors })
      }
      // actually query events here and return successfully
      return getEventsByZipcode(zipCode)
    }
  }
}
</code></pre>

<p>Seeing as these extensions are freeform, however, this builds an <strong>implicit</strong> contract between the server and
client that then needs to be abstracted away by additional client code. This is unfortunate, when you think about
it, because GraphQL is meant to explicitly express shapes of data.</p>

<p>The Apollo team acknowledges this by adding:</p>

<blockquote><p>While convenient, the weakness of this approach is that the format of the validation error messages is not
captured by your schema, making it brittle to changes. Unless you maintain tight control of both server and
client, you should keep the error responses as simple as possible.</p>

<p>For mutations, it can be worthwhile defining these validation errors as first class citizens within your schema.</p></blockquote>

<p>(Which we’ll address next.)</p>

<a name="Make..mutation..error.metadata.part.of.schema.as.separate.fields"></a>
<h3>Make (mutation) error metadata part of schema as separate fields</h3>

<p>One <a href="https://www.apollographql.com/docs/guides/schema-design.html#mutation-responses">commonly suggested approach</a> around mutations is to define status metadata on the
response type next to the field of the affected entity. For example, a response type could look like:</p>

<pre><code>type UpdateArtworkMutationResponse {
  success: Boolean!
  message: String!
  artwork: Artwork
}
</code></pre>

<p>Here there’s a boolean that indicates success, an extra message that sheds context on the situation when a failure
occurs, and finally the <code>artwork</code> that an update was attempted to be made to.</p>

<p>Adding these fields to the same namespace makes sense when we’re thinking of the failure case, but what about the
success case? Do we really need a <code>success</code> boolean to indicate that updates to the <code>artwork</code> were made? What
purpose serves the <code>message</code> field, other than possibly being a sign of an overly positive schema that sends you
happy messages?</p>

<p>Finally, this approach only really works for mutations, as their return type acts as a distinct root type to start
a query from. It would be hard to imagine how to apply this to queries.</p>

<a name="Make.error.metadata.part.of.schema.as.separate.field"></a>
<h3>Make error metadata part of schema as separate field</h3>

<p>Similarly, <a href="https://itnext.io/the-definitive-guide-to-handling-graphql-errors-e0c58b52b5e1">another suggested approach</a> is to add an additional <code>error</code> field to the type in
question, which then describes the error that occurred. The previous example could be rewritten like so:</p>

<pre><code>type GenericError {
  message: String!
}

type UpdateArtworkMutationResponse {
  error: GenericError
  artwork: Artwork
}
</code></pre>

<p>If <code>error</code> is not <code>null</code>, something went wrong. This cleans up the namespace a bit, but more importantly this
approach can be applied to queries too:</p>

<pre><code>type PublishedArtworkNotification {
  artwork: Artwork
}

type PublishedArtworkNotificationsPayload {
  error: GenericError
  notifications: [PublishedArtworkNotification]
}

type Query {
  publishedArtworkNotificationsPayload: PublishedArtworkNotificationsPayload!
}
</code></pre>

<p>Neat.</p>

<p>However, and this may just be our use-case, we don’t have partial data at these stages. We’ve either resolved the
data or we have an error. Hence, this approach would mean we’d always have an unneeded <code>null</code> field, which pollutes
the namespace of the type unnecessarily.</p>

<p>Side-note: if you don’t control the server schema, and are using a client that can extend a server schema on the
client, you could try to retrofit top-level GraphQL errors to these suggested error fields into the schema where
they occurred based on the error <code>path</code>, as shown <a href="https://github.com/facebook/relay/issues/1913#issuecomment-358636018">here</a>.</p>

<a name="Recap"></a>
<h2>Recap</h2>

<p>So to quickly recap, ideally we want a solution to:</p>

<ul>
<li>Use GraphQL: Utilize GraphQL to explicitly describe the error data.</li>
<li>In context: Present the error data exactly where the error occurred in the schema.</li>
<li>All operations: Work for both mutations and queries.</li>
<li>Explicit status: Be concise and encourage ‘clean’ types; that is, no pollution of namespaces with fields only
needed in some cases.</li>
</ul>


<a name="Make.exceptions.first-class.citizens.of.your.schema"></a>
<h3>Make exceptions first-class citizens of your schema</h3>

<p>To that end, the final approach we’ll be discussing, and the one that we at Artsy have started adopting, is to give
exceptions their own type and return those instead of the success type, when they occur. To do this we make use of
a union of both the success and the exception type (or multiples thereof) and then query for those.</p>

<p>The benefits are:</p>

<ul>
<li><p>You can further model the exception in an explicit and introspect-able way.</p>

<p>For example, in the case of an HTTP failure to an upstream service, your exception type could include an integer
status-code field and document it as such.</p></li>
</ul>


<pre><code>type Artwork {
  title: String!
}

type HTTPError {
  message: String!
  statusCode: Int!
}

union ArtworkOrError = Artwork | HTTPError

type Query {
  artworkOrError(id: ID!): ArtworkOrError
}
</code></pre>

<pre><code>query {
  artworkOrError("mona-lisa") {
    ... on Artwork {
      title
    }
    ... on HTTPError {
      statusCode
    }
  }
}
</code></pre>

<ul>
<li>You know exactly where the exception occurred in the graph.</li>
</ul>


<pre><code>type Artist {
  artworksOrErrors: [ArtworkOrError]
}

type Query {
  artist(id: ID!): Artist
}
</code></pre>

<pre><code>query {
  artist("leonardo-da-vinci") {
    artworksOrErrors {
      ... on Artwork {
        title
      }
      ... on HTTPError {
        statusCode
      }
    }
  }
}
</code></pre>

<ul>
<li>You can use it for both mutations and queries.</li>
</ul>


<pre><code>type UpdateArtworkMutationResponse {
  artworkOrError: ArtworkOrError
}
</code></pre>

<ul>
<li>All fields will always be captured in the single <code>artworkOrError</code> field <em>or</em>, if no information about the error
is needed, you simply don’t query for it and get back <code>null</code> instead.</li>
</ul>


<pre><code>query {
  artworkOrError("mona-lisa") {
    ... on Artwork {
      title
    }
  }
}
</code></pre>

<a name="How.we.encode.it.into.our.schema"></a>
<h2>How we encode it into our schema</h2>

<p>I should preface this by clearly stating that while have been thinking about this problem for a while now, only
recently have we started rolling these changes out into our schema, so some of these are not yet discoverable in
<a href="http://github.com/artsy/metaphysics">our open-source GraphQL service</a>.</p>

<a name="Types"></a>
<h3>Types</h3>

<p>As shown before, we define a union of the actual result type <em>and</em> the error type. However, we additionally (will)
define a set of error interfaces, which make it possible for clients to query for errors in a more generic way.</p>

<pre><code>interface Error {
  message: String!
}

interface HTTPError {
  message: String!
  statusCode: Int!
}

type HTTPErrorType implements Error &amp; HTTPError {
  message: String!
  statusCode: Int!
}

type Artwork {
  title: String!
}

union ArtworkOrError = Artwork | HTTPErrorType

type Query {
  artworkOrError(id: ID!): ArtworkOrError
}
</code></pre>

<p>We can now still query as shown in the earlier examples:</p>

<pre><code>query {
  artworkOrError("mona-lisa") {
    ... on Artwork {
      title
    }
    ... on HTTPError {
      message
      statusCode
    }
  }
}
</code></pre>

<p>…but we can now also have generic error components that would query like so:</p>

<pre><code>query {
  artworkOrError("mona-lisa") {
    ... on Artwork {
      title
    }
    ...GenericErrorComponent
    ...GenericHTTPErrorComponent
  }
}

fragment GenericErrorComponent on Error {
  message
}

fragment GenericHTTPErrorComponent on HTTPError {
  message
  statusCode
}
</code></pre>

<p>For the record, we have <em>not</em> yet put these interfaces into production, so the nomenclature is not set in stone yet
and I’d love to hear your input on this. Is <code>Error</code> <em>too</em> generic to use as the base error type? Is there a nicer
naming pattern that would allow us to avoid having to suffix concrete types of an error interface with <code>...Type</code>?</p>

<p>Side-note: there’s <a href="https://github.com/facebook/graphql/pull/373">an RFC</a> to the GraphQL specification that would make it possible to
have interfaces implement other interfaces, thus removing the need to keep repeating the fields of
super-interfaces. This RFC has recently been moved to the draft stage, yay!</p>

<a name="Field.naming"></a>
<h3>Field naming</h3>

<p>As you may have noticed, we’re calling these fields <code>something</code> <em>or</em> <code>error</code>. We are mostly doing this to stay
backwards compatible with our existing schema. While we could certainly add exception types to existing union
fields, we can’t change a single type field into a union type field without breaking compatibility.</p>

<p>Instead we may now have 2 versions of a given field:</p>

<ul>
<li>one with the single type field which is nullable, in case an exception occurred</li>
</ul>


<pre><code>query {
  artwork("mona-lisa") {
    title
  }
}
</code></pre>

<ul>
<li>and another that has the error union type</li>
</ul>


<pre><code>query {
  artworkOrError("mona-lisa") {
    ... on Artwork {
      title
    }
    ... on HTTPError {
      statusCode
    }
  }
}
</code></pre>

<p>This duplication is slightly unfortunate, from a clean schema design perspective, but it’s similar to an existing
pattern in the community. For instance, many schemas provide 2 ways to retrieve lists:</p>

<ul>
<li>one as an immediate list:</li>
</ul>


<pre><code>type Query {
  artworks: [Artwork]
}
</code></pre>

<ul>
<li>and one as a ‘connection’ (as defined by the <a href="https://facebook.github.io/relay/graphql/connections.htm">Relay Connection specification</a>)</li>
</ul>


<pre><code>type ArtworkEdge {
  node: Artwork
}

type ArtworksConnection {
  edges: [ArtworkEdge]
}

type Query {
  artworksConnection: ArtworksConnection
}
</code></pre>

<p>So the jury is still out on whether or not that’s a bad way to name things. We’ll have to see after using this for a
while.</p>

<a name="Downside.of.using.a.union"></a>
<h3>Downside of using a union</h3>

<p>One notable downside is that GraphQL scalar types can <em>not</em> be included in unions. Thus, if you have scalar fields
that could lead to exceptions, you will have to ‘box’ those in object types.</p>

<pre><code>type ArtworkPurchasableBox {
  value: Boolean!
}

union ArtworkPurchasableOrError = ArtworkPurchasableBox | HTTPError

type Artwork {
  currentlyPurchasableOrError: ArtworkPurchasableOrError
}
</code></pre>

<p>This is definitely a case where the pattern of defining 2 fields, one with and one without exception types, comes
in handy. Having to always query through the box type is inelegant, to put it softly.</p>

<p>Side-note: there actually is <a href="https://github.com/facebook/graphql/issues/215">an open RFC</a> to the specification to allow scalars in unions, but
it’s still in stage 0 and is in need of a champion in order to proceed. We may end up trying to do so, based on our
actual experiences with these cases where they may need to be boxed.</p>

<a name="Example.of.how.we.consume.query.errors"></a>
<h3>Example of how we consume query errors</h3>

<pre><code class="ts">import { OrderStatus_order } from "__generated__/OrderStatus_order.graphql"
import React from "react"
import { createFragmentContainer, graphql } from "react-relay"

interface Props {
  order: OrderStatus_order
}

const OrderStatus: React.SFC&lt;Props&gt; = ({ order: orderStatusOrError }) =&gt;
  orderStatusOrError.__typename === "OrderStatus" ? (
    &lt;div&gt;
      {orderStatusOrError.deliveryDispatched
        ? "Your order has been dispatched."
        : "Your order has not been dispatched yet."}
    &lt;/div&gt;
  ) : (
    &lt;div className="error"&gt;
      {orderStatusOrError.code === "unpublished"
        ? "Please contact gallery services."
        : `An unexpected error occurred: ${orderStatusOrError.message}`}
    &lt;/div&gt;
  )

export const OrderStatusContainer = createFragmentContainer(
  OrderStatus,
  graphql`
    fragment OrderStatus_order on Order {
      orderStatusOrError {
        __typename
        ... on OrderStatus {
          deliveryDispatched
        }
        ... on OrderError {
          message
          code
        }
      }
    }
  `
)
</code></pre>

<a name="Example.of.how.we.consume.mutation.errors"></a>
<h3>Example of how we consume mutation errors</h3>

<pre><code class="ts">import { SubmitOrder_order } from "__generated__/SubmitOrder_order.graphql"
import { SubmitOrderMutation } from "__generated__/SubmitOrderMutation.graphql"
import { Router } from "found-relay"
import React from "react"
import { commitMutation, createFragmentContainer, graphql, RelayProp } from "react-relay"

interface Props {
  order: SubmitOrder_order
  relay: RelayProp
  router: Router
}

const SubmitOrder: React.SFC&lt;Props&gt; = props =&gt; (
  &lt;button
    onClick={() =&gt; {
      commitMutation&lt;SubmitOrderMutation&gt;(props.relay.environment, {
        mutation: graphql`
          mutation SubmitOrderMutation($input: SubmitOrder!) {
            submitOrder(input: $input) {
              orderStatusOrError {
                __typename
                ... on OrderStatus {
                  submitted
                }
                ... on OrderError {
                  message
                  code
                }
              }
            }
          }
        `,
        variables: { input: { orderID: props.order.id } },
        onCompleted: ({ submitOrder: { orderStatusOrError } }, errors) =&gt; {
          if (orderStatusOrError.__typename === "OrderStatus") {
            props.router.push(
              `/orders/${props.order.id}/${orderStatusOrError.submitted ? "submitted" : "pending"}`
            )
          } else {
            alert(
              orderStatusOrError.code === "unpublished"
                ? "Please contact gallery services."
                : `An unexpected error occurred: ${orderStatusOrError.message}`
            )
          }
        }
      })
    }}
  /&gt;
)

export const SubmitOrderContainer = createFragmentContainer(
  SubmitOrder,
  graphql`
    fragment SubmitOrder_order on Order {
      id
    }
  `
)
</code></pre>

<!--

### Show example of factory code that produces both single and union typed fields

TODO

-->


<a name="Final.thoughts"></a>
<h2>Final thoughts</h2>

<p>As stated before, we having only recently begun rolling out these changes into our production schema. However, much
thought and experimentation has gone into this to ensure we will be able to address all of <em>our</em> needs, at least.</p>

<p>I would love to hear other people’s thoughts on this and definitely feedback if they try to adopt it themselves. As
a community we should openly iterate together, as much as possible, as we try to make the future of GraphQL a great
one and put legit questions to ‘REST’ ;)</p>

<p>For now, I’ll leave you with this message from some internet ‘rando’:</p>

<blockquote><p>@alloy That diff makes a lot of sense to me. I've also seen user errors as a field on the mutation result, but I
like that union makes it explicit that there was either success or failure and in the case of failure provides
rich information that's in your app's domain.</p></blockquote>

<p>-- <a href="https://twitter.com/leeb/status/1020054709694943232">Lee Byron</a></p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[CSS Trick: Adjusting Text Underlines]]></title>
    <link href="http://artsy.github.io/blog/2012/04/10/css-trick-adjusting-text-underlines/"/>
    <updated>2012-04-10T16:32:00+00:00</updated>
    <id>http://artsy.github.io/blog/2012/04/10/css-trick-adjusting-text-underlines</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Often times people will use <em>border-bottom: 1px solid</em> in favor of <em>text-decoration: underline</em> to give their links some breathing room. But what if you're giving it <em>too</em> much breathing room and want to adjust the height of that underline. With Adobe Garamond that happened to be the case, so we've come up with this little css trick:</p>

<pre><code class="css">a {
  display: inline-block;
  position: relative;
}
a::after {
  content: '';
  position: absolute;
  left: 0;
  display: inline-block;
  height: 1em;
  width: 100%;
  border-bottom: 1px solid;
  margin-top: 5px;
}
</code></pre>

<p>This overlays a CSS pseudo element with a border-bottom that can be adjusted by changing margin-top.</p>

<p>For handling browsers that don't support pseudo elements I recommend targeting them with the <a href="http://paulirish.com/2008/conditional-stylesheets-vs-css-hacks-answer-neither/">Paul Irish class-on-html-trick</a>.</p>

<p>Let your links breathe!</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Responsive Layouts with CSS3]]></title>
    <link href="http://artsy.github.io/blog/2012/01/17/responsive-layouts-with-css3/"/>
    <updated>2012-01-17T11:03:00+00:00</updated>
    <id>http://artsy.github.io/blog/2012/01/17/responsive-layouts-with-css3</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>All of the <a href="http://sass-lang.com/">SCSS</a> stylesheets used to design this blog compile down to one file (view the source of this page and check out screen.css), and there isn't any JavaScript affecting the layout. But there are really three versions of this page. If you're reading this on a smartphone, what you see is almost entirely different from what you would see if you were reading this in a full screen browser. If you're on a computer, try making this page full screen and slowly resize it to make it smaller. You'll first notice that the Artsy logo disappears just before it would cover the text in the main column. Keep reducing the viewport and eventually the page will snap into a mobile format with the Artsy logo centered at the top, followed by the centered header text and mobile search box all above the index of recent posts.</p>

<a name="The.Philosophy"></a>
<h2>The Philosophy</h2>

<p>Why bother? It's true that smartphone web browsers are pretty advanced and certainly can handle rendering the full version of this blog. But there's a big difference between ensuring a site works and creating a good experience for your audience regardless of the device they're using. If anything, advances in the mobile web make responsive layouts like the one on this blog even more necessary — as it becomes more and more likely that your users are viewing your site on a handheld screen, it becomes less acceptable to force your audience to zoom way into your page and follow the text with their thumbs.</p>

<p>The key to a good mobile design is to fix at least one axis — it's fine if the user has to scroll down or to the right to see the rest of the content, but making the user scroll diagonally means that the layout doesn't fit the screen. For text-heavy sites like this blog, it's best to just allow vertical scrolling. Aside from this consideration, links, text fields, and buttons must be large enough to allow for easy navigation with thumbs. The font size may need to be adjusted to optimize viewing on a mobile screen. On a Mac, you can use mobile Safari on the iPhone Simulator that comes with <a href="http://developer.apple.com/xcode/">Xcode</a> to see how your site will look on a phone.</p>

<a name="Media.Queries"></a>
<h2>Media Queries</h2>

<p>The good news is that these responsive layouts aren't difficult to implement. When I set out to theme this <a href="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</a> blog, our designer gave me two comps, one for the full version of the site and the other for the mobile version. The first step towards a responsive layout is to notice common elements between the two designs. If you compare the two versions of the blog, you'll notice that they contain essentially the same content. This means that we need only one template file for both designs, and definitely do not need to resort to creating a whole mobile subdomain to serve different content to small screens. For elements that aren't the same in the two designs, we can simply hide them by setting <code>display: none</code> for devices where the elements shouldn't be shown. I used this technique in a couple of places on the blog: the right sidebar is hidden on the mobile version, while the mobile search bar (which differs from the search bar on the side in that it has placeholder text and appears in the main content <code>div</code>) isn't displayed on the full version of the site.</p>

<p>But how do you apply different styles to the same elements depending on the size of the browser's viewport? There are a couple of ways, but by far the cleanest way is to use CSS3 media queries. Media queries allow developers to apply different styles to elements on a page depending on the media on which they are displayed, whether that medium is a screen, a projection, print, braille, etc. The most common use of media queries, however, is to create responsive layouts. Media queries come after an <code>@media</code> declaration. Directly after comes the definition of the media type: we're concerned with creating responsive layouts for screens, and as a result, we'll declare our styles under <code>@media screen</code>. To apply custom styles based on the size of the screen, we'll use media features, which come after the keyword <code>and</code> and are enclosed in parentheses. Here's the SCSS code used to style the Artsy logo on this blog:</p>

<pre><code class="scss">    #lrg-mark {
        background-image: url("../images/Logo.png");
        background-repeat: no-repeat;
        display: block;
        height: 92px;
        width: 249px;

        span {
          display: none;
        }

        @media screen and (min-width: 482px) {
          left: 35px;
          position: fixed;
          top: 15px;
        }
        @media screen and (max-width: 1280px) and (min-width: 482px) {
          display: none;
        }
        @media screen and (max-width: 481px) {
          margin: 0 auto 20px auto;
          background-position: center top;
        }
    }
</code></pre>

<p>The styles that are common to all viewports are written outside of <code>@media</code> declarations at the top of the styles for <code>#lrg-mark</code> — regardless of the screen size, we want the logo to be the same image and the same size, and we don't want to display the span inside of the div that contains fallback text. The rest of the styles are given in media queries: for a large viewport, we want the logo fixed in the upper right corner, for slightly smaller viewports, we want it to disappear, and for mobile viewports, we want it centered on the screen. Note that 481px is a magic number: it's the width of an iPhone in landscape mode.</p>

<p>The media features <code>max-width</code> and <code>min-width</code> are a little misleading: they don't mean the maximum or minimum possible width of the user's screen. It's best to think of <code>max-</code> as "less-than-or-equal-to" and <code>min-</code> as "greater-than-or-equal-to." See <a href="http://www.w3.org/TR/css3-mediaqueries/">the W3C's website</a> for a complete reference on CSS media queries.</p>

<a name="Making.It.Cross-Browser"></a>
<h2>Making It Cross-Browser</h2>

<p>CSS3 media queries are awesome, but even though all the latest versions of the major browsers support them, it's very likely that a portion of your site's visitors will be using browsers that don't support these new CSS features. Luckily, this problem has already been solved by great people who like to give away things for free. Just include <a href="https://github.com/Modernizr/Modernizr">modernizr.js</a> on your page, and it will provide a JavaScript fallback for media queries, as well as for many other potentially unsupported CSS3 features.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
