<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: video | Artsy Engineering]]></title>
  <link href="http://artsy.github.io/blog/categories/video/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://artsy.github.io/"/>
  <updated>2016-08-22T17:27:27+00:00</updated>
  <id>http://artsy.github.io/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Learn Swift at Artsy, Beginners Lesson One]]></title>
    <link href="http://artsy.github.io/blog/2016/08/15/swift-at-artsy-beginners-lesson-one/"/>
    <updated>2016-08-15T21:18:00+00:00</updated>
    <id>http://artsy.github.io/blog/2016/08/15/swift-at-artsy-beginners-lesson-one</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Last August, Orta and I <a href="http://artsy.github.io/blog/2016/01/26/swift-at-artsy/">led a course at Artsy</a> to teach our colleagues Swift. There were two parallel groups of learners: a "beginners" group who had never coded before, and an "informed" group who already knew how to code. This year, we're leading the course again with a slight twist: we're repeating the course for absolute beginners, and we're introduce a new course for anyone who completed last year's beginner course.</p>

<p>We're really excited both to help new colleagues take their first steps into programming, and to help returning colleagues continue their journey.</p>

<p>Today was lesson one of the beginner group, and I have a <a href="https://youtu.be/OLdSg0XpFqA">screen recording</a> of my walkthrough of <a href="https://github.com/artsy/Swift-at-Artsy/tree/master/Beginners/Lesson%20One">lesson one's material</a>.</p>

<!-- more -->


<p></div></div><iframe width='100%' height='600' src='https://www.youtube.com/embed/OLdSg0XpFqA ' frameborder='0' allowfullscreen></iframe><div class='meta-container'><header>&nbsp;</header></div><div class='content-container'><div class='entry-content'></p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Dev Interviews: Craig Spaeth]]></title>
    <link href="http://artsy.github.io/blog/2016/08/09/Dev-Interview-Craig-Spaeth/"/>
    <updated>2016-08-09T12:11:00+00:00</updated>
    <id>http://artsy.github.io/blog/2016/08/09/Dev-Interview-Craig-Spaeth</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Hello everyone! Orta here, over the summer I've started a series of interviews with the entire development team at Artsy. They're all on different topics, notably around technical and cultural issues. I've recorded a few of them already, and will be sporadically releasing them. I'm still getting the hang of editing and recording side of this, so give me some slack.</p>

<p>Anyway, I'm pumped to introduce the first in the series - <a href="http://craigspaeth.com/">Craig Spaeth</a>.</p>

<p>Craig has been at Artsy for 6 years, moving from the first on-site developer to Director of Web. Our interview covered how Artsy's development team has adapted over time to the changing demands of a growing company. When he joined, Artsy was 6 people, we're now at ~145 people, ~20 developers and 3 businesses.</p>

<p>Jump <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=-0WK1Ebis3M">to YouTube</a> for the video, or click more for a inline video.</p>

<!-- more -->


<p></div></div><iframe width='100%' height='600' src='https://www.youtube.com/embed/-0WK1Ebis3M ' frameborder='0' allowfullscreen></iframe><div class='meta-container'><header>&nbsp;</header></div><div class='content-container'><div class='entry-content'></p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Code Injection for Xcode]]></title>
    <link href="http://artsy.github.io/blog/2016/03/05/iOS-Code-Injection/"/>
    <updated>2016-03-05T12:09:00+00:00</updated>
    <id>http://artsy.github.io/blog/2016/03/05/iOS-Code-Injection</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I have been writing code for roughly a decade. A large chunk of that time has been sitting waiting for my project to compile. It's a nice excuse to <a href="https://xkcd.com/303/">practice sword fighting</a> in the office, but really, deep down. It's frustrating. It's so easy to become <a href="https://xkcd.com/356/">nerd-sniped</a> when you wait for a long time.</p>

<p>As we integrate Swift into our projects, I've been seeing our compile times increase. So, I took some time to look at ways to improve this. The best option, so far, has been dynamic code injection via <a href="https://github.com/johnno1962/injectionforxcode">Injection Plugin for Xcode</a>. In a gist: This means that we don't recompile and re-launch, instead we inject new bits of code into a running application. This reduced the compile cycle on Eigen from 7 seconds to 1 second.</p>

<p>I took some time over the weekend to try and put together a video showing how I used code injection on a trivial app to create a view controller in code. It covers the technique I've <a href="https://github.com/artsy/eigen/pull/1236">started using in Eigen</a> and talks a little bit about how the pieces come together.</p>

<p>Jump <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=uftvtmyZ8TM">to YouTube</a> for the video, or click more for a smaller inline preview.</p>

<!-- more -->


<p></div></div><iframe width='100%' height='600' src='https://www.youtube.com/embed/uftvtmyZ8TM ' frameborder='0' allowfullscreen></iframe><div class='meta-container'><header>&nbsp;</header></div><div class='content-container'><div class='entry-content'></p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Code Review: Energy Sync]]></title>
    <link href="http://artsy.github.io/blog/2016/02/12/Code-Review-Energy-Sync/"/>
    <updated>2016-02-12T12:09:00+00:00</updated>
    <id>http://artsy.github.io/blog/2016/02/12/Code-Review-Energy-Sync</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>We are slowly trying to do high-level code-review views for all of our iOS apps. So far, we've covered <a href="/blog/2016/01/14/eidolon-code-review/">Eidolon</a> and <a href="/blog/2015/11/05/Emergence-Code-Review/">Emergence</a> and now <a href="/blog/2016/02/11/Code-Review-Energy/">Energy</a>. This is the second part of the Energy code review. The <a href="/blog/2016/02/11/Code-Review-Energy/">first part</a> covers the the critical codepaths that go from the App's launch to sending an email, which is the main use-case for the app. This video covers how Folio does sync between the Artsy API and the app.</p>

<p>Sync is a complex problem. This video covers our old techniques, how we changed them, the underlying abstractions we use now and how we can test each component individually. It's an hour long, and it's a little computer-sciencey. So I think people who have shipped some small apps would get a lot out of it.</p>

<p>Jump <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=05HaKChPe_g">to YouTube</a> for the video, or click more for a smaller inline preview.</p>

<!-- more -->


<p></div></div><iframe width='100%' height='600' src='https://www.youtube.com/embed/05HaKChPe_g ' frameborder='0' allowfullscreen></iframe><div class='meta-container'><header>&nbsp;</header></div><div class='content-container'><div class='entry-content'></p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Code Review: Energy overview]]></title>
    <link href="http://artsy.github.io/blog/2016/02/11/Code-Review-Energy/"/>
    <updated>2016-02-11T11:09:00+00:00</updated>
    <id>http://artsy.github.io/blog/2016/02/11/Code-Review-Energy</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>We are slowly trying to do high-level code-review views for all of our iOS apps. So far, we've covered <a href="/blog/2016/01/14/eidolon-code-review/">Eidolon</a> and <a href="/blog/2015/11/05/Emergence-Code-Review/">Emergence</a>. Folio is an app that's shipped to the App Store in early 2012, it's used by our Partners to showcase their works offline, at fairs and on the go. If you want the full spiel, check out <a href="http://folio.artsy.net">this microsite</a>.</p>

<p>This video talks through a lot of the critical codepaths that go from the App's launch to sending an email, which is the main use-case for the app. We have another video coming up which exclusively covers how Folio does sync between the Artsy API and the app.</p>

<p>Jump <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=Xhd25hFzN4o">to YouTube</a> for the video, or click more for a smaller inline preview.</p>

<!-- more -->


<p></div></div><iframe width='100%' height='600' src='https://www.youtube.com/embed/Xhd25hFzN4o ' frameborder='0' allowfullscreen></iframe><div class='meta-container'><header>&nbsp;</header></div><div class='content-container'><div class='entry-content'></p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
