<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: emission | Artsy Engineering]]></title>
  <link href="http://artsy.github.io/blog/categories/emission/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://artsy.github.io/"/>
  <updated>2018-12-16T10:16:31+00:00</updated>
  <id>http://artsy.github.io/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Managing Secrets in a React Native App]]></title>
    <link href="http://artsy.github.io/blog/2018/06/15/cocoapods-keys-react-native/"/>
    <updated>2018-06-15T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <id>http://artsy.github.io/blog/2018/06/15/cocoapods-keys-react-native</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<!--
Iɴᴛʀᴏᴅᴜᴄᴛɪᴏɴ
-->


<p>Hi! I'm Erik, a software engineer on the Purchase team. One of the most visible payoffs from Artsy's investments in React Native <a href="https://artsy.github.io/search/?q=react+native">over the past two years</a> has been the opening up of our mobile codebase to contributors like myself coming primarily from web stacks. It's nice to be able to build mobile interfaces with the same declarative API used by so many of our web projects, but sometimes we still need to bridge the divide to our Objective-C and Swift ecosystem. One such case: replacing the app secrets typically loaded from a deploy environment or web developer's <a href="https://www.npmjs.com/package/dotenv">dotenv</a> file.</p>

<!-- more -->


<!--
Mᴀɪɴ Bᴏᴅʏ
-->


<p><a href="https://github.com/artsy/emission">Emission</a> is Artsy's React Native component library. It contains its own native app in the <code>/Example</code> folder, which uses <a href="https://artsy.github.io/blog/2015/01/21/cocoapods-keys-and-CI/">cocoapods-keys</a> to store secrets while still letting us code in the open. In order to expose these keys to our React Native components, however, we must do a fair bit of setup. Here's a straightforward how-to that also makes a quick tour through the iOS ecosystem for web developers looking at the React Native JavaScript runtime today.</p>

<p>Links to examples below come from <a href="https://github.com/artsy/emission/pull/1086/commits/4a2a3e9260e97d791536cf38376a06b0ad0946a8">this commit</a> which adds a key for the Stripe API to Emission. When we are finished, a client app (<code>/Example</code>, <a href="https://github.com/artsy/eigen">Eigen</a>, etc.) will be able to initialize Emission with this secret, which will in turn make it available to React Native components.</p>

<a name="Steps"></a>
<h2>Steps</h2>

<a name="L1..Add.the.key.to.the.app.s.Podfile."></a>
<h4>1. Add the key to the app's Podfile.</h4>

<p>This is the extent of <code>cocoapods-keys</code> official <a href="https://github.com/orta/cocoapods-keys#usage">setup</a>, and after this you <strong>could</strong> set the key via <code>pod keys set &lt;NAME&gt;</code> or <code>pod install</code>... but we have more to do.</p>

<p><a href="https://github.com/artsy/emission/blob/4a2a3e9260e97d791536cf38376a06b0ad0946a8/Example/Podfile#L63">/Example/Podfile</a>:</p>

<pre><code class="diff">plugin 'cocoapods-keys', {
  :target =&gt; 'Emission',
  :keys =&gt; [
    'ArtsyAPIClientSecret',
    'ArtsyAPIClientKey',
+    'StripePublishableKey',
  ]
}
</code></pre>

<hr />

<a name="L2..Configure.the.library.to.consume.our.new.key"></a>
<h4>2. Configure the library to consume our new key</h4>

<p>We'll need to update the <code>initWithUserId...</code> function — one <strong>fun</strong> part of adjusting to Objective-C is that rather than named functions, we just refer to them by their entire signatures — to expose the new key as a property and add it to <code>constantsToExport</code> (<a href="https://facebook.github.io/react-native/docs/native-modules-ios.html#exporting-constants">docs</a>).</p>

<p>Note that this is happening in our <em>Emission Pod</em>; The pod now expects that key to be available in our <em>consuming</em> Example app as defined above.</p>

<p><a href="https://github.com/artsy/emission/blob/4a2a3e9260e97d791536cf38376a06b0ad0946a8/Pod/Classes/Core/AREmission.h#L17-L34">/Pod/Classes/Core/AREmission.h</a>:</p>

<pre><code class="diff">// ENV Variables
 #import &lt;React/RCTBridgeModule.h&gt;

 @interface AREmissionConfiguration : NSObject &lt;RCTBridgeModule&gt;

+ @property (nonatomic, copy, readonly, nullable) NSString *stripePublishableKey;

 - (instancetype)initWithUserID:(NSString *)userID
           authenticationToken:(NSString *)token
                     sentryDSN:(nullable NSString *)sentryDSN
+         stripePublishableKey:(NSString *)stripePublishableKey
              googleMapsAPIKey:(nullable NSString *)googleAPIKey
                    gravityURL:(NSString *)gravity
                metaphysicsURL:(NSString *)metaphysics
                     userAgent:(NSString *)userAgent;
</code></pre>

<p><code>AREmission</code>'s implementation (.m) needs to be configured to take this new key- It will be exported to our React Native components as <code>Emission</code>. We make our initializer match the signature defined in the header (.h) file, and add an instance <code>_stripePublishableKey</code> to match the <code>@property</code> declaration.</p>

<p><a href="https://github.com/artsy/emission/blob/4a2a3e9260e97d791536cf38376a06b0ad0946a8/Pod/Classes/Core/AREmission.m#L24-L60">/Pod/Classes/Core/AREmission.m</a>:</p>

<pre><code class="diff"> @implementation AREmissionConfiguration
 RCT_EXPORT_MODULE(Emission);
 # ...

 - (NSDictionary *)constantsToExport
 {
   return @{
+    @"stripePublishableKey": self.stripePublishableKey ?: @"",
     # ...lots more
   };
 }

 - (instancetype)initWithUserID:(NSString *)userID
            authenticationToken:(NSString *)token
                      sentryDSN:(NSString *)sentryDSN
+          stripePublishableKey:(NSString *)stripePublishableKey
               googleMapsAPIKey:(NSString *)googleAPIKey
                     gravityURL:(NSString *)gravity
                 metaphysicsURL:(NSString *)metaphysics
                      userAgent:(nonnull NSString *)userAgent
 {
     self = [super init];
     _userID = [userID copy];
+    _stripePublishableKey = [stripePublishableKey copy];
     # ... More copies...
     return self;
 }
</code></pre>

<p><em>Why is <code>copy</code> needed at all? See <a href="https://stackoverflow.com/questions/387959/nsstring-property-copy-or-retain/388002#388002">here</a>.</em></p>

<hr />

<a name="L3..Configure.the.example.app.to.expose.the.new.key.to.our.library"></a>
<h4>3. Configure the example app to expose the new key to our library</h4>

<p>After making sure we have imported the keys from <code>cocoapods-keys</code> we update Emission's setup to use the new initializer signature we defined above.</p>

<p><a href="https://github.com/artsy/emission/blob/4a2a3e9260e97d791536cf38376a06b0ad0946a8/Example/Emission/AppDelegate.m#L109">Example/Emission/AppDelegate.m</a>:</p>

<pre><code class="diff">#import &lt;Keys/EmissionKeys.h&gt;

  - (void)setupEmissionWithUserID:(NSString *)userID accessToken:(NSString *)accessToken keychainService:(NSString *)service;
  {
    # ...
     AREmissionConfiguration *config = [[AREmissionConfiguration alloc]
      initWithUserID:userID
      authenticationToken:accessToken
      sentryDSN:nil
+     stripePublishableKey:keys.stripePublishableKey
      googleMapsAPIKey:nil
      gravityURL:setup.gravityURL
      metaphysicsURL:setup.metaphysicsURL
      userAgent:@"Emission Example"];
    # ...
</code></pre>

<hr />

<a name="L4..Use.that.configured.key.in.a.React.Native.component."></a>
<h4>4. Use that configured key in a React Native component.</h4>

<p><code>Emission</code> is now exposed along with its configured keys via React Native's <a href="https://facebook.github.io/react-native/docs/native-modules-ios.html">NativeModules</a>.</p>

<p><a href="https://github.com/artsy/emission/blob/4a2a3e9260e97d791536cf38376a06b0ad0946a8/src/lib/components/bidding/screens/confirmfirsttimebid.tsx#l31">src/lib/Components/Bidding/Screens/ConfirmFirstTimeBid.tsx</a>:</p>

<pre><code class="js">import { NativeModules } from "react-native";
const Emission = NativeModules.Emission || {};

stripe.setOptions({
  publishableKey: Emission.stripePublishableKey
});
</code></pre>

<!--
Cᴏɴᴄʟᴜsɪᴏɴ
-->


<p>That's it! Compared to a familiar dotenv file, <strong>it</strong> certainly means a bit more ceremony here, but we are working through React Native code, its containing Pod <em>and</em> a consuming app. The process is more complicated, but it's also a nice overview of some fundamentals of Objective-C, iOS development and bridging the gap between react and mobile native code.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Making a React Native Components Pod]]></title>
    <link href="http://artsy.github.io/blog/2018/04/17/making-a-components-pod/"/>
    <updated>2018-04-17T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <id>http://artsy.github.io/blog/2018/04/17/making-a-components-pod</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>When we talk about our React Native setup in abstract, there are two kinds of "<a href="http://2.bp.blogspot.com/_PekcT72-PGE/SK3PTKwW_eI/AAAAAAAAAGY/ALg_ApHyzR8/s1600-h/1219140692800.jpg">now draw The Tick</a>" for
iOS developers:</p>

<ul>
<li>How do I build this React Native as a CocoaPods setup?</li>
<li>How do I get all the JavaScript tooling setup up?</li>
</ul>


<p>We're going to address the first part in this post. By the end of this post we're going to get an <a href="/blog/2016/08/24/On-Emission/">Emission-like
repo</a> set up for an existing OSS Swift iOS app called <a href="https://github.com/GitHawkApp/GitHawk/">GitHawk</a>. The aim being to introduce no
JavaScript tooling into GitHawk itself, and to only expose iOS-native <code>UIViewControllers</code> via a CocoaPod which is
consumed by GitHawk.</p>

<p>To do this we're going to use the CocoaPods' <code>pod lib create</code> template, and React Native's <code>react-native init</code> to
make a self-contained React Native repo. It will export a JS file, and some native code which Podspec will
reference. This keeps the tooling complexity for iOS and React Native separate. Read on to start digging in.</p>

<!-- more -->


<p>So, I'm <strong>choosing</strong> to be annoying here. I will intentionally be adding <code>$</code>s before all of the commands, this is
specifically to slow you down and make you think about each command. This isn't a quick tutorial you can skim in 2
minutes, running though it properly should take about an hour.</p>

<p>_You can also watch along with <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=ucQXL4vkP78">this YouTube video</a> of me going through
the tutorial at <a href="http://artsy.github.io/artsy-x-react-native.html">Artsy x React Native_</a>.</p>

<div class="mobile-only">
<p>
  <strong>Also, before you get started</strong>, it looks like you're using a really small screen, this post expects you would have a terminal around with useful tools for getting stuff done. I'm afraid without that, you're not going to get much out of it. I'd recommend switching to a computer.
</p>
</div>


<a name="What.Are.We.Going.To.Do."></a>
<h2>What Are We Going To Do?</h2>

<p>We will make a React Native components library (GitDawg) for an existing open-source iOS Swift Application
(GitHawk). This reflects an existing app with a team who wants to experiment with React Native in a way that doesn't
affect the main codebase. In Artsy, GitDawg is <a href="https://github.com/artsy/emission">Emission</a>, and GitHawk is <a href="https://github.com/artsy/eigen">Eigen</a>.</p>

<ol>
<li><p>We will clone and set up GitHawk</p></li>
<li><p>We will use <code>pod lib create</code> to make a library repo called GitDawg</p></li>
<li><p>We will use <code>react-native init</code> to make a React Native environment</p></li>
<li><p>We will bundle the React Native code into our Pod's asset folder</p></li>
<li><p>We will edit the Podspec for GitDawg, and then the Podfile for the example project to consume it</p></li>
<li><p>We will use <a href="https://github.com/orta/cocoapods-fix-react-native#readme">cocoapods-fix-react-native</a> to hotfix the React Native files</p></li>
<li><p>We will expose a UIViewController which corresponds to the default screen from <code>react-native init</code> in our Pod</p></li>
<li><p>We will change the storyboard reference to point to the UIViewController from our Pod, and run the simulator to
see our welcome screen.</p></li>
<li><p>We will set up GitHawk to consume our new Pod</p></li>
<li><p>We will change GitHawk to show our new UIViewController instead of the bookmarks screen</p></li>
<li><p>We will edit GitDawg to act more like a development environment</p></li>
</ol>


<a name="GitHawk"></a>
<h2>GitHawk</h2>

<p>Let's get started by having a working <a href="https://github.com/GitHawkApp/GitHawk/">copy of GitHawk</a>. I'll leave the README for GitHawk to do that, but
if you want to be certain you're on the same version as me - I'm working from this commit
<code>6dc2988d23d70eb0862d11f4a365bf47a87848c6</code>.</p>

<p>Clone a copy of GitHawk, and get it running in your Simulator, should take about 5-10 minutes, you'll need Xcode
9.3. Then we can move on to starting our components repo.</p>

<a name="GitDawg.JS"></a>
<h2>GitDawg JS</h2>

<p>When you're done with GitHawk, go back a folder so that you're ready to create the GitDawg repo: <code>$ cd ..</code>.</p>

<a name="Pre-requisites"></a>
<h3>Pre-requisites</h3>

<p>We need CocoaPods: <code>$ gem install cocoapods</code>.</p>

<p>We're going to need node, and a dependency manager. If you run <code>$ brew install yarn</code> you will get both.</p>

<p>I'm running on node <code>8.9.x</code> and yarn <code>1.5.x</code>. Honestly, it shouldn't matter if you're on node 8, or 9. Yarn is
basically CocoaPods for node projects. If you're wondering what the differences are between <a href="https://github.com/yarnpkg/yarn/">yarn</a> and <a href="https://www.npmjs.com/">NPM</a>,
then TLDR: there used to be some, but now there's few. I stick with yarn because I prefer how the CLI works, and I
can easily read the lockfile it generates.</p>

<p>We need the React Native CLI, so let's install it globally: <code>$ yarn global add react-native-cli</code>.</p>

<a name="Starting.with.the.Pod"></a>
<h3>Starting with the Pod</h3>

<p>We're going to let CocoaPods create the initial folder for our project. Let's set up your Pod:</p>

<pre><code class="sh">$ pod lib create GitDawg

Cloning `https://github.com/CocoaPods/pod-template.git` into `GitDawg`.
Configuring GitDawg template.

------------------------------

To get you started we need to ask a few questions, this should only take a minute.

If this is your first time we recommend running through with the guide:
 - http://guides.cocoapods.org/making/using-pod-lib-create.html
 ( hold cmd and click links to open in a browser. )


What platform do you want to use?? [ iOS / macOS ]
 &gt; iOS

What language do you want to use?? [ Swift / ObjC ]
 &gt; ObjC

Would you like to include a demo application with your library? [ Yes / No ]
 &gt; Yes

Which testing frameworks will you use? [ Specta / Kiwi / None ]
 &gt; None

Would you like to do view based testing? [ Yes / No ]
 &gt; No

What is your class prefix?
 &gt; GD
</code></pre>

<p>I'd recommend using only Objective-C at this point, for simplicities sake. Swift is a great language, but I want
tooling simplicity. Swift and React Native is [docs] though. We're also not going to write enough native code to
warrant the setup for testing. Plus, if we skip native testing then we can run CI on linux - which is basically
instant in comparison.</p>

<p>This has made a new library. Let's go into our project's root with <code>$ cd GitDawg</code>. There shouldn't be too much in
here:</p>

<pre><code class="sh">$ ls
Example         GitDawg         GitDawg.podspec LICENSE         README.md         _Pods.xcodeproj
</code></pre>

<p>Because the core competency of the repo is the JavaScript, we're going to rename the "GitDawg" folder in the root to
be about the CocoaPod instead of owning the name of the project. Run <code>$ mv GitDawg Pod</code> to do that.</p>

<p>We want to create our React Native project. I'm hard-coding my versions in these commands to try ensure this post
lasts some time, but you never know what amazing changes the future brings. If things are broken, leave a comment at
the bottom of this post.</p>

<p>Let’s create a GitDawg React Native project, and then rename the folder to src:</p>

<pre><code class="sh"># Use the RN CLI to create a new RN app in the folder GitDawg
$ react-native init GitDawg --version react-native@0.54.4

# Rename the folder to src
$ mv GitDawg src

# Remove _Pods.xcodeproj as it's relevant for our pod
$ rm -rf _Pods.xcodeproj
</code></pre>

<p>We don't want all our project files living in a sub-folder though, so let's move a few of them back to the repo's
root, then remove some unused files.</p>

<pre><code class="sh"># Copy the package metadata, deps, lockfile and dotfiles to root
$ mv src/package.json src/node_modules src/yarn.lock src/.* .

# Remove the ios and android scaffolds as we have the CP one
$ rm -rf src/ios src/android
</code></pre>

<p>Which should make your app's folder look something like this:</p>

<pre><code class="sh">$ ls
Example         GitDawg.podspec LICENSE         README.md       Pods        node_modules    package.json    src             yarn.lock

$ ls src/
App.js    __tests__ app.json  index.js
</code></pre>

<p>To ensure everything is still hooked up, let's make sure that all of your tests are working in the new repo.</p>

<pre><code class="sh">$ yarn test

yarn run v1.5.1
 PASS  src/__tests__/App.js
  ✓ renders correctly (176ms)

Test Suites: 1 passed, 1 total
Tests:       1 passed, 1 total
Snapshots:   0 total
Time:        1.392s
Ran all test suites.
✨  Done in 2.32s.
</code></pre>

<p>We're now going to be done with our JavaScript side, basically is our React Native "hello world". It's a React
Native project that exposes a single component which says <code>"Welcome to React Native!"</code>.</p>

<p>However, it's going to take a bit of work before we can see it in action.</p>

<a name="Deployment"></a>
<h3>Deployment</h3>

<p>We're going to want to have this exposed to our native libraries, so we're going to ship the bundled JavaScript as
our library's source code. We do this via the React Native CLI, and it's going to place the file inside our Pod
folder from earlier.</p>

<pre><code class="sh">$ react-native bundle --entry-file src/index.js --bundle-output Pod/Assets/GitDawg.js --assets-dest Pod/Assets
</code></pre>

<p>It looks like this, when you run it via the sim:</p>

<center><img src="/images/making_cp_pod/success.png" width="50%" /></center>


<a name="GitDawg.Pod"></a>
<h2>GitDawg Pod</h2>

<p>With that done, we can start looking at the native side of our codebase. We let <code>pod lib create</code> set up an Example
app for us to work with in the repo, which consumes a Podspec in the root. So we're going to take a look at the
Podspec, and update it.</p>

<p>Our goal with the Example app is to set up an app exclusively for developing components in. In Artsy's case, this
app handles auth to the Artsy API and has a series of jump-off points for developing a component.</p>

<p>To get started we need to modify the CocoaPod this repo represents:</p>

<ul>
<li>Update our Podspec to handle React Native as a dependency, and our assets</li>
<li>Add support for native compilation via CocoaPods with <a href="https://github.com/orta/cocoapods-fix-react-native#readme">cocoapods-fix-react-native</a></li>
<li>Create a single <code>UIViewController</code> subclass for the Welcome Screen using the bundled React Native JS</li>
</ul>


<p>We want to have our Podspec re-use the metadata from React Native to set up GitDawg's dependencies. So replace
<code>GitDawg.podspec</code> with this:</p>

<pre><code class="ruby">require 'json'

# Returns the version number for a package.json file
pkg_version = lambda do |dir_from_root = '', version = 'version'|
  path = File.join(__dir__, dir_from_root, 'package.json')
  JSON.parse(File.read(path))[version]
end

# Let the main package.json decide the version number for the pod
gitdawg_version = pkg_version.call
# Use the same RN version that the JS tools use
react_native_version = pkg_version.call('node_modules/react-native')

Pod::Spec.new do |s|
  s.name             = 'GitDawg'
  s.version          = gitdawg_version
  s.description      = 'Components for GitHawk.'
  s.summary          = 'Components for GitHawk.'
  s.homepage         = 'https://github.com/orta/GitDawg'
  s.license          = { type: 'MIT', file: 'LICENSE' }
  s.author           = { 'orta' =&gt; 'orta.therox@gmail.com' }
  s.source           = { git: 'https://github.com/orta/GitDawg.git', tag: s.version.to_s }

  s.source_files   = 'Pod/Classes/**/*.{h,m}'
  s.resources      = 'Pod/Assets/{GitDawg.js,assets}'
  s.platform       = :ios, '8.0'

  # React is split into a set of subspecs, these are the essentials
  s.dependency 'React/Core', react_native_version
  s.dependency 'React/CxxBridge', react_native_version
  s.dependency 'React/RCTAnimation', react_native_version
  s.dependency 'React/RCTImage', react_native_version
  s.dependency 'React/RCTLinkingIOS', react_native_version
  s.dependency 'React/RCTNetwork', react_native_version
  s.dependency 'React/RCTText', react_native_version

  # React's dependencies
  s.dependency 'yoga', "#{react_native_version}.React"
  podspecs = [
    'node_modules/react-native/third-party-podspecs/DoubleConversion.podspec',
    'node_modules/react-native/third-party-podspecs/Folly.podspec',
    'node_modules/react-native/third-party-podspecs/glog.podspec'
  ]
  podspecs.each do |podspec_path|
    spec = Pod::Specification.from_file podspec_path
    s.dependency spec.name, "#{spec.version}"
  end
end
</code></pre>

<p>This Podspec is probably more complex then you're used to, but it means less config. To validate the Podspec, use
<code>$ pod ipc spec GitDawg.podspec</code> and read the JSON it outputs. With the Podspec set up, it's time to set up the
example project's <code>Gemfile</code> and <code>Podfile</code>.</p>

<p>We'll start with applying the <a href="https://github.com/orta/cocoapods-fix-react-native#readme">React Native hot-fix plugin</a>, sometimes a version of React Native is released
that doesn't support Swift frameworks (as Facebook doesn't use Swift) and so you have to apply some patches to the
code. I made a CocoaPods Plugin that handles the hot-fixes for you.</p>

<p>Start by making a <code>Gemfile</code> in the <code>Example</code> folder: <code>touch Example/Gemfile</code></p>

<pre><code class="ruby">source 'https://rubygems.org'

gem 'cocoapods'
gem 'cocoapods-fix-react-native'
</code></pre>

<p>Then run <code>$ bundle install</code> in the <code>Example</code> folder, which will set up the ruby dependencies of <code>cocoapods</code> and
<code>cocoapods-fix-react-native</code> for your app. This makes it possible to reference <code>"cocoapods-fix-react-native"</code> in
your <code>Podfile</code> next.</p>

<pre><code class="sh">$ cd Example
$ bundle install
</code></pre>

<p>We want to take the current <code>Podfile</code> and make sure that every React Native dependency comes from the folder
<code>node_modules/react-native</code>. We can do this using the <code>:path</code> operator to redeclare where you can find each Pod.</p>

<p>Note: we also <em>extend</em> the amount of subspecs for <code>'React'</code> in this Podfile via <code>subspecs: ['DevSupport']</code> - this
subspec is what provide the hot code reloading and other developer tools. You'll want this, in here, it will mean
that the example app can be used as a dev environment, and your main app will only get a production environment.</p>

<p>So edit <code>Example/Podfile</code> to look like this:</p>

<pre><code class="ruby">platform :ios, '9.0'

node_modules_path = '../node_modules'
react_path = File.join(node_modules_path, 'react-native')
yoga_path = File.join(react_path, 'ReactCommon/yoga')
folly_spec_path = File.join(react_path, 'third-party-podspecs/Folly.podspec')
glog_spec_path = File.join(react_path, 'third-party-podspecs/glog.podspec')
double_conversion_spec_path = File.join(react_path, 'third-party-podspecs/DoubleConversion.podspec')

plugin 'cocoapods-fix-react-native'

target 'GitDawg_Example' do
  pod 'GitDawg', path: '../'

  # We want extra developer support in React inside this app
  pod 'React', path: react_path, subspecs: ['DevSupport']

  # We're letting CP know where it can find these Podspecs
  pod 'yoga', path: yoga_path
  pod 'Folly', podspec: folly_spec_path
  pod 'DoubleConversion', podspec: double_conversion_spec_path
  pod 'glog', podspec: glog_spec_path
end
</code></pre>

<p>Run the following to set up the React Native dependencies for your project.</p>

<pre><code>$ bundle exec pod install
</code></pre>

<p>We need some native code to represent our Welcome component from the React Native template. Create two new files in
<code>Pod/Classes</code>, then re-create the CocoaPods project for it by <code>pod install</code>ing again.</p>

<pre><code class="sh">$ touch ../Pod/Classes/GDWelcomeViewController.h ../Pod/Classes/GDWelcomeViewController.m
$ bundle exec pod install
$ open GitDawg.xcworkspace
</code></pre>

<p>We're going to make a pretty vanilla <code>UIViewController</code>, so declare it exists in the interface and then use an
<code>RCTRootView</code> as it's <code>self.view</code>.</p>

<pre><code class="objc">#import &lt;UIKit/UIKit.h&gt;

@interface GDWelcomeViewController : UIViewController
@end
</code></pre>

<p>The <code>GDWelcomeViewController</code> is going to handle the React bridging, because that is the simplest option for our
Hello World app. We'll be going back to improve this later.</p>

<pre><code class="objc">#import "GDWelcomeViewController.h"
#import &lt;React/RCTRootView.h&gt;
#import &lt;React/RCTBridgeDelegate.h&gt;
#import &lt;React/RCTBridge.h&gt;

// Let this View Controller handle getting the URL for the JS
@interface GDWelcomeViewController () &lt;RCTBridgeDelegate&gt;
@end

@implementation GDWelcomeViewController

// Set self.view on the VC to be an RCTRootView
- (void)loadView
{
    RCTBridge *bridge = [[RCTBridge alloc] initWithDelegate:self launchOptions:@{}];
    self.view = [[RCTRootView alloc] initWithBridge:bridge
                                         moduleName:@"GitDawg"
                                  initialProperties:@{}];
}

// Use our bundled JS for now
- (NSURL *)sourceURLForBridge:(RCTBridge *)bridge
{
    NSBundle *gitdawgBundle = [NSBundle bundleForClass:GDWelcomeViewController.class];
    return [gitdawgBundle URLForResource:@"GitDawg" withExtension:@"js"];
}

@end
</code></pre>

<p>As the <code>pod lib create</code> template uses storyboards, you will need to open up the example app's storyboard and
<a href="/images/making_cp_pod/settings_welcome.png">change the initial view controller</a> to be a <code>GDWelcomeViewController</code>.
If you see a <a href="/images/making_cp_pod/not_working.png">white screen</a> on the app launches then this hasn't been done.
Run the app in the simulator, and you should get this screen:</p>

<center><img src="/images/making_cp_pod/success.png" width="50%" /></center>


<p>This is the default screen from the React Native template, and it's proof that everything has worked for our dev
app.</p>

<p>Let's take a second to re-cover what has happened to get to this point.</p>

<ol>
<li><p>We used the <code>pod lib create</code> template to make a library repo</p></li>
<li><p>We used <code>react-native init</code> to make a React Native environment, which has the settings in the root and the
source code inside <code>src</code></p></li>
<li><p>We've bundled the React Native code into our CocoaPod's asset folder</p></li>
<li><p>We set up the Podspec for GitDawg, and then the Podfile for the example project to consume it</p></li>
<li><p>We added <a href="https://github.com/orta/cocoapods-fix-react-native#readme">cocoapods-fix-react-native</a> to hot-fix the native files</p></li>
<li><p>We added a UIViewController for the default screen from <code>react-native init</code> to our CocoaPod, and ran
<code>bundle exec pod install</code> to update the example project</p></li>
<li><p>We changed the storyboard reference to point to the UIViewController from our Pod, and ran the simulator to see
our welcome screen</p></li>
</ol>


<p>This is a full run-through of how your Pod would look when integrated into your main app's codebase. At this point
you have a unique, isolated app which is going to be your development environment. In our case this app is a menu of
different root screens and admin flags.</p>

<p>—</p>

<p>OK, let’s go take this and migrate it into GitHawk. This is our end-goal:</p>

<center><img src="/images/making_cp_pod/githawk.gif" width="75%" /></center>


<p>Our setup is going to be different here because we can't rely on React Native coming from the file-system, as we
want to make sure our app has no hint of JS tooling. So we will use CocoaPods to handle downloading and setting up
our versions of the React Native libraries. As of 0.54.x, that is React and Yoga.</p>

<p>We want to have a local copy of the JSON version of Podspecs for each of these. They can be generated from the
Podspecs using <code>bundle exec pod ipc spec [file.podspec]</code>. Let's generate one for React:</p>

<pre><code class="sh">$ cd GitDawg/node_modules/react-native/; pod ipc spec React.podspec
</code></pre>

<p>It will output a bunch of JSON to your terminal. This is perfect. Let's move that text to a file on your desktop.</p>

<pre><code class="sh">$ pod ipc spec React.podspec &gt; ~/Desktop/React.podspec.json
</code></pre>

<!--

You'll see no output if everything went fine. Before you grab that podspec, let's get the one for yoga too.

```sh
$ cd ReactCommon/yoga/; pod ipc spec yoga.podspec > ~/Desktop/yoga.podspec.json
```

-->


<p>For the yoga podspec, you should just grab our version, it's not worth me explaining all the details why, other than
the PR I made to fix a bug isn't shipped in 0.54 so run:</p>

<pre><code class="sh">curl https://raw.githubusercontent.com/artsy/emission/v1.5.0/externals/yoga/yoga.podspec.json &gt; ~/Desktop/yoga.podspec.json
</code></pre>

<p>You should now have two JSON files in your Desktop. Grab them, move them into the <code>Local Pods</code> folder inside
GitHawk. It should already have a few Podspecs.</p>

<pre><code class="sh">$ cd ../../../ # Or however it takes to get back to the project root

# Move any podspec.json into the Local Pods folder
$ mv ~/Desktop/*.podspec.json "Local Pods"
</code></pre>

<p>Modify their <code>Gemfile</code> to include <a href="https://github.com/orta/cocoapods-fix-react-native#readme">cocoapods-fix-react-native</a>:</p>

<pre><code class="diff">source 'https://rubygems.org'

gem 'cocoapods', '~&gt; 1.4.0'
+ gem 'cocoapods-fix-react-native'
</code></pre>

<p>Then run <code>bundle install</code>. Next we need to add GitDawg, and our custom Podspecs to the Podfile:</p>

<pre><code class="diff">source 'https://github.com/CocoaPods/Specs.git'

# Local Pods w/ custom changes
pod 'SwipeCellKit', :path =&gt; 'Local Pods/SwipeCellKit'
pod 'GitHubAPI', :path =&gt; 'Local Pods/GitHubAPI'
pod 'GitHubSession', :path =&gt; 'Local Pods/GitHubSession'

+ # React Native Support
+ plugin 'cocoapods-fix-react-native'
+ pod 'GitDawg', :path =&gt; '../GitDawg'
+ pod 'React', :podspec =&gt; 'Local Pods/React.podspec.json'
+ pod 'yoga',  :podspec =&gt; 'Local Pods/yoga.podspec.json'

target 'Freetime' do
</code></pre>

<p>Then run <code>$ bundle exec pod install</code>. That should grab React Native for you. Unlike inside GitDawg, CocoaPods will
download the source code from the internet. <code>:podspec</code> only tells CocoaPods where to find the Podspec, but it will
still download code externally.</p>

<p>Open up the Xcode Workspace - <code>open Freetime.xcworkspace</code>, and we're gonna make the code changes - it's all in one
file. Open the file <code>RootNavigationManager.swift</code> (it's in <code>Classes/Systems</code>) and add a new <code>import</code> at the top for
<code>GitDawg</code>:</p>

<pre><code class="diff">import UIKit
import GitHubAPI
import GitHubSession
+ import GitDawg
</code></pre>

<p>Then add our new view controller by replacing the bookmarks view controller on line 78.</p>

<pre><code class="diff">        tabBarController?.viewControllers = [
            newNotificationsRootViewController(client: client),
            newSearchRootViewController(client: client),
+            GDWelcomeViewController(),
-            newBookmarksRootViewController(client: client),
            settingsRootViewController ?? UIViewController() // simply satisfying compiler
        ]
</code></pre>

<p>That should get you to the same point as we were in the dev app. Now when you run the app, log in and hit the place
where the bookmarks icon used to live. Tada.</p>

<p>So what did we do? First, we added GitDawg, React and Yoga as dependencies in GitHawk's Podfile to get them
installed. Then we switched to using GitDawg's native view controller in 2 lines of code. No JavaScript in GitHawk,
little faffing overall.</p>

<p>This is how all our view controllers are exposed and used in production.</p>

<a name="What.now."></a>
<h2>What now?</h2>

<p>We've now got a successful deploy of our React Native Pod into an external app. However, we need to make some
changes in GitDawg now to start making it possible to develop efficiently.</p>

<p>We will need to:</p>

<ol>
<li><p>Make a singleton to handle setting up React Native between all potential UIViewControllers</p></li>
<li><p>Use the React Native Packager to get runtime editing support</p></li>
</ol>


<p>Move your terminal back to the GitDawg folder. We're going to make a class that represents our library, GitDawg</p>

<pre><code class="sh">$ touch Pod/Classes/GitDawg.h Pod/Classes/GitDawg.m
</code></pre>

<p>Then we need to re-run <code>$ bundle exec pod install</code> in the <code>Example</code> folder to get it in Xcode. Open up the Xcode
workspace for GitDawg and let's fill in these files. These files are based on <a href="https://github.com/artsy/emission/blob/master/Pod/Classes/Core/AREmission.h">AREmission.h</a> and
<a href="https://github.com/artsy/emission/blob/master/Pod/Classes/Core/AREmission.m">AREmission.m</a>. For us, in a production app, <code>AREmission</code> has a few key responsibilities:</p>

<ol>
<li><p>Pass through the non-optional environment variables to expose in JS</p></li>
<li><p>Create and retain the React Native bridge</p></li>
<li><p>Set up the native modules so that we React Native can communicate with the host app</p></li>
</ol>


<p>For this tutorial we don't need all of these responsibilities, but we will handle the second one.</p>

<p>For the header file, <code>GitDawg.h</code>:</p>

<pre><code class="objc">#import &lt;Foundation/Foundation.h&gt;
#import &lt;React/RCTBridge.h&gt;

NS_ASSUME_NONNULL_BEGIN

/// The RN library API
@interface GitDawg : NSObject

/// The way in which we communicate with React Native
@property (nonatomic, strong, readonly) RCTBridge *bridge;

/// The single instance of a GitDawg
+ (instancetype)sharedInstance;
+ (void)setSharedInstance:(GitDawg *)instance;

/// Pass in nil for a packagerURL to indicate this is in release mode
- (instancetype)initWithPackagerURL:(nullable NSURL *)packagerURL NS_DESIGNATED_INITIALIZER;
- (instancetype)init NS_UNAVAILABLE;

@end

NS_ASSUME_NONNULL_END
</code></pre>

<p>And for the implementation file <code>GitDawg.m</code>:</p>

<pre><code class="objc">#import "GitDawg.h"

@interface GitDawg() &lt;RCTBridgeDelegate&gt;
@property (nonatomic, copy) NSURL *packagerURL;
@end

@implementation GitDawg

static GitDawg *_sharedInstance = nil;

+ (void)setSharedInstance:(GitDawg *)instance;
{
    _sharedInstance = instance;
}

+ (instancetype)sharedInstance;
{
    NSParameterAssert(_sharedInstance);
    return _sharedInstance;
}

- (instancetype)initWithPackagerURL:(NSURL *)packagerURL
{
    self = [super init];

    _packagerURL = packagerURL;
    _bridge = [[RCTBridge alloc] initWithDelegate:self launchOptions:@{}];

    return self;
}

- (NSURL *)sourceURLForBridge:(RCTBridge *)bridge
{
    return self.packagerURL ?: self.releaseBundleURL;
}

- (NSURL *)releaseBundleURL;
{
    return [[NSBundle bundleForClass:self.class] URLForResource:@"GitDawg" withExtension:@"js"];
}

@end
</code></pre>

<p>Then change your <code>GDWelcomeViewController.m</code> to use the shared <code>GitDawg</code>.</p>

<pre><code class="diff"> #import "GDWelcomeViewController.h"
+#import "GitDawg.h"
 #import &lt;React/RCTRootView.h&gt;
-#import &lt;React/RCTBridgeDelegate.h&gt;
-#import &lt;React/RCTBridge.h&gt;

 - (void)loadView
 {
-    RCTBridge *bridge = [[RCTBridge alloc] initWithDelegate:self launchOptions:@{}];
+    RCTBridge *bridge = [GitDawg sharedInstance].bridge;
     self.view = [[RCTRootView alloc] initWithBridge:bridge
                                              moduleName:@"GitDawg"
                                     initialProperties:@{}];
 }

-// Just use our packaged JS for now
-- (NSURL *)sourceURLForBridge:(RCTBridge *)bridge
-{
-    NSBundle *emissionBundle = [NSBundle bundleForClass:GDWelcomeViewController.class];
-    return [emissionBundle URLForResource:@"GitDawg" withExtension:@"js"];
-}
-
 @end
</code></pre>

<p>We use the UIAppDelegate callback to set up our React Native bridge (you want this ready as fast as possible
normally) so edit <code>Example/GitDawg/GDAppDelegate.m</code></p>

<pre><code class="diff"> #import "GDAppDelegate.h"
+#import &lt;GitDawg/GitDawg.h&gt;

 @implementation GDAppDelegate

 - (BOOL)application:(UIApplication *)application didFinishLaunchingWithOptions:(NSDictionary *)launchOptions
 {
-    // Override point for customization after application launch.
+    NSURL *packagerURL = [NSURL URLWithString:@"http://localhost:8081/src/index.bundle?platform=ios"];
+    GitDawg *dawg = [[GitDawg alloc] initWithPackagerURL:packagerURL];
+    [GitDawg setSharedInstance:dawg];
+
     return YES;
 }
</code></pre>

<p>These changes give you the ability to switch between a dev mode and a release mode. Consider that React Native just
runs your JavaScript, the source of that could be anything, including from a local dev server. Well, almost.</p>

<p>Because of Apple's HTTP security, you cannot connect to localhost in an app by default. To fix this, open up
<code>GitDawg-info.plist</code> and right-click to add a new row. Paste in <code>NSAppTransportSecurity</code> as the name, and Xcode will
switch it to "App Transport Security Settings". Hit the <code>+</code> and add "Allow arbitrary loads" then set it to true.</p>

<p>From here: run the GitDawg app and you should see a red screen. This will be telling you to start the React Native
Packager. Let's do that. From the root of the GitDwag repo run <code>$ yarn start</code>. This will start up a server. Once it
says "Metro Bundler Ready." you can go back into your simulator for GitDawg and hit the reload button at the bottom.</p>

<p>That's it.</p>

<p>We're done.</p>

<p>So, there's obviously a lot more to learn here. You've successfully set up a Pod that you can deploy to an app. To
make a real version you'd need to do a bit more process like creating a repo, and making tags.</p>

<p>We use our root view controller in Emission to trigger loading any of our view controllers, in different states. We
also mix that with some admin options, the ability to run someone's PRs and <a href="https://storybook.js.org">storybooks</a>.</p>

<center><img src="/images/making_cp_pod/emission.png" width="100%" /></center>


<p>So good luck! Something like this probably easily scripted, but there's a lot of value in understanding how every
piece comes together. So let me know if you make something cool - we've been using this structure for 2 years now
and I think it's the right way to integrate React Native into an existing complex app. It keeps your JS tooling in a
completely different repo from your iOS tooling.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[React Native, 2 years later]]></title>
    <link href="http://artsy.github.io/blog/2018/03/17/two-years-of-react-native/"/>
    <updated>2018-03-17T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <id>http://artsy.github.io/blog/2018/03/17/two-years-of-react-native</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><a href="https://twitter.com/alloy/">@alloy</a> first mentioned React Native as an option for Artsy back <a href="https://github.com/artsy/mobile/issues/22">in March 2015</a>, and in February 2016 he
made <a href="https://github.com/artsy/emission/commit/b9154d4145feb49b38e713ee84594de04ea377e3#diff-9879d6db96fd29134fc802214163b95a">our first commit</a> to get the ball rolling. Since then, we've grown a new codebase, <a href="https://github.com/artsy/emission/">Emission</a>,
which has slowly taken over the responsibility for creating the UIViewControllers presented inside our iOS app.</p>

<p>We've come quite far from where we started, and I was asked if I could give a talk to summerize what we've learned in
the last 2 years as a set of native developers using React Native.</p>

<p>The <a href="https://speakerdeck.com/orta/react-native-2-years-later">slides are on speakerdeck</a>, and I've <a href="https://github.com/artsy/artsy.github.io/issues/420">opened comments</a> for this post if people have questions. Jump
through to get to the video or watch it <a href="https://www.prolificinteractive.com/iosoho/">on Prolific's site</a> for <a href="https://www.meetup.com/iOSoho/">iOSoho</a>.</p>

<!-- more -->


<p>Table of Contents for the Video:</p>

<ul id="timers">
  <li><a href="#video" data-time="330">Why move? 5:30</a></li>
  <li><a href="#video" data-time="520">Why not Swift? 8:40</a></li>
  <li><a href="#video" data-time="590">What we expected vs what we have: 9:50</a></li>
  <li><a href="#video" data-time="960">Downsides: 16:00</a></li>
  <li><a href="#video" data-time="1235">Artsy Omakase: 20:35</a></li>
  <li><a href="#video" data-time="1420">Upsides: 23:40</a></li>
  <li><a href="#video" data-time="1645">In-App demo of Emission: 27:25</a></li>
  <li><a href="#video" data-time="2195">RN Brownfield Apps: 36:35</a></li>
  <li><a href="#video" data-time="2379">Our Deployment: 39:30</a></li>
</ul>




<center id="video">
  <iframe src="https://player.vimeo.com/video/260417482" width="100%" height="600" frameborder="0" webkitallowfullscreen mozallowfullscreen allowfullscreen></iframe>
</center>




<script src="https://player.vimeo.com/api/player.js"></script>


<script>
  $(() => {
    $('#timers a').click( function(e) {
      var time = $(this).attr("data-time");
      var iframe = document.querySelector('iframe');
      var player = new Vimeo.Player(iframe);
      player.setCurrentTime(time)
      e.stopPropagation()
    });
  })
</script>



]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Modernizing Force]]></title>
    <link href="http://artsy.github.io/blog/2017/09/05/Modernizing-Force/"/>
    <updated>2017-09-05T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <id>http://artsy.github.io/blog/2017/09/05/Modernizing-Force</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><a href="https://github.com/artsy/force">Force</a> is Artsy's main website, <a href="https://www.artsy.net">artsy.net</a>. In the three years since it was <a href="http://artsy.github.io/blog/2014/09/05/we-open-sourced-our-isomorphic-javascript-website/">open-sourced</a>, it has provided a solid foundation to build features on top of without a lot of the costs associated with growth. It is an early example of Isomorphic ("universal") JavaScript, built on top of Express, Backbone, CoffeeScript, Stylus and Jade. It is also highly modular, adopting patterns laid down by its parent project,  <a href="https://github.com/artsy/ezel">Ezel</a>.</p>

<p>When first developed these technologies made a lot of sense; CoffeeScript fixed many of the problems with JavaScript pre-ES6, and Jade / Stylus made working with HTML / CSS much more elegant. As time progressed and new technologies became a thing these solutions starting feeling more burdensome to continue building features with and many of our developers longed to start using next-generation tools like React.</p>

<!-- more -->


<p>Looking at output from <code>cloc</code>, the question is "But how?"</p>

<pre><code class="js">[artsy/force] $ cloc desktop mobile

--------------------------------------------------------
Language                     files                  code
--------------------------------------------------------
CoffeeScript                  1828                 81569
CSS                              9                 76632
Stylus                         577                 32324
JavaScript                     274                 18310
JSON                            30                  6145
Markdown                        41                  1097
HTML                             3                    25
XML                              3                    24
--------------------------------------------------------
SUM:                          2765                216126
--------------------------------------------------------
</code></pre>

<p>216k+ LOC, spread across multiple languages and formats. Given finite resources and a small team rebuilds can be difficult to execute, and so we had to figure out a way to marry the old with the new while also maintaining backwards compatibility / interoperability. Out of this exercise came a few patterns, libraries and projects that I would like to describe in an effort to help those caught in similar situations.</p>

<a name="Step.1:.Get.Your.House..aka.Compiler..in.Order"></a>
<h2>Step 1: Get Your House (aka Compiler) in Order</h2>

<p><a href="https://babeljs.io/">Babel</a> has been around for a while, but lately their team has been putting effort into making it as easy as possible to use. By dropping a <a href="https://github.com/artsy/force/blob/master/.babelrc">.babelrc</a> file into the root of your project, server and client-side JavaScript can share the same configuration, including <a href="https://github.com/tleunen/babel-plugin-module-resolver">module resolution</a> (aka, no more <code>../../../</code>).</p>

<p>A simplified example:</p>

<pre><code class="json">// .babelrc

{
  "presets": ["es2015", "react", "stage-3"],
  "plugins": [
    ["module-resolver", {
      "root": ["./"]
    }]
  ]
}
</code></pre>

<pre><code class="js">// index.js

require('coffee-script/register')
require('babel-core/register')

// Start the app
require('./boot')
</code></pre>

<p>On the client, we use <a href="http://browserify.org/">Browserify</a> with <a href="https://github.com/substack/coffeeify">Coffeeify</a> and <a href="https://github.com/babel/babelify">Babelify</a>:</p>

<pre><code class="json">// package.json

{
  "scripts": {
    "assets": "browserify -t babelify -t coffeeify -o bundle.js",
    "start": "yarn assets &amp;&amp; node index.js"
  }
}
</code></pre>

<p>And then boot it up:
<code>sh
$ yarn start
</code></p>

<p>By adding just a few lines, our existing CoffeeScript pipeline was augmented to support modern JavaScript on both the server and the client, with code that can be shared between.</p>

<a name="Step.2:.Tune-up.Iteration.Time"></a>
<h2>Step 2: Tune-up Iteration Time</h2>

<p><a name="iteration-time"></a></p>

<p>A question that every developer should ask of their stack is:</p>

<blockquote><p>"How long does it take for me to make a change and see that change reflected in a running process?"</p></blockquote>

<p>Does your code take one second to compile, or ten? When writing a back-end service, does your server <a href="https://github.com/remy/nodemon">automatically restart</a> after you make a change, or do you need to <code>ctrl+c</code> (stop it) and then restart manually?</p>

<p>For those of us working in Force, the bottleneck typically involved making changes to back-end code. Due to how we organize our sub-apps, client-side code compilation -- after the server heats up -- is pretty much instant, but that heat-up time can often take a while depending on which app we're working on. So even with a "restart on code change" setup that listens for updates it still felt terribly slow, and this iteration time would often discourage developers from touching certain areas of the codebase. We needed something better!</p>

<p>Enter Webpack and React, which helped popularize the concept of HMR, or "Hot Module Replacement".</p>

<p>From the Webpack docs:</p>

<blockquote><p>"Hot Module Replacement (HMR) exchanges, adds, or removes modules while an application is running, without a full reload."</p></blockquote>

<p>That's more like it! But is there anything similar for the server given we don't use Webpack? This was the question <a href="https://github.com/alloy">@alloy</a>, one of our Engineering Leads, asked himself while researching various setups that ultimately led to <a href="https://github.com/artsy/reaction">Reaction</a>, and for which he found an answer to in Glen Mailer's excellent <a href="https://github.com/glenjamin/ultimate-hot-reloading-example">ultimate-hot-reloading-example</a>. Digging into the code, <a href="https://github.com/glenjamin/ultimate-hot-reloading-example/blob/master/server.js#L38-L45">this little snippet</a> jumped out:</p>

<pre><code class="js">watcher.on('ready', function() {
  watcher.on('all', function() {
    console.log("Clearing /server/ module cache from server");
    Object.keys(require.cache).forEach(function(id) {
      if (/[\/\\]server[\/\\]/.test(id)) delete require.cache[id];
    });
  });
});
</code></pre>

<p>The code seemed simple enough -- on change, iterate through Node.js's internal require cache, look for the changed module, and clear it out. When the module is <code>require</code>'d at a later point it will be like it was required for the first time, effectively hot-swapping out the code.</p>

<p>With this knowledge we wrapped a modified version of this snippet into <a href="https://github.com/artsy/express-reloadable">@artsy/express-reloadable</a>, a small utility package meant to be used with Express.</p>

<p>Here's a full example:</p>

<pre><code class="js">import express from 'express'
import { createReloadable, isDevelopment } from '@artsy/express-reloadable'

const app = express()

if (isDevelopment) {

  // Pass in app and current `require` context
  const reloadAndMount = createReloadable(app, require)

  // Note that if you need to mount an app at a particular root (`/api`), pass
  // in `mountPoint` as an option.
  app.use('/api', reloadAndMount(path.resolve(__dirname, 'api'), {
    mountPoint: '/api'
  }))

  // Otherwise, just pass in the path to the express app and everything is taken care of
  reloadAndMount(path.resolve(__dirname, 'client'))
} else {
  app.use('/api', require('./api')
  app.use(require('./client')
}

app.listen(3000, () =&gt; {
  console.log(`Listening on port 3000`)
})
</code></pre>

<p>In Force, we mounted this library <a href="https://github.com/artsy/force/blob/master/lib/setup.js#L205">at the root</a>, allowing us to make changes anywhere within our numerous sub-apps and with a fresh page reload instantly see those changes reflected without a restart. This approach also works great with API servers, as this implementation from Artsy's <a href="https://github.com/artsy/positron/blob/master/boot.js#L34">editorial app Positron</a> shows. Like magic, it "just works". Why isn't this trick more widely used and known?</p>

<a name="Step.3:.The.View.Layer..or:.How.I.Stopped.Worrying.and.Learned.to.Love.Legacy.UI"></a>
<h2>Step 3: The View Layer, or: How I Stopped Worrying and Learned to Love Legacy UI</h2>

<p>This one was a bit tricky to solve, but ultimately ended up being fairly straightforward and conceptually simple. In Force, we've got dozens of apps built on top of hundreds of components supported by thousands of tests stretched across desktop and mobile. From the perspective of sheer code volume these things aren't going anywhere any time soon. On top of that, our view templates are built using Jade (now known as <a href="https://pugjs.org">Pug</a>), which supports an interesting form of inheritance known as <a href="https://pugjs.org/language/inheritance.html">blocks</a>. What this means in practice is our UI has been extended in a variety of complex ways making alternative view engines difficult on the surface to interpolate.</p>

<p>What to do? It's 2017 and the era of handlebars templates bound to Backbone MVC views is over. We want <a href="https://facebook.github.io/react/">React</a>! We want <a href="https://www.styled-components.com/">Styled Components</a>! And when those tools are surpassed by the Next Big Thing we want that too! But we also want our existing CoffeeScript and Jade and old-school <code>Backbone.View</code>s as well.</p>

<p>Thinking through this problem, <a href="https://github.com/artsy/stitch">@artsy/stitch</a> was born.</p>

<p>Stitch helps your Template and Component dependencies peacefully co-exist. You feed it a layout and some data and out pops a string of compiled html that can be passed down to the client. "Blocks" can be added that represent portions of UI, injected by key. It aims for maximum flexibility: templating engines supported by <a href="https://github.com/tj/consolidate.js">consolidate</a> can be installed and custom rendering engines <a href="https://github.com/artsy/stitch#custom-renderers">can be swapped out or extended</a>. With very little setup it unlocks UI configurations that have been lost to time.</p>

<p>A basic example:</p>

<p>
```html</p>

<div>
  {{title}}
</div>


<pre><code>
</code></pre>

<p>const html = await renderLayout({
  layout: 'templates/layout.handlebars',
  data: {
    title: 'Hello!'
  }
})</p>

<p>console.log(html)</p>

<p>// => Outputs:
/*</p>

<div>
  Hello!
</div>


<p>*/
```</p>

<p>By adding "blocks" you can begin assembling (or adapting to) more complex layouts. Blocks represent either a path to a template or a component (with "component" meaning a React or <a href="https://preactjs.com">React-like</a> function / class component):</p>

<p>
```html
// templates/layout.handlebars</p>

<p><html>
  <head>
    <title>
      {{title}}
    </title>
  </head>
  <body
    {{{body}}}
  </body>
</html>
```
</p>

<pre><code class="js">// index.js

const html = await renderLayout({
  layout: 'templates/layout.handlebars',
  data: {
    title: 'Hello World!',
  },
  blocks: {
    body: (props) =&gt; {
      return (
        &lt;h1&gt;
          {props.title}
        &lt;/h1&gt;
      )
    }
  }
})

console.log(html)

// =&gt; Outputs:
/*
&lt;html&gt;
  &lt;head&gt;
    &lt;title&gt;Hello World!&lt;/title&gt;
  &lt;/head&gt;
  &lt;body&gt;
    &lt;h1&gt;
      Hello World!
    &lt;/h1&gt;
  &lt;/body&gt;
&lt;/html&gt;
*/
</code></pre>

<p>In Force, we're using this pattern to incrementally migrate portions of our app over to React, by taking existing block-based Jade layouts and injecting <code>ReactDOM.renderToString</code> output into them, and then rendering the layout into an HTML string that is passed down from the server and rehydrated on the client, isomorphically.</p>

<p>Our existing Backbone views take advantage of the <code>templates</code> key:</p>

<pre><code class="js">// server.js

import LoginApp from 'apps/login/LoginApp'
import { Provider } from 'react-redux'
import { StaticRouter } from 'react-router'

const html = await renderLayout({
  layout: 'templates/layout.handlebars',
  data: {
    title: 'Login / Sign-up',
  },
  templates: {
    login: 'templates/login.jade'
  },
  blocks: {
    app: (props) =&gt; (
      &lt;Provider store={store}&gt;
        &lt;StaticRouter&gt;
          &lt;LoginApp {...props} /&gt;
        &lt;/StaticRouter&gt;
      &lt;/Provider&gt;
    )
  }
})

res.send(html)
</code></pre>

<p>Similar to blocks, templates located in this object are pre-compiled and available to your components as <code>props.templates</code>.</p>

<p>Once the html has been sent over the wire, we mount it like so:</p>

<pre><code class="js">// client.js

import LoginApp from 'apps/login/LoginApp'

React.render(
  &lt;LoginApp {...window.__BOOTSTRAP__} /&gt; // Data passed down from `data` key
)
</code></pre>

<pre><code class="js">// apps/login/LoginApp.js

import React from 'react'
import Login from 'apps/login/Login'

export default function LoginApp (props) {
  const {
    templates: {
      login
    }
  } = props

  return (
    &lt;Login
      template={login}
    /&gt;
  )
}
</code></pre>

<p>During the server-side render phase existing template code will be rendered with the component, and once the component is mounted on the client <code>componentDidMount</code> will fire and the Backbone view instantiated:</p>

<p>
```js
// apps/login/Login.js</p>

<p>import React, { Component } from 'react'
import LoginBackboneView from 'apps/login/views/LoginView'</p>

<p>export default class Login extends Component {
  componentDidMount () {
    this.loginView = new LoginBackboneView()
    this.loginView.render()
  }</p>

<p>  componentWillUnmount () {
    this.loginView.remove()
  }</p>

<p>  render () {
    return (
      <div>
        <div dangerouslySetInnerHtml={{
          __html: this.props.template
        }}>
      </div>
    )
  }
}
```
</p>

<p>All of the possibilities that Stitch provides are too numerous to go over here, but check out the <a href="https://github.com/artsy/stitch#usage">documentation</a> and <a href="https://github.com/artsy/stitch/tree/master/examples">example apps</a> for more complete usage. While new, this pattern has worked quite well for us and has allowed Force to evolve alongside existing code with very little friction.</p>

<a name="Moving.Forward"></a>
<h2>Moving Forward</h2>

<p>A common thread that connects <a href="https://github.com/artsy/force">Force</a> to <a href="https://github.com/artsy/eigen">Eigen</a> (Artsy's mobile app) is an understanding that while grand re-writes will gladly remove technical debt, technical debt is not our issue. A lot of the patterns we've laid down within our apps still work for us, and many of our implementations remain sufficient to the task. What we needed was an environment where <em>incremental revolution</em> was possible, where old ideas could merge with new and evolve. In terms of Eigen, we felt the best way forward was the adoption of <a href="https://facebook.github.io/react-native/">React Native</a> -- and <a href="https://github.com/artsy/emission">Emission</a> was born. Likewise, for our web and web-based mobile apps, <a href="https://github.com/artsy/reaction">Reaction</a> is serving a similar role. Both of these projects are built with <a href="https://www.typescriptlang.org/">TypeScript</a>, and both rely heavily on functionality that our <a href="http://graphql.org/">GraphQL</a> interface <a href="https://github.com/artsy/metaphysics">Metaphysics</a> provides. But crucially, these projects <em>augment</em> our existing infrastructure; they don't replace it. They fit in with existing ideas, tools and processes that have facilitated Artsy's growth, including highly-specific domain knowledge that our engineers have built up over time.</p>

<p>In conclusion, I hope this post has provided a bit of a window into some of our processes here at Artsy for those facing similar challenges. If you want to take a deeper dive, check out the links below:</p>

<ul>
<li><a href="https://github.com/artsy/express-reloadable">express-reloadable</a></li>
<li><a href="https://github.com/artsy/stitch">stitch</a></li>
<li><a href="https://github.com/artsy/reaction">reaction</a></li>
<li><a href="https://github.com/artsy/emission">emission</a></li>
</ul>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Deploying your app on a weekly basis via fastlane + Travis CI]]></title>
    <link href="http://artsy.github.io/blog/2017/07/31/fastlane-travis-weekly-deploys/"/>
    <updated>2017-07-31T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <id>http://artsy.github.io/blog/2017/07/31/fastlane-travis-weekly-deploys</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>We have a few apps now, but one of them isn't really used by anyone other than developers. This is <a href="https://github.com/artsy/emission/tree/master/Example">our React Native host app</a>. We built our React Native components <a href="/blog/2016/08/24/On-Emission/">as a library</a> to be consumed by our other apps. Our development environment for these components is a unique app that acts as a host for the React Native components. It's effectively a long tableview.</p>

<p>This app is often updated for developers, but never deployed to beta users inside Artsy. So I automated it. Using Travis CI and fastlane. This post covers how I got that set up.</p>

<!-- more -->




<center>
  <img src="/images/fastlane-weekly/screenshot.png" width=300>
</center>


<p>As the JavaScript is continuously deployed, the native side of the app rarely gets a deploy. In order to ensure an up-to-date version of the app, I used the <a href="https://docs.travis-ci.com/user/cron-jobs/">scheduler</a> now available in Travis CI, and Circle CI. This is a perfect use-case for one-off tasks like uploading an app to Apple's Testflight on a weekly basis.</p>

<p>I wanted this to exist outside of our current CI environment for two reasons:</p>

<ul>
<li>Our CI is already <a href="https://github.com/artsy/emission/pull/263">using AppHub</a> to deploy the JavaScript parts of our React Native on a per-commit basis. It's complicated enough as it is, without adding a lot more process.</li>
<li>Our CI is currently running on Linux boxes, and so everything is fast and stable. Deploying using the main repo would force us to use macOS which would slow down our processes.</li>
</ul>


<p>The downside of this choice is that the process of uploading is not inside the main repo, and can go out of sync with the main app.</p>

<a name="Setup"></a>
<h2>Setup</h2>

<p>I created a new repo, and added the <a href="https://github.com/artsy/emission-nebula/commit/4d18a11629e097c71b9a375465c754abf45f62d6">usual LICENSE and README</a>, then started <a href="https://github.com/artsy/emission-nebula/pull/1">working on a PR</a> that added the initial support for CI to run. Here are the general steps I needed to make work:</p>

<ul>
<li>Downloading and setting up the application.</li>
<li>Ensuring signing will work.</li>
<li>Creating the build and shipping it to Testflight.</li>
<li>Notifications that it passed or succeeded.</li>
</ul>


<p>Finally I needed to document the process, which is what you're reading.</p>

<a name="Downloading.and.setting.up.the.application"></a>
<h2>Downloading and setting up the application</h2>

<p>My initial thoughts were to use a submodule, but that option provides little advantage over cloning the repo itself so it's done inline. Our dependencies for the app live in Rubygems (fastlane/CocoaPods), NPM (React Native) and CocoaPods (Artsy Mobile code), so I use the <code>before_install</code> and <code>before_script</code> section of the <code>.travis.yml</code> to set up our dependencies:</p>

<pre><code class="yml"># Use a Mac build please
language: objective-c
osx_image: xcode8.2

# Ensure that fastlane is at the latest version
before_install:
- bundle update

# Let fastlane set up the other dependency managers
before_script:
- bundle exec fastlane setup

# Separate fastlane lanes so that they can be individually
# tested one by one during development
script:
- bundle exec fastlane validate_env_vars
- bundle exec fastlane ci_deploy
</code></pre>

<p>Note the <code>- bundle update</code>. As fastlane works against unofficial iTunes connect which is always changing, it's safer to always use the most recent release.</p>

<a name="Ensuring.signing.will.work."></a>
<h2>Ensuring signing will work.</h2>

<p>This one is a bit tricker, luckily I've already set up one of our apps to use <a href="/blog/2017/04/05/what-is-fastlane-match/">fastlane match</a> and I can re-use that infrastructure. As it is a private repo, Travis did not have access to clone the repo. I fixed this by creating an access token for a user with read-only access to our match-codesigning repo, then exposed this as a private environment variable in CI which the Matchfile uses. E.g.</p>

<pre><code class="ruby">git_url "https://#{ENV['GITHUB_SUBMODULES_USER']}@github.com/artsy/mobile_fastlane_match"

# Instead of 
# git_url "https://github.com/artsy/mobile_fastlane_match"
</code></pre>

<p>This is one of the highlights on fastlane's choice in building a DSL that which sits above a real programming language, you give users a lot of flexibility.</p>

<p>Next up, I added a fastlane lane for code signing, and keychain setup. This just calls two setup functions.</p>

<pre><code class="ruby">lane :setup_signing do
  setup_travis

  match(type: 'appstore')
end
</code></pre>

<a name="Creating.the.build.and.shipping.it.to.Testflight"></a>
<h2>Creating the build and shipping it to Testflight</h2>

<p>This is handled by <a href="https://github.com/fastlane/fastlane/tree/master/gym">fastlane gym</a> at the start of the main lane.</p>

<pre><code class="ruby"># The main job for fastlane in this repo, you can run this on your computer
# You can run it via `bundle exec fastlane ship`
lane :ship do
  # We were having issues with building an a few folders deep.
  # The /Pods bit is because we can rely on it being there, see
  # this link: https://docs.fastlane.tools/advanced/#directory-behavior
  #
  Dir.chdir('../emission/Example/Pods') do
    gym workspace: 'Emission.xcworkspace',
        configuration: 'Deploy',
        scheme: 'Emission'
  end

  # [...]
end
</code></pre>

<p>It uses a scheme for deploys, which prioritises using AppHub over a local React Native server. Gym handles a lot of CLI ugliness for us, and works well.</p>

<p>Sending the app to Testflight involves a a few lines:</p>

<pre><code class="ruby"># Get the last 10 lines of the CHANGELOG for Testflight
changelog = '../emission/CHANGELOG.md'
upcoming_release_notes = File.read(changelog).split("\n### ").first

# Ship to testflight
pilot(changelog: upcoming_release_notes)
</code></pre>

<p>This lets the deploy process figure out what the latest release version is, and how many builds have shipped for that version. Then those can be used to set the build version and create a tag associated with it.</p>

<p><a href="https://github.com/fastlane/fastlane/tree/master/pilot">fastlane pilot</a> is used to send off the compiled build to Testflight.</p>

<a name="Keeping.track.of.deploys"></a>
<h2>Keeping track of deploys</h2>

<p>I don't know when we'll need it today, but it's always good to be able to go back and see what code lines up to every release. To do this I have a few lines of Ruby that creates a tag inside the original Emission repo.</p>

<pre><code class="ruby"># Do a tag, we use a http git remote so we can have push access
# as the default remote for travis is read-only. This needs to be
# inside the emission repo, instead of our own.
Dir.chdir('../emission/Example/') do
  tag = "deploy-#{latest_version}-#{build_version}"
  add_git_tag(key: tag)

  if ENV['GITHUB_SUBMODULES_USER']
    writable_remote = "https://#{ENV['GITHUB_SUBMODULES_USER']}@github.com/artsy/emission.git"
    sh "git remote add http #{writable_remote}"
  else
    sh 'git remote add http https://github.com/artsy/emission.git'
  end
  push_git_tags(remote: 'http')
end
</code></pre>

<a name="Notifications.that.it.passed.or.succeeded."></a>
<h2>Notifications that it passed or succeeded.</h2>

<p>This was easy, I created a new slack inbound web-hook and added that as an environment variable. Then when a build passes we post a notification that there is a new version for everyone in Slack, if the lane fails then it will also post to slack. To ensure we keep on top of it, during development this was commented out.</p>

<pre><code class="ruby"># If the weekly task fails, then ship a message
error do |_, exception|
   slack message: "Error Deploying Emission: #{exception}",
         success: false,
         payload: { Output: exception.error_info.to_s }
end
</code></pre>

<p>That wraps up setting up the CI. Once you've confirmed everything has worked, you can add the scheduler inside Travis and expect to see a slack notification in a week.</p>

<p>By the end of the process, our <code>Fastfile</code> looked like:</p>

<pre><code class="ruby"># This is documented in the Artsy Blog: 
# http://artsy.github.io/blog/2017/07/31/fastlane-travis-weekly-deploys/
lane :setup do
  Dir.chdir('..') do
    sh 'rm -rf emission' if Dir.exist? 'Emission'
    sh 'git clone https://github.com/artsy/emission.git'
    Dir.chdir('emission') do
      sh '. ~/.nvm/nvm.sh &amp;&amp; nvm use &amp;&amp; npm install yarn --global &amp;&amp; yarn install'
    end

    Dir.chdir('emission/Example') do
      sh 'pod repo update'
      sh 'pod install'
    end
    stamp_plist
  end
end

# Lets the CI run a bunch of jobs, and share ENV vars between them
lane :ci_deploy do
  setup_signing
  stamp_plist
  ship
end

# The main job for fastlane in this repo, you can run this on your computer
# You can run it via `bundle exec fastlane ship`
lane :ship do
  # We were having issues with building an a few folders deep.
  # The /Pods bit is because we can rely on it being there, see
  # this link: https://docs.fastlane.tools/advanced/#directory-behavior
  #
  Dir.chdir('../emission/Example/Pods') do
    gym(workspace: 'Emission.xcworkspace',
        configuration: 'Deploy',
        scheme: 'Emission')
  end

  # Get the last 10 lines of the CHANGELOG for Testflight
  changelog = '../emission/CHANGELOG.md'
  upcoming_release_notes = File.read(changelog).split("\n### ").first

  # Ship to testflight
  pilot(changelog: upcoming_release_notes)

  # Log into iTunes connect, get the latest version of the app we shipped, and how many builds we've sent
  Spaceship::Tunes.login(ENV['FASTLANE_USERNAME'], ENV['FASTLANE_PASSWORD'])
  app = Spaceship::Tunes::Application.find('net.artsy.Emission')
  latest_version = app.build_trains.keys.sort.last
  train = app.build_trains[latest_version]
  build_version = train.builds.count + 1

  # Do a tag, we use a http git remote so we can have push access
  # as the default remote for travis is read-only. This needs to be
  # inside the emission repo, instead of our own.
  Dir.chdir('../emission/Example/') do
    tag = "deploy-#{latest_version}-#{build_version}"
    add_git_tag(key: tag)

    if ENV['GITHUB_SUBMODULES_USER']
      writable_remote = "https://#{ENV['GITHUB_SUBMODULES_USER']}@github.com/artsy/emission.git"
      sh "git remote add http #{writable_remote}"
    else
      sh 'git remote add http https://github.com/artsy/emission.git'
    end

    push_git_tags(remote: 'http')
  end

  slack message: 'There is a new Emission beta available on Testflight.',
        payload: {
          'Version' =&gt; latest_version,
          "What's new" =&gt; upcoming_release_notes
        },
        default_payloads: []
end

# In case you need to update the signing profiles for this app
lane :update_signing do
  match(type: 'appstore')
end

# Used by CI, will not sneakily update (the CI only has read-only access to the repo anyway)
lane :setup_signing do
  setup_travis
  match(type: 'appstore')
end

# Minor plist modifications
lane :stamp_plist do
  plist = 'emission/Example/Emission/Info.plist'

  # Increment build number to current date
  build_number = Time.new.strftime('%Y.%m.%d.%H')
  `/usr/libexec/PlistBuddy -c "Set CFBundleVersion #{build_number}" "#{plist}"`
end

# Mainly so we don't forget to include these vars in the future
lane :validate_env_vars do
  unless ENV['FASTLANE_USERNAME'] &amp;&amp; ENV['FASTLANE_PASSWORD'] &amp;&amp; ENV['MATCH_PASSWORD']
    raise 'You need to set FASTLANE_USERNAME, FASTLANE_PASSWORD and MATCH_PASSWORD in your environment'
  end

  unless ENV['SLACK_URL']
    raise "You need to set SLACK_URL (#{ENV['SLACK_URL']}) in your environment."
  end
end

# If the weekly task fails, then ship a message, a success would also send
error do |_, exception|
  slack(message: "Error Deploying Emission: #{exception}",
        success: false,
        payload: { Output: exception.error_info.to_s })
end
</code></pre>

<p>Automatically deploying is a good pattern for encouraging more deploys of an app which has only been deployed once. It's a pattern we could also move to in some of our other apps too, if it feels good. If you're interested in if something has changed since this post was authored, the repo is here: https://github.com/artsy/emission-nebula so you can read out the Fastfile and we'll answer questions you have inside GitHub issues on it.</p>

<p>The most annoying part about building deployment changes are that an iteration takes ~20 minutes, so make sure you also have another (easily interrupted) task to do at the same time.</p>

<p>The second most annoying is that it took months to eventually get this right - so I owe Felix Krause a big thanks for sitting down and pairing with me, we figuring out that <code>xcodebuild</code> can create empty archive issues when you run projects that have the xcproject/xcworkspace a few levels deep.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
