<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: mobile | Artsy Engineering]]></title>
  <link href="http://artsy.github.io/blog/categories/mobile/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://artsy.github.io/"/>
  <updated>2020-12-17T22:48:53+00:00</updated>
  <id>http://artsy.github.io/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Becoming Mobile First]]></title>
    <link href="http://artsy.github.io/blog/2020/09/29/becoming-mobile-first-at-artsy/"/>
    <updated>2020-09-29T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <id>http://artsy.github.io/blog/2020/09/29/becoming-mobile-first-at-artsy</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>It was a Wednesday, mid-summer 2019. I don't know which Wednesday specifically, but I know that it was <em>a</em>
Wednesday because I was attending Artsy's weekly all-hands meeting. Two hundred colleagues were also there (many
dialing in remotely) and we were all listening to
<a href="https://files.artsy.net/documents/artsy-names-new-ceo.pdf">Artsy's new CEO</a> talk about the company's direction.
Mike Steib had only been around for a few months at that point, getting to know the business. He was talking about
the product direction, and I was listening intently.</p>

<p>With Artsy's iOS app, I knew there were only really two directions we could go. As I listened, I reflected on how
we had gotten here.</p>

<!-- more -->


<p>When I joined Artsy in 2014, I joined the Mobile Team. It was an amazing team. While we were called the "mobile"
team, we only worked on Artsy's iOS apps and not the mobile website.</p>

<p>By 2016, Artsy Engineering had grown to the size that having only a "mobile team" and a "web team" was no longer
working well. We dissolved both teams and distributed the engineers into
<a href="https://artsy.github.io/blog/2016/03/28/artsy-engineering-organization-stack/">new product teams</a>, focused on
vertical aspects of Artsy's business. Auctions. Partner Success. Editorial. And so on. The idea was that each team
would have total autonomy over building products to support their slice of the business, and each would have the
engineering and design resources to build new features across both our web and iOS canvases.</p>

<p>That structure worked well, and continues to work well today (we have continued re-organizing ourselves into new
teams to better meet business goals). But once we dissolved the mobile team, there was no longer anyone looking at
our iOS software holistically. The app had become a series of silos – each silo was internally consistent, but
distinct from each other. Often each silo was written in distinct programming languages (we had also started
adopting React Native).</p>

<p>New iOS technologies had been created by Apple, but our teams weren't taking full advantage of them. We would
update to support the latest versions of Xcode and iOS in the free time between other tickets. It wasn't ideal. Of
the <a href="https://github.com/artsy/mobile">five original members of the Mobile Team</a>, everyone else had moved on except
me.</p>

<p>As a product, the app was languishing.</p>

<p>Yet despite this, it was also hugely popular among our users and very important to Artsy's business. Art collectors
love our app! It gets a large percentage of our total sessions. Also, users place an outsized number of auction
bids and artwork inquiries using our app relative to the number of sessions on our website. In fact, the highest
value artwork transaction <em>ever</em> to take place on Artsy was made on an iPad, running software that I helped build.
I'm still pretty proud of that.</p>

<p>So, Wednesday all-hands. I stood there, not sure of what would happen next. I could see Artsy either making a
massive investment in the app, or I could see Artsy cutting its losses and focusing on the software that we already
knew how to build. Which direction we took largely depended on this new CEO, who was now standing in front of us
all and describing the direction Artsy's product would take next.</p>

<a name="The.Dream"></a>
<h2>The Dream</h2>

<p>Mike said something that caused a lot of raised eyebrows in the crowd. People were excited. <em>I</em> was excited.
Artsy's product organization would shift to adopt a "mobile-first strategy."</p>

<p>Someone asked "does this mean the app will reach feature parity with Artsy's website?"</p>

<p>Mike responded: "No. It means that features are going to launch <em>first</em> on the app. If anything, it's the <em>website</em>
that will be catching up <em>to the app</em>."</p>

<p>I was kind of blown away! I mean, this had been the spirit of our original re-org in 2016, but that hadn't really
materialized. The app had continued to trail the website. At most, only one product team was ever building new
features for the app (usually which ever team I happened to be on). Shifting to this mobile-first strategy would be
a <em>massive</em> undertaking, but I was keen.</p>

<p>In August, an email landed in my inbox from Artsy's head of software. He wanted to spin up a new team to focus on
the app: the team would be responsible for supporting Artsy's new mobile-first product strategy. He wanted to know
what I thought, and he wanted to know if I was interested in leading the team.</p>

<p>Honestly, it was a dream come true.</p>

<p><img src="/images/2020-09-29-becoming-mobile-first-at-artsy/rfc.png" alt="Screenshot of the RFC for creating the Mobile Experience team" /></p>

<p>Here we are, a year later. This is the story of how Artsy created its Mobile Experience team. How we recovered a
languishing iOS app. How engineers helped shift the product organization to a mobile-first product strategy. And
how Artsy grew from <em>sometimes</em> having <em>a</em> team working on the app, to usually having <em>every</em> team working on it.</p>

<p><img src="/images/2020-09-29-becoming-mobile-first-at-artsy/faq.png" alt="Another screenshot of the RFC for creating the Mobile Experience team, describing frequently asked questions" /></p>

<a name="Getting.Our.Bearings"></a>
<h2>Getting Our Bearings</h2>

<p>When Artsy created its new Mobile Experience team, we were already resource-constrained and so the new team would
need to be nimble. We had three full-time engineers (myself as tech lead, and two others), assisted by a designer,
product manager, and data analyst, who would each be spending only half their work time on the Mobile Experience
team. We needed to be scrappy. I'm really proud of the work that that early team accomplished, and I look back
fondly on those first few months working with Sam, Joanna, David, Kieran, and Ani.</p>

<p>The first thing we did was define our own mandate. What was this team responsible for? What was it <em>not</em>
responsible for? "Mobile Experience" is pretty vague, and we had to answer a lot of upfront questions. Would we be
responsible for <em>all</em> of Artsy's iOS software? No, just the main collector app. Would we be responsible for Artsy's
mobile website? No, that's too far-reaching. What about Android? Well, yes, eventually...</p>

<p>After we decided on our mandate, the next step was to get really familiar with the existing app. We storyboarded
out all the existing screens and their connections to one another.</p>

<p><img src="/images/2020-09-29-becoming-mobile-first-at-artsy/walkthrough.png" alt="Screenshot of all the screens in our app laid out to discuss" /></p>

<p><img src="/images/2020-09-29-becoming-mobile-first-at-artsy/brainstorm.png" alt="Screenshot of a brainstorm for app ideas" /></p>

<p>No one on our team had complete knowledge of every screen in the app, not even me, so exploring it together was a
great way to uncover what needed immediate attention. One example was our partner page, which displayed information
to our users about Artsy's partners: galleries, museums, auction houses, etc. We learned that the app actually used
an ancient web view, and it didn't even show the partner's <em>artworks</em>. The artworks! Probably the most important
thing for it to do!</p>

<p><img src="/images/2020-09-29-becoming-mobile-first-at-artsy/old_partner.png" alt="Screenshot of a presentation showing the old partner page" /></p>

<p><img src="/images/2020-09-29-becoming-mobile-first-at-artsy/new_partner.png" alt="Screenshot of a presentation showing the new partner page, which looks much nicer" /></p>

<p>This is where "being scrappy" started to take root. Usually when developing new features, Artsy designers iterate
on a design before we plan on execution, then we implement, test, and deploy. The nice part of replacing something
that was <em>obviously broken</em> was that we didn't feel beholden to this usual process; whatever we built would be
better than what we had. One engineer and our designer started the new partner page with a quick pencil sketch,
using the app's existing UI abstractions to design something that we could quickly build. Once we had a prototype,
the engineer and designer iterated. The whole project took only about three weeks.</p>

<a name="Early.Wins"></a>
<h2>Early Wins</h2>

<p>Learning about the app itself was critical, but equally important was learning about how our users <em>used</em> the app.
We scheduled user interviews and, in the mean time, looked into our anonymized user analytics. Our data analyst
found a few representative sessions and we walked through each action that a user took. One big lesson here was how
much our app users relied on the app's search feature, which was still written in Objective-C and hadn't been
updated in a long time. We found that users would often search for the same query several times in the same
session. For example, users would search for "banksy", wander off exploring some art, and then return to search for
"bansky" again. And again. And again.</p>

<p>Our search implementation didn't show users their own recent searches, which would have greatly reduced the amount
of friction users experienced while exploring the art world in the app. Our other engineer took point working with
our designer to migrate the app's search to React Native. We also added some other features to our search page,
like adding entity subtitles so users would know if the result they were tapping on was an artwork, and artist, a
gallery, and so on. The whole project took about a month to complete, and we have continued to iterate on the app's
search.</p>

<p><img src="/images/2020-09-29-becoming-mobile-first-at-artsy/new_search.png" alt="Screenshot of a presentation showing the new search" /></p>

<p>In early conversations with company leadership, the Mobile Experience team settled on an... interesting strategy to
what we would prioritize. Our mission was "to make the app not suck." This might seem harsh! But it came from a
place of caring. We knew how much better the app could be and we were motivated to make that a reality. In the
spring of 2020, the team felt like we had reached a point where the app no longer "sucked" – our goal now was "to
make the app amazing."</p>

<p>During 2020, we made a lot of changes to the app. We had built a new home page, a profile tab for users, granular
push notification settings, Sign In with Apple, and more.</p>

<p><img src="/images/2020-09-29-becoming-mobile-first-at-artsy/new_home.png" alt="Screenshot of a presentation showing the new home page" /></p>

<p>It was really exciting to show off our progress to the rest of the company at our monthly Demo Day, especially in
those early months. The product team makes up only a quarter of our company and it was really cool to hear gallery
liaisons complementing our new partner page, or sales people complementing our refreshed home feed. I think that
people had gotten so used to the app not moving much at all that this sudden high velocity of development was as
exciting for them as it was for us.</p>

<a name="Setting.Up.Others.To.Succeed"></a>
<h2>Setting Up Others To Succeed</h2>

<p>Artsy's goal for the Mobile Experience team was explicitly <em>not</em> to centralize all our iOS feature development, and
so our mandate included much more that just working on iOS software ourselves. We wanted to sit between a typical
product team and a "platform" team, to provide infrastructure and assistance so any team at Artsy could develop
their own iOS feature. This was a big challenge, and required work at the individual and team levels.</p>

<p>The first step was apparent before we even created the Mobile Experience team. Artsy Engineering runs skills
surveys every six months, and we knew that building iOS software in React Native was something Artsy engineers
weren't really familiar with, but that they really wanted to learn more about. I worked with the Engineering team's
Peer Learning Working Group to design a curriculum – big shout out to Christina and Adam for their help here!</p>

<p><a href="https://artsy.github.io/blog/2019/12/03/ios-learning-group/">The iOS Learning Group took four weeks to deliver four lessons</a>.
The learners were mostly web engineers, so I emphasized the familiar parts of writing React Native software. I also
provided weekly office hours for learners to get assistance with homework. I even stretched my wings as an
educator, developing new skills around curriculum design and delivery. After the course, learners responded
positively to the experience and we have integrated lessons learned from the iOS Learning Group into subsequent
peer learning groups.</p>

<a name="Aligning.Product.Releases"></a>
<h2>Aligning Product Releases</h2>

<p>Now that engineers had a solid grasp of how to build software in our application, we could re-align our product
development process around iOS. I can't speak to the design side of this, but from a product perspective the most
critical milestone was defining a regular 2-week app release cadence. Let me explain.</p>

<p>Prior to the Mobile Experience team, we released the app pretty irregularly. We would release whenever we had
something big to release, basically. There are two major flaws with that approach. The first problem is that since
each release was bigger, each release was scarier. No one really felt confident releasing app updates. The second
problem was that large pieces of work tended to get coupled together. This came to a head last summer when we were
blocked from releasing an redesigned artwork view because we were waiting for a major overhaul to Artsy's GraphQL
API to be completed. Without guidance or structure, different teams were building big projects and both had their
changes in our default branch – it was a bit chaotic.</p>

<p>These two problems are incidental to how we worked at Artsy but there is another, inherent problem to developing
mobile apps:
<a href="https://artsy.github.io/blog/2020/03/02/ios-deploys-super-weird-totally-normal/">deploying iOS software is weird</a>.
Engineers, designers, and product managers at Artsy are used to being able to quickly and cheaply deploy software
to the <em>web</em>, not the App Store. iOS software is deployed to our user's hardware, not to servers we control, which
introduces the possibility that users might not upgrade. Software we shipped years ago is still being run today –
we have the analytics to prove it. Not to mention that every app update has to go through Apple's App Store review
process. Getting our product team aligned on a release schedule might also help us get aligned on the weirdness of
deploying iOS software.</p>

<center>
<blockquote class="twitter-tweet"><p lang="en" dir="ltr">iOS developers! I have a question for you. I hear a lot about teams releasing app updates on a 2-week cadence, to increase user confidence/App Store ranking/team morale/etc.<br><br>Have any teams shared their experiences with this? Bonus points for any quantitative data. Thanks!! 🤗</p>&mdash; Ash Furrow (@ashfurrow) <a href="https://twitter.com/ashfurrow/status/1184845989510811649?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">October 17, 2019</a></blockquote> <script async src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"></script>
</center>


<p><br /></p>

<p>As the Mobile Experience team formed, I reached out to other mobile teams to find out about how they structured
regular releases. <a href="https://twitter.com/Cform">Matt Greenwell</a> from BuzzFeed was really helpful in particular,
outlining their experience of the pros and cons of a regular release cadence. We implemented a two-week release
cadence so that all product teams could align their own feature development and testing around this predictable
structure. We also created documentation for teams to hide their in-progress work behind feature flags. And
finally, we refined our app QA process; teams would QA their own features and bug fixes while the Mobile Experience
team would used a QA script to test the app <em>generally</em>, every other Monday, before submitting an update to the App
Store.</p>

<p><img src="/images/2020-09-29-becoming-mobile-first-at-artsy/cadence.png" alt="Calendar describing our cadence on an example sprint" /></p>

<a name="Making.Deploys.Not.Scary"></a>
<h2>Making Deploys Not Scary</h2>

<p>To further help teams get into the habit of developing and releasing iOS software often, we created nightly betas.
We also adopted a clever idea from our web colleagues: deploy blocks. In case of a technical reason to not release
a beta, we create a block and the CI job that deploys the beta would fail with a descriptive message. This reduced
a lot of chatter in Slack where engineers would ask "could I make a new beta?" Instead, engineers usually just wait
for the nightly beta. And if they get impatient, they now default to action (their beta deploy will fail if we set
up a block).</p>

<p>All of this was automated through <a href="https://fastlane.tools">fastlane</a> on our CI provider. We had been using fastlane
for a long time at Artsy, but the Mobile Experience team took the time to share knowledge of how it worked. Any
engineer at Artsy can now make a beta (<code>make deploy</code>) or promote the latest beta to an App Store submission
(<code>make promote_beta_to_submission</code>).</p>

<p>We deploy more often and, consequently, each deploy is less scary. And everyone is aware of the need to hide
in-progress work behind feature flags. At this point, updates to our app are mundane, predictable, and boring. Just
the way we like them.</p>

<a name="Being.Generous.With.Our.Time"></a>
<h2>Being Generous With Our Time</h2>

<p>Our QA and deploy process touches on something I want to go into more detail about, which is how the Mobile
Experience team helped support other product teams. I described earlier how Mobile Experience sits somewhere
between a normal product team and a platform team, and we leveraged that to our advantage. It would have been easy
to become primarily a supportive team, and leave feature development up to others. However, that would leave us
unaware of how day-to-day development <em>feels</em> in the app. We own the platform, and that includes the developer
experience. By sitting in this ambiguous in-between state, we stayed aware of both the needs of everyday
developers, and the needs of our platform.</p>

<p>I would encourage engineers from other teams to ask us for help, which led to a lot of pairing sessions. To be
honest, I think it probably interfered with our productivity, but it was worth it. A half hour of my time spent
pairing with a colleague might save them three hours of banging their head against Xcode. But it's not the time
saved that I care about, it's the head-banging. I want engineers at Artsy to feel empowered to build their own iOS
software, and that's only going to happen if they feel comfortable and supported.</p>

<p>When the Galleries team kicked off their ambitious Viewing Rooms project, we helped them get started by lending an
engineer to them for a few sprints. When they ran into problems, we were generous with our time by pairing with
them. When they were nearing completion, we helped them test the new feature. This all culminated in a smooth
release.</p>

<p><img src="/images/2020-09-29-becoming-mobile-first-at-artsy/new_loader.png" alt="Screenshot of a presentation showing the new home page's new loading indicator" /></p>

<p>Speaking of Developer Experience, we took a keen interest in standardizing our best practices and modernizing the
codebase. We
<a href="https://github.com/artsy/eigen/blob/dc81bbc9cd33d51d10054a6c57e61a1bd0ee3e75/docs/preferred_practices.md">documented how we wanted the app's codebase to look</a>
and set up
<a href="https://github.com/artsy/eigen/blob/dc81bbc9cd33d51d10054a6c57e61a1bd0ee3e75/tslint-rules/useWrappedComponentsRule.js">processes like lint rules</a>
to encourage developers to follow our best practices. We also invited any engineer at Artsy to join our
twice-weekly Knowledge Share meetings (I'll discuss these in-depth shortly). We looked for bottle necks in the
development process and found many problems, which we addressed.
<a href="https://github.com/artsy/eigen/pull/3022">We combined the Native iOS and React Native repositories</a> (which had
historically been separated). <a href="https://github.com/artsy/eigen/pull/3105">We overhauled the CI configuration</a> to
leverage heavy caching – average build times dropped from fifteen minutes to less than five.
<a href="https://github.com/artsy/eigen/pull/3210">And we adopted stricter TypeScript compiler settings</a> so that engineers
would be forced to deal with nullability and other causes of bugs. (Hey, sometimes you need a carrot and sometimes
you need a stick.)</p>

<p>The React Native community has grown a lot since 2016. If Artsy were to begin our adoption of React Native today,
we would be really well-supported by a community that has defined best practices, documented standard approaches to
problems, and a consolidated opinion on what a React Native codebase should "feel" like. None of that existed in
2016, and our early architectural decisions don't really reflect contemporary best practices. We continue working
to bring our codebase closer to resembling a fresh project created with <code>react-native init</code>.</p>

<p>I'm extraordinarily happy with how things have shaped up, and in the direction we continue to move. This is all an
ongoing process, and should remain an ongoing process. For example, engineers were still facing a bottleneck with
core parts of our app's routing logic that were in Objective-C, so we recently
<a href="https://github.com/artsy/eigen/pull/3771">moved all routing to TypeScript</a>. Not only does moving code out of
Objective-C make it easier for everyone to build, but it also ladders up to a cross-platform Artsy app.</p>

<p>We still have older practices in the app that we want to migrate away from, like testing with Enzyme. But overall,
things are looking good!</p>

<iframe width="100%" height="400" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/IEn2_WSKFHw" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture" allowfullscreen></iframe>


<a name="Knowledge.Shares"></a>
<h2>Knowledge Shares</h2>

<p>We achieved most of these big, infrastructural changes in meetings called <em>Knowledge Shares</em>, which I mentioned
earlier. I should write a dedicated blog post on these (update: <a href="/blog/2020/12/09/share-your-knowledge/">I did write one</a>), but in short: Knowledge Shares are a <em>structured</em> time to
facilitate <em>unstructured learning</em>. Anyone can bring a topic to Knowledge Share, from a ticket that they're stuck
on to an idea they have to a neat trick they recently learned. We set aside these two hours a week to discuss
whatever the team wants, and we don't only invite engineers.</p>

<p>New feature designs, product roadmaps, and data analyses are often brought up by our non-engineering colleagues; we
discuss these at the beginning of the meetings to make sure everyone's time is respected. Throughout the week,
someone will raise a question in Slack. Before we had Knowledge Share meetings, we might schedule a dedicated
half-hour meeting to discussing this question. But instead, we now say "alright let's chat about this at tomorrow's
KS." Usually the discussion lasts a lot less than a half hour, so we save time and needless context-switching.</p>

<p>Knowledge Shares are also a manifestation of my philosophy of tech leadership, which is this: none of us have built
an Artsy before, so instead of optimizing for building an Artsy, let's optimize for <em>learning</em> how to build an
Artsy. The best Artsy we can build. And as a natural byproduct, an Artsy gets built. But it's the <em>learning</em> that
is treated as the paramount goal.</p>

<p>Like I said, I owe you a whole blog post on Knowledge Share meetings. I hope I have conveyed how important these
scheduled "structured unstructured learning" times have been for us.</p>

<a name="The.Results"></a>
<h2>The Results</h2>

<p>So where does that leave us? It's been a year and change, where are we now? Well I'm happy to say that we've made a
huge impact. We've gone from only having (at most) one product team writing iOS software at a time to having nearly
<em>every</em> product team building iOS software. Artsy is through the woods of its transition to a mobile-first product
strategy. We still have a ways to go, but it feels like we have finally realized the dream we had in 2016 where
every team is fully equipped and empowered to deliver on their own business goals, across all of Artsy's canvasses.</p>

<p>Our App Store ranking has shot through the roof – not surprising considering our "make it not suck" and then "make
it amazing" approach. Artsy's iOS app rating now sits at a stout 4.7.</p>

<p><img src="/images/2020-09-29-becoming-mobile-first-at-artsy/ratings.png" alt="Screenshot of a graph showing an increasing average App Store rating" /></p>

<p>We've also started tracking our iOS developer experience within Artsy. We know exactly where we still need work
because we ask our engineers where they need support.</p>

<p>It's taken a mammoth effort, and there's so much more that I could talk about, but this blog post is long enough
already! Looking at the work we've done, the ways we've done it, and the results of our effort... I feel ecstatic.</p>

<a name="Next.Steps"></a>
<h2>Next Steps</h2>

<p>All that said, Artsy's product team is currently embarking on another reorganization. With so much technical and
product debt paid off, Artsy has evolved past the need for a dedicated Mobile Experience team. It's bittersweet,
but I'm proud to say that the new Collector Experience team is about to be born. Our team will continue to own the
mobile platform, including its holistic user experience and day-to-day developer experience, but we'll have an
expanded mandate. That mandate includes a cross-platform Artsy app that will work for collectors on Android as well
as iOS.</p>

<p>The Mobile Experience team has grown, too. Since we started last year with just a few engineers and limited product
support, we now boast a full roster of engineers and product support. I want to thank everyone on the team,
currently: David, Sam, Brian, Mike, Brittney, Pavlos, and Mounir. You have made the past year an incredibly
rewarding experience for me as I learn the ropes of technical leadership. I'm so proud of what we've built together
and I'm excited for what the new Collector Experience team is going to do next!</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Deploying your app on a weekly basis via fastlane + Travis CI]]></title>
    <link href="http://artsy.github.io/blog/2017/07/31/fastlane-travis-weekly-deploys/"/>
    <updated>2017-07-31T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <id>http://artsy.github.io/blog/2017/07/31/fastlane-travis-weekly-deploys</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>We have a few apps now, but one of them isn't really used by anyone other than developers. This is <a href="https://github.com/artsy/emission/tree/master/Example">our React Native host app</a>. We built our React Native components <a href="/blog/2016/08/24/On-Emission/">as a library</a> to be consumed by our other apps. Our development environment for these components is a unique app that acts as a host for the React Native components. It's effectively a long tableview.</p>

<p>This app is often updated for developers, but never deployed to beta users inside Artsy. So I automated it. Using Travis CI and fastlane. This post covers how I got that set up.</p>

<!-- more -->




<center>
  <img src="/images/fastlane-weekly/screenshot.png" width=300>
</center>


<p>As the JavaScript is continuously deployed, the native side of the app rarely gets a deploy. In order to ensure an up-to-date version of the app, I used the <a href="https://docs.travis-ci.com/user/cron-jobs/">scheduler</a> now available in Travis CI, and Circle CI. This is a perfect use-case for one-off tasks like uploading an app to Apple's Testflight on a weekly basis.</p>

<p>I wanted this to exist outside of our current CI environment for two reasons:</p>

<ul>
<li>Our CI is already <a href="https://github.com/artsy/emission/pull/263">using AppHub</a> to deploy the JavaScript parts of our React Native on a per-commit basis. It's complicated enough as it is, without adding a lot more process.</li>
<li>Our CI is currently running on Linux boxes, and so everything is fast and stable. Deploying using the main repo would force us to use macOS which would slow down our processes.</li>
</ul>


<p>The downside of this choice is that the process of uploading is not inside the main repo, and can go out of sync with the main app.</p>

<a name="Setup"></a>
<h2>Setup</h2>

<p>I created a new repo, and added the <a href="https://github.com/artsy/emission-nebula/commit/4d18a11629e097c71b9a375465c754abf45f62d6">usual LICENSE and README</a>, then started <a href="https://github.com/artsy/emission-nebula/pull/1">working on a PR</a> that added the initial support for CI to run. Here are the general steps I needed to make work:</p>

<ul>
<li>Downloading and setting up the application.</li>
<li>Ensuring signing will work.</li>
<li>Creating the build and shipping it to Testflight.</li>
<li>Notifications that it passed or succeeded.</li>
</ul>


<p>Finally I needed to document the process, which is what you're reading.</p>

<a name="Downloading.and.setting.up.the.application"></a>
<h2>Downloading and setting up the application</h2>

<p>My initial thoughts were to use a submodule, but that option provides little advantage over cloning the repo itself so it's done inline. Our dependencies for the app live in Rubygems (fastlane/CocoaPods), NPM (React Native) and CocoaPods (Artsy Mobile code), so I use the <code>before_install</code> and <code>before_script</code> section of the <code>.travis.yml</code> to set up our dependencies:</p>

<pre><code class="yml"># Use a Mac build please
language: objective-c
osx_image: xcode8.2

# Ensure that fastlane is at the latest version
before_install:
- bundle update

# Let fastlane set up the other dependency managers
before_script:
- bundle exec fastlane setup

# Separate fastlane lanes so that they can be individually
# tested one by one during development
script:
- bundle exec fastlane validate_env_vars
- bundle exec fastlane ci_deploy
</code></pre>

<p>Note the <code>- bundle update</code>. As fastlane works against unofficial iTunes connect which is always changing, it's safer to always use the most recent release.</p>

<a name="Ensuring.signing.will.work."></a>
<h2>Ensuring signing will work.</h2>

<p>This one is a bit tricker, luckily I've already set up one of our apps to use <a href="/blog/2017/04/05/what-is-fastlane-match/">fastlane match</a> and I can re-use that infrastructure. As it is a private repo, Travis did not have access to clone the repo. I fixed this by creating an access token for a user with read-only access to our match-codesigning repo, then exposed this as a private environment variable in CI which the Matchfile uses. E.g.</p>

<pre><code class="ruby">git_url "https://#{ENV['GITHUB_SUBMODULES_USER']}@github.com/artsy/mobile_fastlane_match"

# Instead of 
# git_url "https://github.com/artsy/mobile_fastlane_match"
</code></pre>

<p>This is one of the highlights on fastlane's choice in building a DSL that which sits above a real programming language, you give users a lot of flexibility.</p>

<p>Next up, I added a fastlane lane for code signing, and keychain setup. This just calls two setup functions.</p>

<pre><code class="ruby">lane :setup_signing do
  setup_travis

  match(type: 'appstore')
end
</code></pre>

<a name="Creating.the.build.and.shipping.it.to.Testflight"></a>
<h2>Creating the build and shipping it to Testflight</h2>

<p>This is handled by <a href="https://github.com/fastlane/fastlane/tree/master/gym">fastlane gym</a> at the start of the main lane.</p>

<pre><code class="ruby"># The main job for fastlane in this repo, you can run this on your computer
# You can run it via `bundle exec fastlane ship`
lane :ship do
  # We were having issues with building an a few folders deep.
  # The /Pods bit is because we can rely on it being there, see
  # this link: https://docs.fastlane.tools/advanced/#directory-behavior
  #
  Dir.chdir('../emission/Example/Pods') do
    gym workspace: 'Emission.xcworkspace',
        configuration: 'Deploy',
        scheme: 'Emission'
  end

  # [...]
end
</code></pre>

<p>It uses a scheme for deploys, which prioritises using AppHub over a local React Native server. Gym handles a lot of CLI ugliness for us, and works well.</p>

<p>Sending the app to Testflight involves a a few lines:</p>

<pre><code class="ruby"># Get the last 10 lines of the CHANGELOG for Testflight
changelog = '../emission/CHANGELOG.md'
upcoming_release_notes = File.read(changelog).split("\n### ").first

# Ship to testflight
pilot(changelog: upcoming_release_notes)
</code></pre>

<p>This lets the deploy process figure out what the latest release version is, and how many builds have shipped for that version. Then those can be used to set the build version and create a tag associated with it.</p>

<p><a href="https://github.com/fastlane/fastlane/tree/master/pilot">fastlane pilot</a> is used to send off the compiled build to Testflight.</p>

<a name="Keeping.track.of.deploys"></a>
<h2>Keeping track of deploys</h2>

<p>I don't know when we'll need it today, but it's always good to be able to go back and see what code lines up to every release. To do this I have a few lines of Ruby that creates a tag inside the original Emission repo.</p>

<pre><code class="ruby"># Do a tag, we use a http git remote so we can have push access
# as the default remote for travis is read-only. This needs to be
# inside the emission repo, instead of our own.
Dir.chdir('../emission/Example/') do
  tag = "deploy-#{latest_version}-#{build_version}"
  add_git_tag(key: tag)

  if ENV['GITHUB_SUBMODULES_USER']
    writable_remote = "https://#{ENV['GITHUB_SUBMODULES_USER']}@github.com/artsy/emission.git"
    sh "git remote add http #{writable_remote}"
  else
    sh 'git remote add http https://github.com/artsy/emission.git'
  end
  push_git_tags(remote: 'http')
end
</code></pre>

<a name="Notifications.that.it.passed.or.succeeded."></a>
<h2>Notifications that it passed or succeeded.</h2>

<p>This was easy, I created a new slack inbound web-hook and added that as an environment variable. Then when a build passes we post a notification that there is a new version for everyone in Slack, if the lane fails then it will also post to slack. To ensure we keep on top of it, during development this was commented out.</p>

<pre><code class="ruby"># If the weekly task fails, then ship a message
error do |_, exception|
   slack message: "Error Deploying Emission: #{exception}",
         success: false,
         payload: { Output: exception.error_info.to_s }
end
</code></pre>

<p>That wraps up setting up the CI. Once you've confirmed everything has worked, you can add the scheduler inside Travis and expect to see a slack notification in a week.</p>

<p>By the end of the process, our <code>Fastfile</code> looked like:</p>

<pre><code class="ruby"># This is documented in the Artsy Blog: 
# http://artsy.github.io/blog/2017/07/31/fastlane-travis-weekly-deploys/
lane :setup do
  Dir.chdir('..') do
    sh 'rm -rf emission' if Dir.exist? 'Emission'
    sh 'git clone https://github.com/artsy/emission.git'
    Dir.chdir('emission') do
      sh '. ~/.nvm/nvm.sh &amp;&amp; nvm use &amp;&amp; npm install yarn --global &amp;&amp; yarn install'
    end

    Dir.chdir('emission/Example') do
      sh 'pod repo update'
      sh 'pod install'
    end
    stamp_plist
  end
end

# Lets the CI run a bunch of jobs, and share ENV vars between them
lane :ci_deploy do
  setup_signing
  stamp_plist
  ship
end

# The main job for fastlane in this repo, you can run this on your computer
# You can run it via `bundle exec fastlane ship`
lane :ship do
  # We were having issues with building an a few folders deep.
  # The /Pods bit is because we can rely on it being there, see
  # this link: https://docs.fastlane.tools/advanced/#directory-behavior
  #
  Dir.chdir('../emission/Example/Pods') do
    gym(workspace: 'Emission.xcworkspace',
        configuration: 'Deploy',
        scheme: 'Emission')
  end

  # Get the last 10 lines of the CHANGELOG for Testflight
  changelog = '../emission/CHANGELOG.md'
  upcoming_release_notes = File.read(changelog).split("\n### ").first

  # Ship to testflight
  pilot(changelog: upcoming_release_notes)

  # Log into iTunes connect, get the latest version of the app we shipped, and how many builds we've sent
  Spaceship::Tunes.login(ENV['FASTLANE_USERNAME'], ENV['FASTLANE_PASSWORD'])
  app = Spaceship::Tunes::Application.find('net.artsy.Emission')
  latest_version = app.build_trains.keys.sort.last
  train = app.build_trains[latest_version]
  build_version = train.builds.count + 1

  # Do a tag, we use a http git remote so we can have push access
  # as the default remote for travis is read-only. This needs to be
  # inside the emission repo, instead of our own.
  Dir.chdir('../emission/Example/') do
    tag = "deploy-#{latest_version}-#{build_version}"
    add_git_tag(key: tag)

    if ENV['GITHUB_SUBMODULES_USER']
      writable_remote = "https://#{ENV['GITHUB_SUBMODULES_USER']}@github.com/artsy/emission.git"
      sh "git remote add http #{writable_remote}"
    else
      sh 'git remote add http https://github.com/artsy/emission.git'
    end

    push_git_tags(remote: 'http')
  end

  slack message: 'There is a new Emission beta available on Testflight.',
        payload: {
          'Version' =&gt; latest_version,
          "What's new" =&gt; upcoming_release_notes
        },
        default_payloads: []
end

# In case you need to update the signing profiles for this app
lane :update_signing do
  match(type: 'appstore')
end

# Used by CI, will not sneakily update (the CI only has read-only access to the repo anyway)
lane :setup_signing do
  setup_travis
  match(type: 'appstore')
end

# Minor plist modifications
lane :stamp_plist do
  plist = 'emission/Example/Emission/Info.plist'

  # Increment build number to current date
  build_number = Time.new.strftime('%Y.%m.%d.%H')
  `/usr/libexec/PlistBuddy -c "Set CFBundleVersion #{build_number}" "#{plist}"`
end

# Mainly so we don't forget to include these vars in the future
lane :validate_env_vars do
  unless ENV['FASTLANE_USERNAME'] &amp;&amp; ENV['FASTLANE_PASSWORD'] &amp;&amp; ENV['MATCH_PASSWORD']
    raise 'You need to set FASTLANE_USERNAME, FASTLANE_PASSWORD and MATCH_PASSWORD in your environment'
  end

  unless ENV['SLACK_URL']
    raise "You need to set SLACK_URL (#{ENV['SLACK_URL']}) in your environment."
  end
end

# If the weekly task fails, then ship a message, a success would also send
error do |_, exception|
  slack(message: "Error Deploying Emission: #{exception}",
        success: false,
        payload: { Output: exception.error_info.to_s })
end
</code></pre>

<p>Automatically deploying is a good pattern for encouraging more deploys of an app which has only been deployed once. It's a pattern we could also move to in some of our other apps too, if it feels good. If you're interested in if something has changed since this post was authored, the repo is here: https://github.com/artsy/emission-nebula so you can read out the Fastfile and we'll answer questions you have inside GitHub issues on it.</p>

<p>The most annoying part about building deployment changes are that an iteration takes ~20 minutes, so make sure you also have another (easily interrupted) task to do at the same time.</p>

<p>The second most annoying is that it took months to eventually get this right - so I owe Felix Krause a big thanks for sitting down and pairing with me, we figuring out that <code>xcodebuild</code> can create empty archive issues when you run projects that have the xcproject/xcworkspace a few levels deep.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[What is fastlane match?]]></title>
    <link href="http://artsy.github.io/blog/2017/04/05/what-is-fastlane-match/"/>
    <updated>2017-04-05T12:17:00+00:00</updated>
    <id>http://artsy.github.io/blog/2017/04/05/what-is-fastlane-match</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Like anyone working on a non-trivial app in the iOS world who values their time, we use fastlane. <a href="https://fastlane.tools">fastlane</a> is a suite
of tools that makes it much simpler to automate the very manual processes provided by Apple for deployment.</p>

<p>We've adopted it in a relatively piece-meal manner in different projects, converting custom in-house code to something
provided by the gem.  Over time we found what pieces of the suite work for us. <a href="https://github.com/artsy/energy/pull/266">I've adopted another today</a>: <a href="https://github.com/fastlane/fastlane/tree/master/match">match</a>.</p>

<p>match automates setting up your iOS projects for code signing. One of the most arduous orthogonal tasks which every dev team learns and then forgets.</p>

<p>In using match, we have given away a bit of control with code signing, and so this post is going to dig into; what we used
to have, and how it works now with match instead.</p>

<!-- more -->


<p>When match came out, I knew this was a 🌟 idea.</p>

<ul>
<li>Automatically generate the right certificates and keys for your different apps and environments.</li>
<li>Take all your developer certificates and keys, move them to a central place accessible via private git repos.</li>
<li>Encrypt all your certs and keys, the team just needs to share one password.</li>
<li>Migrate all of those keys on both the developer's and CI's computers.</li>
</ul>


<p>You can now have a consistent signing setup between how you work, and how your CI runs. After understanding this, I migrated
Artsy's app store apps to deploy via <a href="https://circleci.com">Circle CI</a>. We initially gave match a shot, but ended up having issues with supporting
multiple apps. So, I replicated the core ideas in match into our Fastfile. It looked like this:</p>

<pre><code class="ruby">lane :setup_for_app_store do
  app_name = "eigen"
  signing_root = "signing"

  `git clone https://github.com/artsy/mobile_code_signing.git #{signing_root}`

  # prints out the codesigning identities
  system "security find-identity -v -p codesigning"

  # Install the iOS distribution certificate, -A
  system "security import #{signing_root}/ios_distribution.cer  -k ~/Library/Keychains/login.keychain -A"

  # Move our provisioning profile in
  profile_path = File.expand_path("~") + "/Library/MobileDevice/Provisioning Profiles/"
  destination = profile_path + "/" + app_name + ".mobileprovision"
  profile = Dir.glob(signing_root + "/profiles/" + app_name + "/*").first

  # Ensure folder exists
  unless File.directory?(profile_path)
    FileUtils.mkdir_p(profile_path)
  end

  # Migrate it in
  FileUtils.copy profile, destination
  puts "Installed Profile"

  # Install the key
  key = Dir.glob(signing_root + "/keys/" + app_name + "/*").first
  system "security import #{key} -k ~/Library/Keychains/login.keychain -P #{ENV['MATCH_PASSWORD']}  -A "

  # prints out the codesigning identities
  system "security find-identity -v -p codesigning"

  # Clean-up
  `rm -rf #{signing_root}`
end
</code></pre>

<p>Pretty neat, huh? It handles the centralization and migration of certificates. The trade-off against match is:</p>

<ul>
<li>We continue to maintain our own certificates, keys and provisioning profiles.</li>
<li>There is no easy way to update these.</li>
<li>There is tooling which makes it easy to see the state of all the code signing process.</li>
</ul>


<p>A year later, on a project which gets no-where near as much developer attention, I discovered that we had got multiple
parts of the certs, keys and profiles wrong when updating our central repo. So, for <a href="http://folio.artsy.net">this project</a>, I have switched to use match.</p>

<hr />

<a name="So.how.does.it.work.now."></a>
<h1>So how does it work now?</h1>

<p>First, I ran <code>bundle exec fastlane appstore</code> and <code>bundle exec fastlane dev</code>.</p>

<p>This creates the certificates, keys and profiles on iTunes connect and gives you output similar to this:</p>

<pre><code class="sh">
+-----------------------+------------------------------------------------+
|                        Summary for match 2.25.0                        |
+-----------------------+------------------------------------------------+
| readonly              | true                                           |
| git_url               | https://github.com/artsy/mobile_fastlane_match |
| type                  | appstore                                       |
| git_branch            | master                                         |
| app_identifier        | sy.art.folio                                   |
| username              | it@artsymail.com                               |
| keychain_name         | login.keychain                                 |
| team_id               | 23KMWZ572J                                     |
| team_name             | Art.sy Inc.                                    |
| verbose               | false                                          |
| force                 | false                                          |
| skip_confirmation     | false                                          |
| shallow_clone         | false                                          |
| force_for_new_devices | false                                          |
| skip_docs             | false                                          |
| platform              | ios                                            |
+-----------------------+------------------------------------------------+

+-------------------+-----------------------------------------------+
|                       Installed Certificate                       |
+-------------------+-----------------------------------------------+
| User ID           | 23KMWZ572J                                    |
| Common Name       | iPhone Distribution: Art.sy Inc. (23KMWZ572J) |
| Organisation Unit | 23KMWZ572J                                    |
| Organisation      | Art.sy Inc.                                   |
| Country           | US                                            |
| Start Datetime    | Apr  4 13:59:06 2017 GMT                      |
| End Datetime      | Apr  4 13:59:06 2018 GMT                      |
+-------------------+-----------------------------------------------+

+---------------------+-----------------------------------------+-------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------+
|                                                                       Installed Provisioning Profile                                                                        |
+---------------------+-----------------------------------------+-------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------+
| Parameter           | Environment Variable                    | Value                                                                                                       |
+---------------------+-----------------------------------------+-------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------+
| App Identifier      |                                         | sy.art.folio                                                                                                |
| Type                |                                         | appstore                                                                                                    |
| Platform            |                                         | ios                                                                                                         |
| Profile UUID        | sigh_sy.art.folio_appstore              | b045df0f-a691-4b7a-ac34-8349a3684030                                                                        |
| Profile Name        | sigh_sy.art.folio_appstore_profile-name | match AppStore sy.art.folio                                                                                 |
| Profile Path        | sigh_sy.art.folio_appstore_profile-path | /Users/orta/Library/MobileDevice/Provisioning Profiles/b045df0f-a691-4b7a-ac34-8349a3684030.mobileprovision |
| Development Team ID | sigh_sy.art.folio_appstore_team-id      | 23KMWZ572J                                                                                                  |
+---------------------+-----------------------------------------+-------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------+
</code></pre>

<p>Which at a glimpse gives a lot of the most useful information about how all the pieces come together. The new repo looks like this:</p>

<pre><code class="sh">$ tree mobile_fastlane_match

├── README.md
├── certs
│   ├── development
│   │   ├── P4K6FACAUD.cer
│   │   └── P4K6FACAUD.p12
│   └── distribution
│       ├── N5BMJ28RQ2.cer
│       └── N5BMJ28RQ2.p12
├── match_version.txt
└── profiles
    ├── appstore
    │   └── AppStore_sy.art.folio.mobileprovision
    └── development
        └── Development_sy.art.folio.mobileprovision
</code></pre>

<a name="So..what.is.Match.doing.here."></a>
<h2>So, what is Match doing here?</h2>

<ol>
<li><p>match creates a new key (the <code>*.p12</code>) - normally you would generate one of these through Keychain, and the entire team would
to share this. We keep ours in team <a href="http://1password.com">1Password</a>. It needs to be used consistently when request certificates from Apple
though the "Request a Certificate from a Certificate Authority" part of getting your certs set up.</p></li>
<li><p>Using <a href="https://github.com/fastlane/fastlane/tree/master/cert">cert</a>: match will use this key <a href="https://github.com/fastlane/fastlane/blob/14dea61e4c81bf9be13bb86c09aa225c6e572618/cert/lib/cert/runner.rb#L141">to create a signing request</a> for you.</p></li>
<li><p>Using <a href="https://github.com/fastlane/fastlane/tree/master/cert">cert</a>: match will generate a certificate for <a href="https://github.com/fastlane/fastlane/blob/14dea61e4c81bf9be13bb86c09aa225c6e572618/cert/lib/cert/runner.rb#L79">development or distribution</a> for you.</p></li>
<li><p>Using <a href="https://github.com/fastlane/fastlane/tree/master/cert">cert</a>: match will <a href="https://github.com/fastlane/fastlane/blob/14dea61e4c81bf9be13bb86c09aa225c6e572618/match/lib/match/runner.rb#L133">generate a Provisioning Profile</a> using your certificate and data pulled from your Xcode Project.
In my case, for development and distribution.</p>

<p>These profiles are tied directly to one app and the certificate in step 3. For development, all devices in the dev center are also added.</p></li>
<li><p>These files are then installed in their various methods.</p></li>
<li><p>These files are then moved into your git repo, a commit is made for you, then pushed and the repo is removed from your computer.</p></li>
</ol>


<p>This process is nice, because this ^ is a lot of work. I only had to run a command.</p>

<p>It would take at about 30 minutes to do this if I knew exactly what I wanted through the web interface + Keychain.</p>

<p>We currently need to do this for every app. This works fine for the app where we are deploying multiple betas a month,
but for one when we're deploying <em>maybe</em> a beta once a month or two (<em>eek! sorry...</em>) then it feels like every time you've come
back to do some work, the world has shifted a bit.</p>

<p>We do lose the fact that we know someone has specifically set everything up to work right at some point, but given how
Xcode updates, <a href="http://stackoverflow.com/questions/4057241/iphone-what-is-a-wwdr-intermediate-certificate">WWDR updates</a> and certificate expirations tend to crop up - it can be frustrating to maintain.</p>

<p>So would I move <a href="https://github.com/artsy/eigen">Eigen</a> to match? Maybe, next time something breaks. Till then I think new apps, and less-often updated
apps should use match.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Xcode 8 Manual Codesigning with Fastlane]]></title>
    <link href="http://artsy.github.io/blog/2017/01/13/xcode-8-fastlane-codesigning/"/>
    <updated>2017-01-13T14:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <id>http://artsy.github.io/blog/2017/01/13/xcode-8-fastlane-codesigning</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>New year, new deploy process! Late last year our mobile team completed the update to Swift 3 (and thus, the update to Xcode 8). The latest version of Apple's IDE includes a lovely feature: automating provisioning profile management! (Note: not sarcasm, the feature is really nice. Check out the <a href="https://developer.apple.com/videos/play/wwdc2016/401/">WWDC video</a> for an in-depth exploration.)</p>

<p><img src="/images/2017-01-13-xcode-8-fastlane-codesigning/xcode-screenshot.png" alt="Automatic code signing settings" /></p>

<p>However, when I went to make our first <a href="http://artsy.github.io/blog/2015/12/15/Automating-Testflight-Deploys/">automated deploy</a> today, things didn't work; I got a somewhat cryptic error about code signing.</p>

<!-- more -->


<blockquote><p>Code signing is required for product type 'Application' in SDK 'iOS 10.1'</p></blockquote>

<p>Code signing was failing for our project. Hmm. First step in fixing a bug is always to reproduce it, which I could do locally. I started looking into the code that manages our deploys' signing process and got lost. My colleague Orta was kind enough to give me a hand.</p>

<p>Some background: the Fastlane suite of tools includes <a href="https://github.com/fastlane/fastlane/tree/master/match">Match</a>, which manages your signing certificates and provisioning profiles in a private GitHub repository. We don't use match due to complications with our multiple apps, but we use <a href="https://github.com/artsy/eigen/blob/608f60860165dd9b3c376da00492a3cb36bf5214/fastlane/Fastfile#L95-L130">very similar logic</a> to clone the repo, extract the certificate and profile, and install the keys on CI.</p>

<p>So what wasn't working?</p>

<p>Well it turns out that Xcode's fancy new automatic code signing was incompatible with our manual process of specifying certificates and profiles. The easy solution would be to simply disable that setting, but that would be a shame: the new automatic code signing makes developing on devices way easier and we didn't want to sacrifice that for the sake of our deploys.</p>

<p>So we went looking and luckily found <a href="https://github.com/artsy/eigen/pull/2104">the solution</a>. We amended our codesigning setup with the <a href="https://docs.fastlane.tools/actions/#update_project_provisioning">update_project_provisioning</a> and <a href="https://docs.fastlane.tools/actions/#update_project_team">update_project_team</a> Fastlane actions, and the <a href="https://github.com/hjanuschka/fastlane-plugin-update_project_codesigning">update_project_codesigning plugin</a>. Basically, we disable the automatic signing feature and then manually set the provisioning profile to the one we cloned from our private GitHub repo.</p>

<p>So remember folks, if you're ever asked to sacrifice ease of development for the sake of getting computers to behave, there's probably a better way.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Accessing the app's Source Code from your Simulator]]></title>
    <link href="http://artsy.github.io/blog/2016/10/14/Accessing-the-Source-Code-from-your-Simulator/"/>
    <updated>2016-10-14T12:17:00+00:00</updated>
    <id>http://artsy.github.io/blog/2016/10/14/Accessing-the-Source-Code-from-your-Simulator</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>In the last few months twice I've wanted to access the source code of our application. The first time I did it I came up with a pretty neat hack, but it wouldn't really work in many places. The second time however, I <a href="https://twitter.com/orta/status/786470282093625344">asked the internet</a>, and the <a href="https://twitter.com/saniul/status/786470857635827712">internet</a> <a href="https://twitter.com/0xced/status/786619335116750848">replied</a>.</p>

<p>TLDR: You can use your <a href="https://github.com/artsy/emission/pull/350/commits/2a39c743bcaaf2e3b848ad60621198f40365fdd2">project's scheme</a> to expose derived Xcode environment variables to your source code.</p>

<p>The rest of the blog post is a little bit about <em>why</em> I wanted to do that and what I did with it.</p>

<!-- more -->


<p>Both times I've wanted to access the source code of our apps is because I've wanted to make better admin tools. It should come as no surprise to people who know me that I care about tooling, but I also care a lot about making it possible for our admins to do their own thing. As such, our <a href="https://github.com/artsy/eigen/blob/master/Artsy/View_Controllers/Admin/ARAdminSettingsViewController.m">admin settings panel</a> in Eigen is extensive.</p>

<a name="Root.React.Components"></a>
<h3>Root React Components</h3>

<p>The first time came when I started to think about what admin options I'd like to see for people using our React Native side. These are the options I came up with:</p>

<p> <img src="/images/source-code-sim/react-admin-eigen.png" alt="/images/source-code-sim/react-admin-eigen.png" /></p>

<p>There are two interesting things about it:</p>

<ul>
<li>We support running any master commit of our React Native code inside Eigen, for Admins, <a href="https://apphub.io">via AppHub</a></li>
<li>We allow loading arbitrary React components as an admin.</li>
</ul>


<p> It's this last bit that's interesting, right now I'm working on a new root Gene component (read: new view controller) in Emission, our React Native implementation. As this work has not moved upstream into Eigen, I can access it through a commit on AppHub, and then open it using our custom module loader:</p>

<p><img src="/images/source-code-sim/react-module-eigen.png" alt="/images/source-code-sim/react-module-eigen.png" /></p>

<p>In order to show the available root components (Artist/Home/Gene), we use GitHub's raw URLs to download the source code of our Open Source apps. Hah, a nice hack right? I <a href="https://github.com/artsy/eigen/blob/master/Artsy/View_Controllers/Admin/ARAdminNetworkModel.m">created</a> a <code>ARAdminNetworkModel</code> with an API like this:</p>

<pre><code class="objc">@interface ARAdminNetworkModel : NSObject

- (void)getEmissionJSON:(NSString *)path completion:(void (^)(NSDictionary *json, NSError *error))completion;

- (void)getEmissionFile:(NSString *)path completion:(void (^)(NSString *fileContents, NSError *error))completion;

@end
</code></pre>

<p>Which simply uses <code>NSURLSession</code> under the hood:</p>

<pre><code class="objc">- (void)getEmissionData:(NSString *)path completion:(void (^)(NSData *data, NSError *error))completion;
{
    NSURLSession *session = [NSURLSession sharedSession];
    NSString *urlFormat = @"https://raw.githubusercontent.com/artsy/emission/master/%@";
    NSString *url = [NSString stringWithFormat: urlFormat, path];
    NSURLRequest *request = [NSURLRequest requestWithURL:[NSURL URLWithString:url]];
    NSURLSessionDataTask *task = [session dataTaskWithRequest:request completionHandler:^(NSData *data, NSURLResponse *response, NSError *error) {
            completion(data, error);
    }];
    [task resume];
}
</code></pre>

<p>Nothing special, but it required a cognitive jump to get there.</p>

<a name="Submodule.Introspection"></a>
<h3>Submodule Introspection</h3>

<p>The second time I wanted this is inside <a href="https://github.com/artsy/emission/tree/master/Example">the example app</a> for Emission. This is a typical example application for a library made by <code>pod lib create</code>. This example app is basically just the admin settings panel from Eigen, shown above.</p>

<p>When I <a href="https://github.com/artsy/emission/pull/347">switched the</a> example app to use a similar theme and menu DSL as Eigen, I also took the chance to expand on the buttons we had available. Previously there was the ability to load the view controller for one specific artist, but I knew we had a <a href="https://github.com/artsy/metaphysics/blob/master/schema/artist/maps/artist_title_slugs.js">giant list of artist slugs</a> inside one of our optional sub-modules. What I wanted to do, was offer a random Artist from that if the submodule was <code>init</code>'d.</p>

<p>This required introspecting the source, which I could have also done via the GitHub API, but it was also feasible to do by accessing the filesystem outside of the simulator. This is totally possible ( and is <a href="https://www.objc.io/issues/15-testing/snapshot-testing/">how FBSnapshots works</a> ) but I needed to access the project root, then I could build relative links. Thus, <a href="https://twitter.com/orta/status/786470282093625344">I asked the internet</a>. I knew these variables existed, but that they were a part of the build process - and not exposed to the app runtime.</p>

<p>There are two ways to do it, both make sense for different contexts:</p>

<ul>
<li><a href="https://github.com/artsy/emission/blob/74d0bc6cc45da906436f8bbc33710ea030657ee8/Example/Emission/Info.plist#L5-L6">Baking the value into your Info.plist</a> - which makes it available for all consumers at runtime, e.g. you could deploy this value, but it's not too useful for my problem.</li>
<li><a href="https://github.com/artsy/emission/pull/350/commits/2a39c743bcaaf2e3b848ad60621198f40365fdd2">Exposing it as an environment variable via your scheme</a> - perfect for this case, the variable won't be exported when you deploy.</li>
</ul>


<p>Now our scheme looks like this:</p>

<p></div></div><a href='/images/source-code-sim/scheme-settings-emission.png'><img src="/images/source-code-sim/scheme-settings-emission.png"></a><div class='meta-container'><header>&nbsp;</header></div><div class='date-container'>&nbsp;</div><div class='content-container'><div class='entry-content'></p>

<p>I can then use the value of <code>SRCROOT</code> as the start of an absolute path to get to any of the source code in our project. Making the <a href="https://github.com/artsy/emission/blob/dda57636e424ab7d4517de57f3e8bd917fcb3c6f/Example/Emission/ARRootViewController.m#L85-L108">final code</a>:</p>

<pre><code class="obj-c">- (ARCellData *)jumpToRandomArtist
{
  NSString *sourceRoot = [NSProcessInfo processInfo].environment[@"SRCROOT"];
  NSString *artistListFromExample = @"../externals/metaphysics/schema/artist/maps/artist_title_slugs.js";
  NSString *slugsPath = [sourceRoot stringByAppendingPathComponent:artistListFromExample];

  NSFileManager *manager = [NSFileManager defaultManager];

  // Don't have the submodule? bail, it's no biggie
  if (![manager fileExistsAtPath:slugsPath]) { return nil; }

  // Otherwise lets support jumping to a random Artist
  return [self tappableCellDataWithTitle:@"Artist (random from metaphysics)" selection: ^{
    NSString *data = [NSString stringWithContentsOfFile:slugsPath encoding:NSUTF8StringEncoding error:nil];

    ... and so on
</code></pre>

<a name="Tooling"></a>
<h3>Tooling</h3>

<p>Paying attention to your admin tools, and improving your development experience for the whole team is a great way to win friends and influence people. Introspecting your source code may help that.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
