<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: oss | Artsy Engineering]]></title>
  <link href="http://artsy.github.io/blog/categories/oss/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://artsy.github.io/"/>
  <updated>2016-01-26T17:59:15+00:00</updated>
  <id>http://artsy.github.io/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Teaching Swift at Artsy]]></title>
    <link href="http://artsy.github.io/blog/2016/01/26/swift-at-artsy/"/>
    <updated>2016-01-26T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <id>http://artsy.github.io/blog/2016/01/26/swift-at-artsy</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>While the Artsy engineering team includes many disciplines, tech stacks, and personalities, we all share a few things in common: a respect for each other, an appreciation of art-meets-science, and a celebration of learning. These are actually traits shared with our entire company, even non-engineers. So last Summer when Orta and I had some down time, it occurred to us how we could do something super-productive that was congruent with our values: we could teach the company Swift.</p>

<!-- more -->


<p>Like most project ideas, the first step was to create a <a href="https://github.com/orta/Swift-at-Artsy">GitHub repo</a>. We made it open source because <a href="http://code.dblock.org/2015/02/09/becoming-open-source-by-default.html">why not</a>. Orta and I chatted and realized that to teach the company Swift, we would need two tracks:</p>

<ul>
<li>A track for newcomers who may have never programmed before.</li>
<li>A track for anyone who could explain what "object-oriented programming" meant.</li>
</ul>


<p>It was really important to us to include beginners who had no exposure to programming – the digital marketing and genoming teams specifically were keen to learn how to program.</p>

<p>I'm a big believer in using "newcomer" and "informed" to describe the two groups of developers – it helps prevent newcomers from feeling inadequate and better describes the expectations for students.</p>

<p>We also focused on Swift-only, no iOS. That allowed us to focus on the language – which was fun because it let us focus on us learning new stuff, too – and we kept the course to five one-hour sessions (per track).</p>

<p>Next step was obviously to create a Slack chatroom. We re-purposed the oft-neglected room dedicated to Taylor Swift and turned it into a place where anyone could ask questions and share resources. It's also a helpful place to @channel everyone to remind them about the classes.</p>

<p></div></div><a href='/images/2016-01-26-swift-at-artsy/chatroom.png'><img src="/images/2016-01-26-swift-at-artsy/chatroom.png"></a><div class='meta-container'><header>&nbsp;</header></div><div class='date-container'>&nbsp;</div><div class='content-container'><div class='entry-content'></p>

<p>Orta taught the beginner course and I TA'd it, answering questions as he instructed and offering suggestions when I felt something should be clarified (kind of like pair-programming except for teaching). We switched roles for the informed class. Preparing course materials was done through GitHub pull requests, which integrated well into our existing workflow on the mobile team.</p>

<p>We ran into some troubles in the first classes of both tracks: Swift 2 was in beta, and getting everyone on the correct versions of Xcode proved... difficult. Keeping them up-to-date as Xcode betas continued to be released over five weeks was also challenging. This was a problem in both tracks, but some problems were track-specific.</p>

<p>Explaining fundamental concepts like variables and for-loops to beginners is challenging. It reminded me of when I TA'd intro-to-Java courses in University (while the code then was obviously much uglier, <code>javac</code> is arguably more user-friendly than Xcode). Having the pair-programming approach worked well to help explain these concepts.</p>

<p>The biggest challenge with the informed class was rounding everyone up to actually attend the classes. Engineers are addicted to being busy, and like most side-projects, everyone was initially very excited about the course, but that interest dropped off quickly. Orta would help by physically going to our colleagues' desks and gently reminding them.</p>

<p>Regardless of the challenges, the course had a significant impact, both within Artsy and in the larger Swift community. Some of the course materials have been <a href="https://github.com/orta/Swift-at-Artsy/blob/master/Beginners/Lesson%20One/README_ZH.md">translated into Chinese</a> and we regularly received suggestions (and occasionally corrections) about our content. Newcomers to programming gained insights into <em>what exactly engineers do</em> and why bugs happen, while informed colleagues saw parallels between Swift and their own favourite languages (most often Scala). The course materials have also helped other mobile team members (who usually write only Objective-C) get started with Swift.</p>

<p>The beginner students really appreciated <a href="https://github.com/orta/Swift-at-Artsy/tree/master/Beginners/Lesson%20Three">lesson three</a> because we used real-world (scaled down) data structures that Artsy actually uses. We presented problems to solve – problems our colleagues were familiar with from their day-to-day work – and we showed how they can be solved with programming. <a href="https://github.com/orta/Swift-at-Artsy/tree/master/Beginners/Lesson%20Four">Lesson four </a> was the most well-received lesson as it featured some concrete "making the computer do cool stuff" material.</p>

<p>Finally, there was just a great sense of accomplishment. Orta and I had taken time during a downtime in engineering work and turned it into something that helped the company and helped the community. We got thanked internally and externally, and that felt great; helping others has a lot of tangible benefits, but feeling good about it is one of my favourites.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Eidolon: Code Review]]></title>
    <link href="http://artsy.github.io/blog/2016/01/14/eidolon-code-review/"/>
    <updated>2016-01-14T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <id>http://artsy.github.io/blog/2016/01/14/eidolon-code-review</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><a href="https://github.com/artsy/eidolon">Eidolon</a> is the third app from Artsy's mobile team, and it was the <a href="http://artsy.github.io/blog/2014/11/13/eidolon-retrospective/">first to be developed totally in the open</a>. It's often used as a reference for what an app written in Swift, or written using FRP, should look like. Given how interested the community seems to be around the app, it's about time we did a walkthrough of the code.</p>

<!-- more -->


<p>This was done as a part of the engineering team's weekly lunch and learn sessions, where we get together and share what we've been working on. Since most of you aren't Artsy engineers, and so you can't ask questions in-person, please feel free to <a href="https://github.com/artsy/eidolon/issues/new">open an issue</a> to ask for any clarifications.</p>

<p>Jump <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=LAAMk7oLrmg">to YouTube</a> for the video, or click more for a smaller inline preview.</p>

<p></div></div><iframe width='100%' height='600' src='https://www.youtube.com/embed/LAAMk7oLrmg ' frameborder='0' allowfullscreen></iframe><div class='meta-container'><header>&nbsp;</header></div><div class='date-container'>&nbsp;</div><div class='content-container'><div class='entry-content'></p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Open Expectations]]></title>
    <link href="http://artsy.github.io/blog/2016/01/13/OSS-Expectations/"/>
    <updated>2016-01-13T11:09:00+00:00</updated>
    <id>http://artsy.github.io/blog/2016/01/13/OSS-Expectations</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>The Artsy engineering team has been moving towards Open Source by Default. In 2015 the Mobile team managed to get there. Since then, we've been writing up our process on this blog and offering advice to anyone would would ask for it.</p>

<p>I've been in talks with lots of companies you've heard of, on the how and the why of this. Recently <a href="https://ello.co">Ello</a> got in touch, and we tried to <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Dyson_sphere">capture the process</a>.  They came out with a great post that I'd strongly <a href="https://ello.co/jayzes/post/tqLL-Z8U8GfbDySRk6wbKg">recommend reading</a>. I'd like to try and come from the other side, and address what are the questions people ask. Consider this a FAQ for how the mobile team does/got to OSS by default.</p>

<!-- more -->


<p><img src = "https://d324imu86q1bqn.cloudfront.net/uploads/asset/attachment/3421690/ello-optimized-08acbd80.gif"></p>

<h3>Really, is <em>everything</em> Open Source?</h3>

<p>No, and it probably never will. There are companies who are (e.g. <a href="https://buffer.com/transparency">Buffer</a> &amp; <a href="https://automattic.com">Automattic</a>) however Artsy is considerably less transparent in-comparison. We have code-bases that will stay closed, and we have data that could stay closed.</p>

<p>Companies revolve around ideas, and understanding what your core value is important. A company who make money purely off selling their apps could be easily copied, and OSS by default won't work for them. Artsy is a platform, but OSS by default can work for us because a technical platform is just one aspect of what we offer.</p>

<h3>How did we start the process?</h3>

<p>We're lucky to have <a href="http://www.forbes.com/special-report/2014/30-under-30/art-and-style.html">technical</a> <a href="https://www.linkedin.com/in/sebastiancwilich">co-founders</a>, and a CTO with a strong belief in <a href="http://code.dblock.org/2015/02/09/becoming-open-source-by-default.html">Open Source</a>. So we had a head-start, I respect that.</p>

<p>Like all big ideas, it started out small. We'd abstract out shared concerns into libraries. This is something that anyone who has heard a little bit about Open Source can get behind. "We're building on top of <em>x</em>, so we really should give back out <em>x</em>+<em>y</em>" it's low-risk, and potentially high reward. Getting the company on-board with your OSS libraries is about acclimatisation.</p>

<p>This works best by taking small incremental steps. You need buy-in from everyone involved through-out the process. Moving to OSS by Default is 30% technical work and 70% political relationships. There has to be infrastructure in place in order to not leak secrets, but you also need to ensure that the entire company doesn't feel threatened by the insight offered by opening the development process. There is no shortcut here.</p>

<p>For me, this process involved talking with everyone involved in each project. Setting aside 1-on-1 time specifically on the subject to answer question about the ramifications for OSSing it. This ranged from "we will need to change the flow around <em>x</em> and <em>y</em>." to "Yes, the competition will be able to see how we do <em>x</em> and <em>y</em>." I came very prepared to these meetings.</p>

<p>For our mobile apps, we progressively introduced Open by Default to our apps based on their age. We started out by creating a whole <a href="/blog/2014/11/13/eidolon-retrospective/">new project</a> as Open Source. Then started applying what we had learned to <a href="/blog/2015/04/28/how-we-open-sourced-eigen/">older</a> <a href="/blog/2015/08/06/open-sourcing-energy/">projects</a>. They had more risk, given that they were mature apps.</p>

<h3>Couldn't someone make a business copying me?</h3>

<p>It's also worth remembering that an app being OSS does not stop it <a href="http://venturebeat.com/2014/03/30/threes-vs-2048-when-rip-offs-do-better-than-the-original-game/">being copied</a>. Or, well, your <a href="http://www.bloomberg.com/bw/articles/2012-02-29/the-germany-website-copy-machine">entire business</a>.</p>

<p>Code only represents the <em>past to almost present</em> of your business, losing a valuable colleague hurts because of their ability to move your business forwards. A "fresh replacement" has a while to go in terms of being able to make the change you want. Someone trying to build off your source, has to learn to understand your motivations, your aspirations and then try build what they'd like around that. It's not good business sense.</p>

<h3>License Selection</h3>

<p>I covered this in <a href="/blog/2015/12/10/License-and-You/">Licensing for OSS</a>. If you want the TL:DR for Apps on app stores, jump to "Viral".</p>

<p>We use the <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/MIT_License">MIT license</a> on all Open Source projects. It's worked out so far for us, because as a platform each individual component can exist standalone. Having a fork of all our projects does not make you a competitor to us.</p>

<h3>I have code that <em>has</em> to stay hidden</h3>

<p>So do we! In the iOS world, we use API compatible Open/Closed CocoaPods that allow for us to mock out for OSS consumers and let us use <a href="/blog/2014/06/20/artsys-first-closed-source-pod/">private implementations</a>. If you're trying to hide secret API calls, it's probably easier for someone to run a <a href="http://www.charlesproxy.com">proxy</a> than it is to find the section of code calling it.</p>

<p>Having the core of your application Open Source doesn't mean you cannot develop features in private. I <a href="https://github.com/artsy/eigen/pull/302">built a WatchOS app</a> for Eigen entirely on a private repo, where once a week for 2 months I rebase'd changes from the main repo. When we felt comfortable about making it known publicly we were working on it - I brought it over to a public repo and initiated the <a href="https://github.com/artsy/eigen/pull/302">code review</a>.</p>

<h3>Our expectations of OSS contributors</h3>

<p>We don't expect people to contribute to our apps. For libraries, that's different. I think <a href="https://ello.co/jayzes/post/tqLL-Z8U8GfbDySRk6wbKg">Ello's write-up</a> really nailed this point, so I'll just quote jayzes:</p>

<blockquote><p>On one hand, we have library and infrastructure code — things that are more generic and reusable. These are the sort of thing that we can more easily envision starting to grow communities around, albeit small ones.</p>

<p>On the other hand, we have custom-built applications, which are likely to have limited utility outside of their current purpose due to size and coupling to other parts of Ello’s infrastructure (the Ello API, for one). We don’t envision these apps building much of a community around themselves in the way that most open source tools and libraries do, and see the primary value in opening them up coming as a result of increased transparency. That having been said, we’ll certainly accept pull requests that fit our product roadmap and engineering standards, should anyone feel like jumping in and contributing!</p></blockquote>

<p>Beautiful. This is exactly how I feel, and in over a year these expectations have been met. Some of our libraries have become big, and our apps have received small feature PRs. We're pleasantly surprised when it happens, but we don't expect it.</p>

<h3>What didn't we expect?</h3>

<p>I didn't expect to be told face to face how many people have read, and learned from our codebases. We get around 120 unique clones of our iOS apps every week. People tell us that it's where they found a certain technique, or that they could see how the trade-offs were made for certain decisions.</p>

<p>I also under-estimated how useful open code is in encouraging a culture of writing. Ash once quoted <a href="https://twitter.com/ashfurrow/status/676814159363842048">me in a tweet</a> saying:</p>

<blockquote><p>Order of importance: blog posts > types > tests</p></blockquote>

<p>While it is a joke against functional programmers, in general; having these huge codebases gives a lot to talk about. A commit says the what, a pull request the how and a blog post gives the why. Writing about our code allows us to provide documentation for future employees with the context around how decisions were made. Nobody <em>wants</em> to ship messy code, but a lot of the time you choose to in order to provide something positive.</p>

<h3>How does Open Source affect security</h3>

<p>Artsy has a <a href="https://www.artsy.net/security">security policy</a>, with bounties and ways to report issues. From our perspective so far, having this open has not affected the reports we receive. If 1Password <a href="https://teams.1password.com/white-paper/1Password%20for%20Teams%20White%20Paper.pdf">can say</a></p>

<blockquote><p>We believe that openness always trumps “security through obscurity”.</p></blockquote>

<p>Then show off their algorithms that keep passwords safe, then so long as we're careful about our keys and stick to best security practices. We seem to be doing alright.</p>

<h3>What is a good approach to talk to the legal team?</h3>

<p>I have a friend who works in a very large company. He told me that he was aiming to Open Source his app. He had had a few meetings with the legal team that didn't really go anywhere. After a few meetings, he explained that they weren't aiming for community-building with this, but aiming to develop in the open. This change of perspective, changed the tone of the meetings from then on in. It became much easier to start the political work necessary to even begin working on the technical aspect.</p>

<h3>Alright, so I'm gonna need ammo for these meetings.</h3>

<p>Looking back at the last year, here's been some highlights:</p>

<h4>Personal</h4>

<ul>
<li>It's gratifying to give back to communities who help you get things done.</li>
<li>It's so much easier to talk about <a href="https://github.com/artsy/eigen/issues/586">technical challenges</a>, and <a href="/blog/2015/12/15/Automating-Testflight-Deploys/">achievements</a> when you can let people explore; before, the code review, and after.</li>
<li>The code you write does not become unavailable to you when you leave the company. Carry your best ideas between jobs.</li>
</ul>


<h4>Company-wide</h4>

<ul>
<li>You can structure in a way so that contributions within your team reflect how working in the OSS community is. Lowering the barrier of entry for your team to contribute back to their dependencies. There is little cultural differences between being a high-level contributor to CocoaPods and working in the Artsy mobile team.</li>
<li>Working in the open is a great way to raise the profiles of your team, and the individuals on it. This opens extra potential for personal growth for individuals. Not just professional.</li>
<li>It can make it easier to hire, because you can "<a href="https://github.com/artsy/mobile/">show</a>", not "<a href="https://www.artsy.net/article/artsy-jobs-mobile-engineer">tell</a>" the positives in your team culture.</li>
<li>You open the doors to potential contributors. Those contributors could eventually become hires.</li>
</ul>


<p>This is still pretty new, there's a lot to explore in the space. The mobile team at Artsy is always happy to talk with people interested in doing it themselves. Send us an email at <a href="mailto:mobile@artsy.net">mobile@artsy.net</a>, tweet to <a href="https://twitter.com/ArtsyOpenSource">@ArtsyOpenSource</a> or DM me <a href="https://twitter.com/orta">@orta</a>.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Licenses for OSS Code]]></title>
    <link href="http://artsy.github.io/blog/2015/12/10/License-and-You/"/>
    <updated>2015-12-10T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <id>http://artsy.github.io/blog/2015/12/10/License-and-You</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>As a part of our internal Lunch and Learn series, I  gave a talk to our developers with an overview of the different types of source code licenses available.</p>

<p>We always recommend MIT within Artsy, but understanding what the other ones are and <a href="http://artsy.github.io/blog/2012/01/29/how-art-dot-sy-uses-github-to-build-art-dot-sy/">why we made</a> the choices we have done is valuable.</p>

<p>Jump <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=0r7JcN3Q_LY">to YouTube</a> for the video, or click more for a smaller inline preview, as well as all of the speakers notes.</p>

<!-- more -->


<p></div></div><iframe width='100%' height='600' src='https://www.youtube.com/embed/0r7JcN3Q_LY ' frameborder='0' allowfullscreen></iframe><div class='meta-container'><header>&nbsp;</header></div><div class='date-container'>&nbsp;</div><div class='content-container'><div class='entry-content'></p>

<h3>Licenses For Code</h3>

<p>Attn:<em>I am not a lawyer</em>, but I have to care about this from an app dev perspective, and a dependency manager perspective.</p>

<p>Recommendation for further reading:</p>

<ul>
<li>http://choosealicense.com</li>
<li>https://tldrlegal.com/</li>
</ul>


<p>We'll talk about 3 types of licenses:</p>

<ul>
<li>Permissive: MIT/BSD, used by jQuery, Rails, Artsy OSS</li>
<li>Mostly Permissive: Apache/Mozzila, used by SVN, Firefox</li>
<li>Copyleft: GPL, used by Git, Linux, Wordpress</li>
</ul>


<h3>Common Components</h3>

<p>All share one important thing:</p>

<ul>
<li>YOU MAY USE THIS</li>
<li>NO WARRANTY</li>
<li>DISCLAIMER OF LIABILITY</li>
</ul>


<p>Which is basically the crux of how we can all actually use and write OSS without ending up bankrupt. E.g. when a major component of your infrastructure "fails" - it's not the fault of the author. Example: <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Shellshock_(software_bug">Shellshock</a>) - no-one tried suing the maintainers of Bash.</p>

<h3>License Free</h3>

<p>By choosing to not include a license, you only applying your copyright to the code. All code is the copyright of someone, because creation of anything is covered by copyright. Copyright is, err, complex. Roughly speaking though, there is no contract between you and someone using your code. This means <em>all</em> of the power is in favour of the library author. A library consumer would need to email the author and ask for permission on a case by case basis, even then there is nothing stopping a developer revoking the ability for you to use their library after the fact. It's also different depending on the country the library author is in. However in the end the default copyright is not a license, so add one.</p>

<p><a href="http://blog.codinghorror.com/pick-a-license-any-license/">This is basically the default license for code. </a></p>

<p>This means that code on a blog could not be safe to use unless they've declared its license, whereas for something like stack overflow all of the contents there are licensed under the Creative Commons. Which I'll talk about later.</p>

<p>Just uploading some code to GitHub actually does put it under a license of sort, which includes the ability for someone to fork and view the code. It's explicit in the GitHub T&amp;C, they could not have those features without it. Other than that though, you offer no contract with the library user.</p>

<h3>OSI</h3>

<p>So when we say Open Source license, we are talking about licenses that come from the Open Source Initiative. They are a pragmatic group who say whether a license should be classed as 'open source' or not. A bit weird, but they generally just debate a lot of the legal stuff in these licenses and try to find holes so that everyone is protected. It's basically a seal of approval. There are very few licenses that are not OSI approved, the one you might know is the WTFPL - which is basically default copyright anyway.</p>

<p>On the mobile team we requested that dependencies of ours convert from WTFPL so that we don’t have the issue mention about the public domain, we as Artsy have little protection against the library authors future wishes.</p>

<h3>Permissive</h3>

<p>What you think of as open source is the modern day permissive license.</p>

<p>These are the least restrictive, and are considered "business friendly." They apply very little rules between author and library consumer.</p>

<p>People use permissive licenses because conceptually they allow the most programmer freedom to use, change and improve a library.</p>

<p>They also protect the author, in the sense that a consumer cannot claim that the author created the product the consumer made. They protect the author from liability.</p>

<h4>The one thing</h4>

<p>For example someone could take your library, and rename it, then apply a different license. Not breaking any rules, unless they ignore attribution.</p>

<p>This happened this year with <a href="https://github.com/Microsoft/WinObjC">WinObjC</a>
Microsoft's version of Objective-C, which also aimed for API compatibility with Apple's developer frameworks. They built it up with a lot of other source code, but didn't provide attribution.</p>

<p>https://github.com/Microsoft/WinObjC/issues/35
https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=10024377</p>

<blockquote><p>The ONE SINGLE requirement of the Cocotron MIT license is that the license text, including copyright holders, remains in the source. THAT'S IT, can you please manage to do that.</p></blockquote>

<h3>Patently Permissive</h3>

<p>Moving up in terms WRT strength of the contract, there is the permissive+patent libraries. These allow library authors to have patents on the software. This can make it more business friendly, depending on the business goals. The most common are Apache and the Mozilla Public License.</p>

<h3>Viral</h3>

<p>The GPL, and it's crew. Roughly speaking, they say that if you want to include any GPL'd code in your projects, you need to make your entire project GPL. There is an important distinction in the GPL in that version 2, and version 3 differ in important ways. The one that I think is most important is that GPL 3 allows sub-licensing. This means that you can say "I can give Artsy a license for this code under BSD terms", allowing for some flexibility in how you apply the license.</p>

<p>It's considered viral because if you have any GPL code anywhere, then everything becomes GPL.  Rule of thumb is to avoid this license, however I'd like to offer a reason why Artsy might ship GPL code.</p>

<p>On the OSS iOS side, we release all of our apps as MIT. I could be quite worried about people shipping copies of our applications. For example there could be fake versions of the Artsy app on the App Store, or competitors could use it to bootstrap. If I was very, very worried I would ship it as GPL 3 with an MIT sublicense to Artsy. This means that anyone who ships a copy of our app to the app store without our express permission for a sublicense that allows DRM.</p>

<p>Generally though we don’t need to do this because we have the ability to revoke an app’s access to the API, meaning it cannot talk to Artsy, and our apps are pretty useless at that point.</p>

<h3>Creative Commons</h3>

<p>So, the Creative Commons is a license on content like videos, images and corpuses of text. They are not OSI approved, and <a href="https://wiki.creativecommons.org/wiki/Frequently_Asked_Questions#Can_I_use_a_Creative_Commons_license_for_software.3F">actively recommend</a> that people use an OSI license for code. This is because software licenses have more to care about: distribution, compilation  and working with other license / patents. Things that you don't have to deal with WRT other types of content.</p>

<p>All CC-licensed code requires attribution of <a href="http://blog.stackoverflow.com/2009/06/attribution-required/">some sort</a>.</p>

<p>In CocoaPods all the design assets are released under CC, but all the code is BSD.</p>

<h2>Twitter Q &amp; A</h2>

<h3>Can I re-license after the fact?</h3>

<p>So, have you wondered why sometimes you have to sign a CLA ( contributors license agreement ) to work on a repo? Relicensing is one of these things. Let's take 3 examples.</p>

<ul>
<li><p><em>VLC</em> - Wanted to put an app on the app store, VLC was GPL. As each contributor owned their contributions if one single party who had contributed to the codebase didn't agree with putting an app on the store then they couldn't ship. It took an extra year and a half to get VLC re-licensed to get on the store.</p></li>
<li><p><em>Swift</em> - New language by Apple, they <em>specifically</em> ensure that people keep the rights to their contributions. This means Apple are not special. They cannot decide to suddenly switch license if Google decide it to be the new language for Android. There is no self destruct button.</p></li>
<li><p><em>Solaris</em> - When Sun got bought by Oracle a bunch of projects got canned, one of the ways that they were able to do this and to nuke the code was because they owned all the copyrights to every contribution made to the codebases owned by Sun. They closed the source for the entire OS. It was totally within their rights.</p></li>
</ul>


<p><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=10669891">Sources</a>, <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=-zRN7XLCRhc">History of Solaris</a></p>

<h3>Do I need to include a copyright banner on every file?</h3>

<p>No, it's possible that if it's likely that specific files will be used outside of the project ( e.g. your code is not totally atomic ) then it's valuable to note the license multiple times. However as long as a license is shipped with the code then you're good, if that license states something to the effect of “this software and associated documentation files (the "Software")”.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Using OCR To Fix a Hilarious Bug]]></title>
    <link href="http://artsy.github.io/blog/2015/11/05/Using-OCR-To-Fix-A-Hilarious-Bug/"/>
    <updated>2015-11-05T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <id>http://artsy.github.io/blog/2015/11/05/Using-OCR-To-Fix-A-Hilarious-Bug</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>For a little while, we would get very strange bug reports. People would complain that artist thumbnails (viewed in several different contexts across the web and our iOS apps) would not be an image of the artist's work, but rather text, which had inexplicably become an actual JPG. This wasn't just text appearing in a <code>div</code> that should contain an <code>img</code> or something like that, these were actual JPG's that were pictures of text.</p>

<p>We would fix these as they came up, chalking the strangeness up to some relic of an old image processing pipeline, data being migrated, etc.</p>

<p>However, the reports kept coming in. This blog post is about how we diagnosed this actual bug, and how we used a simple Ruby script and OCR to help us detect and fix the existing images.</p>

<!-- more -->


<p>Here's an example of a bug report where the thumbnail for <a href="https://www.artsy.net/artist/marina-abramovic-1">Marina Abramović</a> became the text of her bio.</p>

<p><img src="/images/2015-11-12-hilarious-bug/search.png" alt="Bad Search" /></p>

<p>Here's one from our <a href="https://github.com/artsy/eigen">iOS app</a> showing that thumbnails for related artists are set to their bios as well.</p>

<p><img src="/images/2015-11-12-hilarious-bug/eigen.png" alt="Bad Related Artists" /></p>

<p>Weird right? We eventually tracked down what was going on, and it's actually perfectly summarized in <a href="https://github.com/blueimp/jQuery-File-Upload/pull/3356">this issue</a>. When someone copies text from Excel, it also generates an image of that cell or cells, and puts it into the clipboard. We immediately suspected something with <code>pasteZone</code>, and the bug was easy to reproduce - have an image in your clipboard and paste anywhere on the page.</p>

<p>We have an admin panel that allows some metadata about an artist to be edited. This includes their bio, as well as a place to upload a representative image as their 'cover thumbnail'.</p>

<p>As the issue describes, we had some text input fields, as well as a file upload form using <a href="https://github.com/blueimp/jQuery-File-Upload">Blueimp's jQuery File Upload</a>. When you don't specify a <code>pasteZone</code> it defaults to the entire document. This means that a paste event anywhere on the page will trigger that event.</p>

<p>Our editorial team was using Microsoft Excel and Word to organize some data about the artist, including bios. When ready, a team member would copy and paste the bio into the bio input text field. This would also immediately fire the event for the image upload, which now automagically became an actual picture of the text of the bio. Our API and image processing pipeline would happily accept that, leading to the incredibly bizarre bug reports.</p>

<p>My immediate fix was to specify and scope <code>pasteZone</code> (and similarly, <code>dropZone</code>) to the element the file upload widget was bound to. That would prevent the problem from happening again. Taking a quick look art some random samples of artists, it looked like potentially thousands of records might have been affected and I became interested in a programmatic way to detect these images. A manual approach would have been very cumbersome.</p>

<p>Since the images were that of text, I decided to use OCR to remove artist thumbnails that it determined had 'too much text'. This may have unset valid covers from artists that use lots of text in their work, such as <a href="https://www.artsy.net/artist/joseph-kosuth">Joseph Kosuth</a>. However, this was safe to do since we have some custom logic to fall back to an image of an iconic artwork by the artist in the case of a missing thumbnail.</p>

<p>To get OCR functionality in Ruby, I decided to use <a href="https://github.com/tesseract-ocr/tesseract">Tesseract</a>, a great OSS library. Once I had it installed, I used a <a href="https://github.com/meh/ruby-tesseract-ocr">ruby wrapper</a> to make using it easier.</p>

<p>The script eventually turned into something like:</p>

<pre><code class="ruby"># initialize and configure Tesseract
engine = Tesseract::Engine.new do |config|
  config.language  = :eng
  config.blacklist = '|'
end

# iterate over artists and pull their thumbnails
# given the URL to a publicly accessible image at img

text = engine.text_for(img)
text = text.gsub(/[^a-z ]/i, '').gsub(' ', '')
if text.length &gt; 30
  puts "Found problematic artist #{artist_doc['last']}"
  # ...
end
</code></pre>

<p>So all we do is find all the text in an image, and then remove any garbage characters or artifacts from the OCR analysis, and then use 30 as an arbitrary cutoff to determine if an image was problematic. If the image had more than 30 characters as detected by the OCR library, we wound up unsetting it from the artist.</p>

<p>The additional logic to set artist covers from their iconic artworks was already in place, and I ran this script in production, identifying and unsetting over 1000 problematic thumbnails. And we haven't gotten any new reports of this bug since then :)</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
