<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: oss | Artsy Engineering]]></title>
  <link href="http://artsy.github.io/blog/categories/oss/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://artsy.github.io/"/>
  <updated>2016-05-17T11:45:48+00:00</updated>
  <id>http://artsy.github.io/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Public Speaking - Part 2: Where To Start?]]></title>
    <link href="http://artsy.github.io/blog/2016/03/14/public-speaking-part2-where-to-start/"/>
    <updated>2016-03-14T11:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <id>http://artsy.github.io/blog/2016/03/14/public-speaking-part2-where-to-start</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>So you’ve decided <a href="http://artsy.github.io/blog/2016/03/09/public-speaking-part1-is-it-for-me/">you’d like to give speaking a go</a>, or perhaps you were always interested. By now you’re probably wondering where to start.</p>

<p>There are various options depending on what you’re looking for. Would you prefer a smaller, intimate audience or would you like to reach far and wide? Is the topic of your choice suited for a quick talk or would you rather discuss it at length? Let’s have a look.</p>

<!-- more -->


<h3>In-house / Workplace Knowledge Share</h3>

<p>Lots of workplaces dedicate some time to knowledge sharing nowadays (and if yours doesn’t, see if you can start one!). They can be technical, for instance at Artsy we host a technical Lunch and Learn weekly. They could also be on any topic, like <a href="https://www.artsy.net/article/natalia-maldonado-introduction-to-office-meditation-5-steps-to-peace-of-mind-at-work">meditation</a>. Anywhere between 5 and 15 minutes in length is common, and they are a perfect opportunity to talk about things you know well. This could be centred around your day to day work, spreading the knowledge to decrease <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Bus_factor">the bus factor</a>, or something from your personal life. I’ve given a talk on <a href="https://speakerdeck.com/mennenia/colour-theory">colour theory in painting</a> once.</p>

<p>If you have a workplace you feel comfortable at, this is definitely a good place to start.</p>

<p>One of the key elements in public speaking that is often forgotten is the fact that the audience wants you to succeed. They’re not there to poke holes or boo you off stage. They are curious to see what you have to say and learn from you. Give them that opportunity.</p>

<p>Even if your goal is towards speaking at bigger events, any chance at practicing and putting together a well flowing talk is good and shouldn’t be ignored.</p>

<h3>Local meet-ups</h3>

<p>If you’re in a city that has a thriving meet-up scene, you may want to put your name forward to speak on a certain topic. A UK meet-up, <a href="http://www.meetup.com/NSLondon/">NSLondon</a>, is a great example of this. Many different members of the community have spoken, and it’s created a lovely atmosphere where it feels like you’re exchanging interesting tidbits of information continuously. Also for newcomers it’s created a welcoming atmosphere, as the people speaking are often people they know or “just like them”.</p>

<p>If you have a meet-up with a similar positive vibe, there’s no reason not to have a chat with the organisers and see what the next steps would be. It might even be well worth practicing a talk here, for when you’ve got a bigger event coming up and you would like feedback. Bare in mind, the audience wants you to succeed!</p>

<p>Sidenote — if your city does not (yet) have a great meet-up, it’s well worth starting one.</p>

<h3>Conferences</h3>

<p>Often considered the most intimidating of all. People have purchased tickets and possibly travelled from far. The audience is usually in the hundreds, occasionally even more than a thousand. Even the most experienced speakers can get a bit nervous for this.</p>

<p>Funnily enough, my first ever talk, since starting out as a developer, was at a <a href="http://www.iosdevuk.com/">conference</a>. It happened to have a very friendly atmosphere and really wasn’t that scary. I can’t stress enough that, yes, the audience wants you to succeed. I remember talking through my introduction and seeing all the curious, attentive faces. They were there because they were interested. They cared for what I had to say.</p>

<p>I will say that this doesn’t necessarily mean you should go talk about anything your heart desires. Ultimately the attendees are there to learn, so it’s only fair that as speakers you’d tailor your presentation towards your audience. But more on that in Part 3.</p>

<p>To be considered, often conference organisers ask people to submit a CfP (Call for Papers / Call for Proposals). This is your chance to submit details on what you’d like to present on, although they may <a href="http://www.osfeels.com/talk-ideas/">give you suggestions</a>. You usually want to include a preliminary talk title, an abstract, and a bit of background on yourself. If you’ve done any talks before and they happen to have been recorded, it’s worth including the video or otherwise previous slidedecks.</p>

<p>As for how CfPs then get chosen depends on the conference. Most of the time the organisational committee selects talks from the proposal list. Some conferences have <a href="http://www.altconf.com">an independent panel</a> review anonymised proposals or have a system in place where <a href="http://cfp.uikonf.com/about">the community votes</a>. Once it’s been decided, they will get back in touch with you.</p>

<p>Usually conferences are swarmed with CfPs so please don’t be discouraged if it takes a few tries to get picked. It’s understandable to feel rejected and give up, but bare in mind that a friend of mine felt this way yet kept applying. He got his break at NSSpain 2014, and now is incredibly active in the <a href="http://www.meetup.com/swift-language/">San Francisco Swift</a> meet-up scene. All of this got the ball rolling and now he's given talks all around the world. <a href="https://twitter.com/simjp">You might even have heard of him</a>.</p>

<h3>Lightning talks</h3>

<p>If a CfP is a bit too much to prepare at the moment (we’re all busy) or you didn’t get in, another option is to give a lightning talk if the conference of your choice has slots. When done well, they are great.</p>

<p>A lightning talk is usually capped at 5 minutes, and gives you the time and space to cover one thing well. The best ones I’ve heard, have had one main message to convey and did so excellently.</p>

<p>They require a bit of planning as you <a href="http://quoteinvestigator.com/2012/04/28/shorter-letter/">want to be concise</a>, but will be done before you know it and gives the audience a great point of reference to engage with you. Not to mention that sometimes you might get asked to do a full talk based off these.</p>

<h3>Preparing content</h3>

<p><a href="http://artsy.github.io/blog/2016/03/09/public-speaking-part1-is-it-for-me/">Choosing to publicly speak</a> and where is only half the battle. Deciding the content, formulating an abstract, talk title, and slides are not trivial. But fear not, Part 3 in this series will have you covered. Stay tuned!</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Public Speaking - Part 1: Is It For Me?]]></title>
    <link href="http://artsy.github.io/blog/2016/03/09/public-speaking-part1-is-it-for-me/"/>
    <updated>2016-03-09T11:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <id>http://artsy.github.io/blog/2016/03/09/public-speaking-part1-is-it-for-me</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>At Artsy, sharing knowledge is heavily encouraged and so we write our code in the open, document using blog posts, and speak about our experiences. Many have <a href="https://twitter.com/qnoid/status/702955785064677376">bumped into us</a> at various places around the world. And so I often get the question: “How did you get started? I’m interested in speaking too”.</p>

<p>In the name of sharing experiences with others, I can’t encourage this enough. Unfortunately though, public speaking is still considered <a href="https://www.washingtonpost.com/news/wonk/wp/2014/10/30/clowns-are-twice-as-scary-to-democrats-as-they-are-to-republicans/">man’s biggest fear</a>.</p>

<p>I’d like to share with you the benefits of public speaking, tips on how to get started, and how to give great presentations.</p>

<!-- more -->


<h2>Why do it?</h2>

<h3>Communication</h3>

<p>Without necessarily realising, you’re publicly speaking all the time. At the heart of it, it’s the act of communicating and expressing your ideas and viewpoints for others to understand.</p>

<p>It could be as simple as ordering your morning coffee or as important as trying to convince your team that they should use a new technology. Regardless of the context, it involves restructuring your thoughts into words and metaphors that you think others can relate to in order for them to understand your concepts.</p>

<p><strong>Public speaking is a skill that is always good to improve on</strong>. Misunderstandings happen all the time, and at the heart of that is often poor communication.</p>

<p>I know people have refrained from speaking up in meetings at work, because they struggle with speaking in front of others. There’s no need for everyone to be a keynote speaker at a conference, but if it’s hindering you in your career, it may be worth practicing. Everyone should feel empowered to call a meeting, participate in discussions, or ask questions at an all hands.</p>

<h3>Learning</h3>

<p>Another reason giving talks is 👍🏽 is that it will allow you to learn more fully. One of the best ways to learn is by <a href="http://ideas.time.com/2011/11/30/the-protege-effect/">teaching others</a>. You grasp ideas better yourself and in order to communicate them properly, you get into the habit of restructuring your ideas and concepts.</p>

<p>Unfortunately, people often also consider this the blocker to public speaking. Not only are you afraid you’ll accidentally make a fool of yourself (“what if I trip?”) but also that it will be apparent that you don’t know something well enough. The only way to get over this is by doing it.</p>

<p>Chances are that you are actually very knowledgeable in certain fields, you just perceive that as normal. “Yeah, but that’s not interesting… everyone knows about <em>that</em>”. And I can bet that, well, probably not everyone knows about that. Definitely not as much as you might actually do.</p>

<p>We all have our strengths. This is the time to play on them. We can’t be experts in both Core Image, Core Animation, and the Objective C runtime, all the while knowing everything about Swift Protocols. Pick your slice from a much wider scope. It doesn’t need to be a full framework, even just a specific use case of it, like <a href="https://realm.io/news/gwendolyn-weston-ios-background-networking/">background transfer services</a>.</p>

<p>Furthermore, see it as a learning opportunity. Speak about a topic that truly interests you and take this time to uncover things you’ve always wanted to know. It does not require you to be an expert up front — sharing knowledge gives you the chance to become one.</p>

<p>For example, I wanted to give a talk on the beauty of design and why beautiful things “just work”. I took this chance to read papers and books on the field of positive psychology and design, learning all kinds of fun new facts. Others have shared with me also that it wasn’t until they decided to write or speak about certain API that they fully got to understand all the ins and outs.</p>

<h2>Ok you got me interested… now what?</h2>

<p>That's great!</p>

<p>Next you'd probably want to figure out where you'd like to speak and how to prepare a good talk. This will be covered in the next two posts, so stay tuned.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Code Review: Energy Sync]]></title>
    <link href="http://artsy.github.io/blog/2016/02/12/Code-Review-Energy-Sync/"/>
    <updated>2016-02-12T12:09:00+00:00</updated>
    <id>http://artsy.github.io/blog/2016/02/12/Code-Review-Energy-Sync</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>We are slowly trying to do high-level code-review views for all of our iOS apps. So far, we've covered <a href="/blog/2016/01/14/eidolon-code-review/">Eidolon</a> and <a href="/blog/2015/11/05/Emergence-Code-Review/">Emergence</a> and now <a href="/blog/2016/02/11/Code-Review-Energy/">Energy</a>. This is the second part of the Energy code review. The <a href="/blog/2016/02/11/Code-Review-Energy/">first part</a> covers the the critical codepaths that go from the App's launch to sending an email, which is the main use-case for the app. This video covers how Folio does sync between the Artsy API and the app.</p>

<p>Sync is a complex problem. This video covers our old techniques, how we changed them, the underlying abstractions we use now and how we can test each component individually. It's an hour long, and it's a little computer-sciencey. So I think people who have shipped some small apps would get a lot out of it.</p>

<p>Jump <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=05HaKChPe_g">to YouTube</a> for the video, or click more for a smaller inline preview.</p>

<!-- more -->


<p></div></div><iframe width='100%' height='600' src='https://www.youtube.com/embed/05HaKChPe_g ' frameborder='0' allowfullscreen></iframe><div class='meta-container'><header>&nbsp;</header></div><div class='content-container'><div class='entry-content'></p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Code Review: Energy overview]]></title>
    <link href="http://artsy.github.io/blog/2016/02/11/Code-Review-Energy/"/>
    <updated>2016-02-11T11:09:00+00:00</updated>
    <id>http://artsy.github.io/blog/2016/02/11/Code-Review-Energy</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>We are slowly trying to do high-level code-review views for all of our iOS apps. So far, we've covered <a href="/blog/2016/01/14/eidolon-code-review/">Eidolon</a> and <a href="/blog/2015/11/05/Emergence-Code-Review/">Emergence</a>. Folio is an app that's shipped to the App Store in early 2012, it's used by our Partners to showcase their works offline, at fairs and on the go. If you want the full spiel, check out <a href="http://folio.artsy.net">this microsite</a>.</p>

<p>This video talks through a lot of the critical codepaths that go from the App's launch to sending an email, which is the main use-case for the app. We have another video coming up which exclusively covers how Folio does sync between the Artsy API and the app.</p>

<p>Jump <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=Xhd25hFzN4o">to YouTube</a> for the video, or click more for a smaller inline preview.</p>

<!-- more -->


<p></div></div><iframe width='100%' height='600' src='https://www.youtube.com/embed/Xhd25hFzN4o ' frameborder='0' allowfullscreen></iframe><div class='meta-container'><header>&nbsp;</header></div><div class='content-container'><div class='entry-content'></p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Being a Good OSS Citizen]]></title>
    <link href="http://artsy.github.io/blog/2016/01/28/being-a-good-open-source-citizen/"/>
    <updated>2016-01-28T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <id>http://artsy.github.io/blog/2016/01/28/being-a-good-open-source-citizen</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Let's take a look at the day in the life of an open source citizen: me. On our app, I was given <a href="https://github.com/artsy/eigen/issues/971">an issue</a> that would allow users to refine what kinds of sale artworks they were looking at, and it included this <em>awesome</em> slider control so they could set min/max price ranges.</p>

<!-- more -->


<p></div></div><a href='/images/2016-01-28-being-a-good-open-source-citizen/design.png'><img src="/images/2016-01-28-being-a-good-open-source-citizen/design.png"></a><div class='meta-container'><header>&nbsp;</header></div><div class='date-container'>&nbsp;</div><div class='content-container'><div class='entry-content'></p>

<p>Nice.</p>

<p>But iOS doesn't have a slider like that built into UIKit, so I headed to <a href="https://cocoapods.org">CocoaPods.org</a> to find something that would work for me. Searching for "range slider" yielded a bunch of results, and I looked through three or four of them.</p>

<p>I picked <a href="https://cocoapods.org/pods/MARKRangeSlider">this one</a> because it did <em>almost exactly</em> what I needed, provided a reasonable level of customization, and had a history of development leading up to a recent v1.0.</p>

<p>But I said it did "almost exactly" what I needed, which meant I'd have to modify it. At this point, many developers either look for a different library or abandon the idea of using an existing library altogether and invent one themselves. That's a shame, because it's almost always faster and easier to improve an existing library than it is to build your own.</p>

<p>So let's step through what I did to modify this library for my needs. First, I checked to see if there was an issue for my feature already opened on the repository; maybe someone else had tried this, and I could benefit from their experience! That wasn't the case, so I forked the library to my personal account and cloned my fork locally. Now I can modify the library's code and commit it to my fork.</p>

<p>Next I add the library to my <code>Podfile</code>, but I'm clever about it.</p>

<pre><code class="rb">pod 'MARKRangeSlider', :path =&gt; '../MARKRangeSlider'
</code></pre>

<p>This tells CocoaPods that I'm <em>working</em> on the pod, and, it is stored in a local directory (the one where I cloned my fork). This makes it a "development pod", so that the files in Xcode are actually the ones I've cloned locally.</p>

<p>This is a really important, but subtle point. Normally, CocoaPods downloads copies of the files and stores those copies, but in this case, it refers to the existing files. It doesn't copy them at all: any changes I make to the library while working on my app are to the files I cloned. That means they can be easily committed and pushed up to my fork.</p>

<p>That's exactly what I did. I made my changes from within the app until I was satisfied, and <a href="https://github.com/ashfurrow/MARKRangeSlider/commit/aefbeb181b62c8c257a7d0ada1e75834489b1909">pushed them to my fork</a>, then pointed the <code>Podfile</code> to my fork of the pod.</p>

<pre><code class="rb">pod 'MARKRangeSlider', :git =&gt; 'https://github.com/ashfurrow/MARKRangeSlider.git'
</code></pre>

<p>Nice. At this point, I continued on as a developer, running a <code>pod install</code> to download the forked library with my commits as usual. I finished building the feature and <a href="https://github.com/artsy/eigen/pull/1075">PR'd it using my fork</a>.</p>

<p><img src="/images/2016-01-28-being-a-good-open-source-citizen/done.gif" alt="" /></p>

<p>I could've stopped here, but that'd be a shame. Someone else might want the same changes I made, and I should submit them back. I <a href="https://github.com/vadymmarkov/MARKRangeSlider/pull/22">opened a PR</a> on the library to contribute my changes back, and I made sure to explain <em>why</em> my changes were necessary. Because our app is open source, I was even able to link to <em>our</em> PR to show the library author how their work was being used.</p>

<p>The next morning, I woke up to find my PR had been merged, and after the author pushed an updated version of the library (including my changes), I updated our app's <code>Podfile</code> once more.</p>

<pre><code class="rb">pod 'MARKRangeSlider'
</code></pre>

<p>Then ran <code>pod update MARKRangeSlider</code> so it would update <em>just</em> that pod, and point it to the new release. I re-ran the unit tests to make sure I hadn't broken anything, and <a href="https://github.com/artsy/eigen/pull/1077">PR'd the change</a>.</p>

<p>This sounds like a lot, and having written it all out, I guess it is. But it's a series of small steps, not big ones, and I've worked like this long enough that it's second-nature to me now.</p>

<hr />

<p>I believe that using existing open source libraries is almost always better than writing your own, and I believe that improvements made to open source ought to be shared. Those beliefs shape my behaviour as a developer, and as a person.</p>

<p>Making your first contribution to a project may seem scary, but we all <a href="https://github.com/B-Sides/ELCSlider/pull/1">start somewhere</a>. It gets easier, and in time, you will become a paragon of open source citizenry.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
