<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: OSS | Artsy Engineering]]></title>
  <link href="https://artsy.github.io/blog/categories/oss/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="https://artsy.github.io/"/>
  <updated>2023-02-15T17:40:04+00:00</updated>
  <id>https://artsy.github.io/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Using OCR To Fix a Hilarious Bug]]></title>
    <link href="https://artsy.github.io/blog/2015/11/05/Using-OCR-To-Fix-A-Hilarious-Bug/"/>
    <updated>2015-11-05T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <id>https://artsy.github.io/blog/2015/11/05/Using-OCR-To-Fix-A-Hilarious-Bug</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>For a little while, we would get very strange bug reports. People would complain that artist thumbnails (viewed in several different contexts across the web and our iOS apps) would not be an image of the artist’s work, but rather text, which had inexplicably become an actual JPG. This wasn’t just text appearing in a <code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">div</code> that should contain an <code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">img</code> or something like that, these were actual JPG’s that were pictures of text.</p>

<p>We would fix these as they came up, chalking the strangeness up to some relic of an old image processing pipeline, data being migrated, etc.</p>

<p>However, the reports kept coming in. This blog post is about how we diagnosed this actual bug, and how we used a simple Ruby script and OCR to help us detect and fix the existing images.</p>

<!-- more -->

<p>Here’s an example of a bug report where the thumbnail for <a href="https://www.artsy.net/artist/marina-abramovic-1">Marina Abramović</a> became the text of her bio.</p>

<p><img src="/images/2015-11-12-hilarious-bug/search.png" alt="Bad Search" /></p>

<p>Here’s one from our <a href="https://github.com/artsy/eigen">iOS app</a> showing that thumbnails for related artists are set to their bios as well.</p>

<p><img src="/images/2015-11-12-hilarious-bug/eigen.png" alt="Bad Related Artists" /></p>

<p>Weird right? We eventually tracked down what was going on, and it’s actually perfectly summarized in <a href="https://github.com/blueimp/jQuery-File-Upload/pull/3356">this issue</a>. When someone copies text from Excel, it also generates an image of that cell or cells, and puts it into the clipboard. We immediately suspected something with <code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">pasteZone</code>, and the bug was easy to reproduce - have an image in your clipboard and paste anywhere on the page.</p>

<p>We have an admin panel that allows some metadata about an artist to be edited. This includes their bio, as well as a place to upload a representative image as their ‘cover thumbnail’.</p>

<p>As the issue describes, we had some text input fields, as well as a file upload form using <a href="https://github.com/blueimp/jQuery-File-Upload">Blueimp’s jQuery File Upload</a>. When you don’t specify a <code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">pasteZone</code> it defaults to the entire document. This means that a paste event anywhere on the page will trigger that event.</p>

<p>Our editorial team was using Microsoft Excel and Word to organize some data about the artist, including bios. When ready, a team member would copy and paste the bio into the bio input text field. This would also immediately fire the event for the image upload, which now automagically became an actual picture of the text of the bio. Our API and image processing pipeline would happily accept that, leading to the incredibly bizarre bug reports.</p>

<p>My immediate fix was to specify and scope <code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">pasteZone</code> (and similarly, <code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">dropZone</code>) to the element the file upload widget was bound to. That would prevent the problem from happening again. Taking a quick look art some random samples of artists, it looked like potentially thousands of records might have been affected and I became interested in a programmatic way to detect these images. A manual approach would have been very cumbersome.</p>

<p>Since the images were that of text, I decided to use OCR to remove artist thumbnails that it determined had ‘too much text’. This may have unset valid covers from artists that use lots of text in their work, such as <a href="https://www.artsy.net/artist/joseph-kosuth">Joseph Kosuth</a>. However, this was safe to do since we have some custom logic to fall back to an image of an iconic artwork by the artist in the case of a missing thumbnail.</p>

<p>To get OCR functionality in Ruby, I decided to use <a href="https://github.com/tesseract-ocr/tesseract">Tesseract</a>, a great OSS library. Once I had it installed, I used a <a href="https://github.com/meh/ruby-tesseract-ocr">ruby wrapper</a> to make using it easier.</p>

<p>The script eventually turned into something like:</p>

<div class="language-ruby highlighter-rouge"><div class="highlight"><pre class="highlight"><code><span class="c1"># initialize and configure Tesseract</span>
<span class="n">engine</span> <span class="o">=</span> <span class="no">Tesseract</span><span class="o">::</span><span class="no">Engine</span><span class="p">.</span><span class="nf">new</span> <span class="k">do</span> <span class="o">|</span><span class="n">config</span><span class="o">|</span>
  <span class="n">config</span><span class="p">.</span><span class="nf">language</span>  <span class="o">=</span> <span class="ss">:eng</span>
  <span class="n">config</span><span class="p">.</span><span class="nf">blacklist</span> <span class="o">=</span> <span class="s1">'|'</span>
<span class="k">end</span>

<span class="c1"># iterate over artists and pull their thumbnails</span>
<span class="c1"># given the URL to a publicly accessible image at img</span>

<span class="n">text</span> <span class="o">=</span> <span class="n">engine</span><span class="p">.</span><span class="nf">text_for</span><span class="p">(</span><span class="n">img</span><span class="p">)</span>
<span class="n">text</span> <span class="o">=</span> <span class="n">text</span><span class="p">.</span><span class="nf">gsub</span><span class="p">(</span><span class="sr">/[^a-z ]/i</span><span class="p">,</span> <span class="s1">''</span><span class="p">).</span><span class="nf">gsub</span><span class="p">(</span><span class="s1">' '</span><span class="p">,</span> <span class="s1">''</span><span class="p">)</span>
<span class="k">if</span> <span class="n">text</span><span class="p">.</span><span class="nf">length</span> <span class="o">&gt;</span> <span class="mi">30</span>
  <span class="nb">puts</span> <span class="s2">"Found problematic artist </span><span class="si">#{</span><span class="n">artist_doc</span><span class="p">[</span><span class="s1">'last'</span><span class="p">]</span><span class="si">}</span><span class="s2">"</span>
  <span class="c1"># ...</span>
<span class="k">end</span>
</code></pre></div></div>

<p>So all we do is find all the text in an image, and then remove any garbage characters or artifacts from the OCR analysis, and then use 30 as an arbitrary cutoff to determine if an image was problematic. If the image had more than 30 characters as detected by the OCR library, we wound up unsetting it from the artist.</p>

<p>The additional logic to set artist covers from their iconic artworks was already in place, and I ran this script in production, identifying and unsetting over 1000 problematic thumbnails. And we haven’t gotten any new reports of this bug since then :)</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Releasecop Tracks Stale Releases]]></title>
    <link href="https://artsy.github.io/blog/2015/09/01/releasecop-tracks-stale-releases/"/>
    <updated>2015-09-01T17:30:00+00:00</updated>
    <id>https://artsy.github.io/blog/2015/09/01/releasecop-tracks-stale-releases</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Artsy practices a sort of <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Continuous_delivery">continuous delivery</a>. We keep release cycles short and the process of reviewing, testing, and deploying our software as reliable, fast, and automated as possible. (This blog has touched on these practices <a href="http://artsy.github.io/blog/categories/testing/">multiple</a> <a href="http://artsy.github.io/blog/categories/continuous-integration">times</a>.)</p>

<p>Usually, commits that have been reviewed and merged are immediately built and tested. Successfully built versions of the codebase are often automatically deployed to a staging environment. On an automated or frequent-but-manual basis, that version is deployed to a production environment. Thus, commits form a pipeline:</p>

<ul>
  <li>From developers’ working branches</li>
  <li>To the master branch</li>
  <li>Through a hopefully-successful build</li>
  <li>To a staging environment</li>
  <li>To production</li>
</ul>

<p>The number of apps and services we deploy has grown to <em>dozens</em> per team, so sometimes things fall through the cracks. We’ve been using <a href="https://github.com/joeyAghion/releasecop">Releasecop</a> for the last few months to get gentle email reminders when an environment could use a deploy.</p>

<!-- more -->

<div class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge"><div class="highlight"><pre class="highlight"><code>gem install releasecop
releasecop edit
</code></pre></div></div>

<p>This opens a <em>manifest</em> file where you can describe the sequence of git remotes and branches that make up your own release pipeline. For example:</p>

<div class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge"><div class="highlight"><pre class="highlight"><code>{
  "projects": {
    "charge": [
      { "name": "master", "git": "git@github.com:artsy/charge.git" },
      { "name": "staging", "git": "git@heroku.com:charge-staging.git" },
      { "name": "production", "git": "git@heroku.com:charge-production.git" }
    ],
    "gravity": [
      { "name": "master", "git": "git@github.com:artsy/gravity.git" },
      { "name": "master-succeeded", "git": "git@github.com:artsy/gravity.git", "branch": "master-succeeded" },
      { "name": "staging", "git": "git@github.com:artsy/gravity.git", "branch": "staging" },
      { "name": "production", "git": "git@github.com:artsy/gravity.git", "branch": "production" }
    ]
  }
}
</code></pre></div></div>

<p>The <code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">charge</code> app is a typical deployment to Heroku. Work progresses from the <code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">master</code> branch to a <code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">charge-staging</code> app to a <code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">charge-production</code> app. The <code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">gravity</code> app is a more complicated, non-Heroku deployment. It updates git branches to reflect what has been merged (<code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">master</code>), tested (<code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">master-succeeded</code>), deployed to staging, and deployed to production.</p>

<p>Run the <code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">releasecop check [app]</code> command to report the status of your apps’ releases:</p>

<div class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge"><div class="highlight"><pre class="highlight"><code>$ releasecop check --all
charge...
  staging is up-to-date with master
  production is up-to-date with staging
gravity...
  master-succeeded is up-to-date with master
  staging is up-to-date with master-succeeded
  production is behind staging by:
    06ca969 2015-09-04 [config] Replace Apple Push Notification certificates that expire today. (Eloy Durán)
    171121f 2015-09-03 Admin-only API for cancelling a bid (Matthew Zikherman)
    4c5feea 2015-09-02 install mongodb client in Docker so that import rake tasks can run (Barry Hoggard)
    95347d1 2015-08-31 Update to delayed_job cookbook that works with Chef 11.10 (Joey Aghion)
2 project(s) checked. 1 environment(s) out-of-date.
</code></pre></div></div>

<p>A nightly <a href="https://jenkins-ci.org/">Jenkins</a> job emails us the results, but a cron job could work equally well.</p>

<p><a href="https://github.com/joeyAghion/releasecop">Releasecop</a> reminds us to deploy ready commits and close the loop on in-progress work. We hope you find it useful. (Pull requests are welcome!)</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
