<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: panel | Artsy Engineering]]></title>
  <link href="http://artsy.github.io/blog/categories/panel/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://artsy.github.io/"/>
  <updated>2018-12-16T10:16:31+00:00</updated>
  <id>http://artsy.github.io/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[C4Q&A: 2]]></title>
    <link href="http://artsy.github.io/blog/2018/01/10/C4Q-QandA-two/"/>
    <updated>2018-01-10T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <id>http://artsy.github.io/blog/2018/01/10/C4Q-QandA-two</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><a href="https://www.c4q.nyc">C4Q is</a> C4Q is a non-for-profit hacker school based in NYC. We've had members of the Artsy team help out by being TAs, running committees and steering the curriculum as Engineers in the industry for many years. In 2017, C4Q reached out to arrange a meetup between Artsy engineers and students who were learning Android and Web development. This year we ran a panel for the other half of the C4Q students who study iOS and Web.</p>

<p>We got an entirely new set of panelists to cover similar topics as <a href="/blog/2017/10/10/C4Q-QandA/">last time</a> - so if you're wondering
what it's like in the industry, and what makes an Artsy engineer. The video is after the link.</p>

<!-- more -->




<center>
<iframe width='100%' height='600' src='https://www.youtube.com/embed/pp0vNokDzaQ' frameborder='0' allowfullscreen></iframe>
</center>


<p>Our twitter links in sitting order: <a href="https://twitter.com/realmrblock">@realmrblock</a>, <a href="https://twitter.com/sweir27">@sweir27</a>, <a href="https://twitter.com/yuki24">@yuki24</a>, <a href="https://twitter.com/cychi1210">@cychi1210</a>, <a href="https://twitter.com/orta">@orta</a>, <a href="https://twitter.com/acjay1">@acjay1</a> let us know if you have any more questions.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[C4Q&A]]></title>
    <link href="http://artsy.github.io/blog/2017/10/10/C4Q-QandA/"/>
    <updated>2017-10-10T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <id>http://artsy.github.io/blog/2017/10/10/C4Q-QandA</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><a href="https://www.c4q.nyc">C4Q is</a> is a non-for-profit hacker school based in NYC. We've had members of the Artsy team help
out by being TAs, running committees and steering the curriculum as Engineers in the industry for many years. C4Q recently
reached out to arrange a meetup between Artsy engineers and students who are learning Android and Web development.</p>

<p>We thought it would be cool to have a talk from dB, our CTO, on what Artsy is and to also host a Q&amp;A panel with our
engineers. For a lot of the students it was their first time meeting a team of engineers, so we anticipated a lot of
question time.</p>

<p>In prepration for the event, I reached out to the internet for ideas on what sort of questions juniors would be interested
in hearing about, and people said they were also interested in hearing what we ended up being asked, and what our answers
were. This post has the youtube video of the opening talk, and our panel's Q &amp; A session.</p>

<p>It was really awesome to talk about how far we've grown as individuals, and what is important in our engineering lives.</p>

<!-- more -->




<center>
<iframe width='100%' height='600' src='https://www.youtube.com/embed/leiKlKXRvuk' frameborder='0' allowfullscreen></iframe>
</center>


<p>Our twitter links:  <a href="https://twitter.com/orta">@orta</a>, <a href="https://twitter.com/craigspaeth">@craigspaeth</a>, <a href="https://twitter.com/kana_abe">@kana_abe</a>, <a href="https://twitter.com/dblockdotorg">@dblockdotorg</a>, <a href="https://twitter.com/xtina_starr">@Xtina_Starr</a> let us know if
you have any more questions.</p>

<p>If you want more, there's also <a href="/blog/2018/01/10/C4Q-QandA-two/">part 2 with different engineers</a>.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
