<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: newrelic | Artsy Engineering]]></title>
  <link href="http://artsy.github.io/blog/categories/newrelic/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://artsy.github.io/"/>
  <updated>2018-12-16T10:16:31+00:00</updated>
  <id>http://artsy.github.io/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Measuring Performance in Grape APIs with NewRelic RPM]]></title>
    <link href="http://artsy.github.io/blog/2012/11/29/measuring-performance-in-grape-apis-with-new-relic/"/>
    <updated>2012-11-29T21:21:00+00:00</updated>
    <id>http://artsy.github.io/blog/2012/11/29/measuring-performance-in-grape-apis-with-new-relic</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Knowing how well your API performs in real time is essential to any successful project. That's because you can't fix what you can't measure.</p>

<p>We use and heavily contribute to <a href="http://github.com/intridea/grape">Grape</a>, a Ruby API DSL. Grape is a Rack middleware and we have been reporting API performance data to <a href="http://newrelic.com/">NewRelic</a> with code from <a href="http://code.dblock.org/new-relic-performance-instrumentation-with-grape-api">my older blog post</a>.</p>

<p>It's time to improve the reporting implementation and address performance monitoring in both development and production environments. Here's what a single API request breakdown is going to look like.</p>

<p><img src="/images/2012-11-29-measuring-performance-in-grape-apis-with-new-relic/transaction-detail.png"></p>

<!-- more -->


<a name="NewRelic.RPM"></a>
<h2>NewRelic RPM</h2>

<p>The first step is to add the <code>newrelic_rpm</code> gem to Gemfile, which implements the actual realtime performance reporting to NewRelic. We also use <a href="https://github.com/mongoid/mongoid">Mongoid</a> and the <a href="https://github.com/mongoid/moped">Moped</a> MongoDB Ruby driver, which can be instrumented with <code>newrelic_moped</code>.</p>

<pre><code class="ruby Gemfile">gem "newrelic_moped", "0.0.3"
gem "newrelic_rpm", "3.3.3"
</code></pre>

<p>You will need <code>config/newrelic.yml</code> in your application. Ours can be found in <a href="https://gist.github.com/4170458">this gist</a> and works well both locally and on Heroku.</p>

<a name="Instrumenting.Grape"></a>
<h2>Instrumenting Grape</h2>

<p>In the past we used <a href="https://gist.github.com/1233422">NewRelic::Agent::Instrumentation::API</a>, which works for any generic Rack middleware. This would report all API calls to NewRelic, but would treat requests to <em>/api/artist/andy-warhol</em> and <em>/api/artist/wassily-kandinsky</em> as unrelated. That is because the instrumenter is a Rack middleware that wraps Grape requests <em>before</em> they reach Grape. The only information available is the request URL, and not the actual API route that is going to be matched when the request is processed.</p>

<p>We want both requests to <em>/api/artist/andy-warhol</em> and <em>/api/artist/wassily-kandinsky</em> to be treated as <em>/api/artist/:id</em>. Lets insert a middleware inside Grape itself, once the URL has been matched to a route.</p>

<pre><code class="ruby api.rb">class API &lt;&lt; Grape::API
  use ApiNewRelicInstrumenter
  ...
end
</code></pre>

<p>The new instrumenter has access to the current API endpoint via <code>env['api.endpoint']</code> and reports data via NewRelic's <code>ControllerInstrumentation</code>.</p>

<pre><code class="ruby">class ApiNewRelicInstrumenter &lt; Grape::Middleware::Base
  include NewRelic::Agent::Instrumentation::ControllerInstrumentation

  def call(env)
    trace_options = {
      category: :rack,
      path: env['api.endpoint'].routes.first.route_path,
      request: request,
      ...
    }

    perform_action_with_newrelic_trace(trace_options) do
      yield
    end

  end
end
</code></pre>

<p>The complete code for <code>ApiNewRelicInstrumenter</code> can be found in <a href="https://gist.github.com/4170469">this gist</a>. It supports enabling and disabling performance reporting by setting <code>NEW_RELIC_ID</code> and works around NewRelic's method name limitations (these cannot contain slashes).</p>

<a name="Development.Environment"></a>
<h2>Development Environment</h2>

<p>You can now see NewRelic performance data in development mode, too. If you mount Grape inside Rails run <code>NEW_RELIC_ID=foo rails s</code>. Navigate to <em>http://localhost:3000/newrelic</em> to see your local traces.</p>

<p><img src="/images/2012-11-29-measuring-performance-in-grape-apis-with-new-relic/developer-mode.png"></p>

<p>Drill into an individual request to find several detailed breakdowns of how time was spent, including specific MongoDB queries (under "SQL", naturally).</p>

<p><img src="/images/2012-11-29-measuring-performance-in-grape-apis-with-new-relic/sql-detail.png"></p>

<p>NewRelic is a commercial product, but you can run development mode for free! Note that enabling this will triple your local Rails boot time: we enable development mode by setting <code>development_mode: &lt;%= !!ENV['NEW_RELIC_ID'] %&gt;</code> in <a href="https://gist.github.com/4170458">newrelic.rpm</a>.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
