<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: node | Artsy Engineering]]></title>
  <link href="http://artsy.github.io/blog/categories/node/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://artsy.github.io/"/>
  <updated>2016-10-16T12:00:09+00:00</updated>
  <id>http://artsy.github.io/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Helping the Web Towards OSS by Default]]></title>
    <link href="http://artsy.github.io/blog/2016/09/06/Milestone-on-OSS-by-Default/"/>
    <updated>2016-09-06T12:17:00+00:00</updated>
    <id>http://artsy.github.io/blog/2016/09/06/Milestone-on-OSS-by-Default</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>The main Artsy.net website for the desktop, <a href="https://github.com/artsy/force">Force</a>, was our first Artsy application to open its source code, <a href="http://artsy.github.io/author/craig">Craig</a> and <a href="http://artsy.github.io/author/brennan">Brennan</a> did it <a href="/blog/2014/09/05/we-open-sourced-our-isomorphic-javascript-website/">back in 2014</a>. Force's public offering laid the groundwork for the iOS OSS projects to come afterwards: <a href="/blog/2014/11/13/eidolon-retrospective/">Eidolon</a>, <a href="/blog/2015/04/28/how-we-open-sourced-eigen/">Eigen</a>, <a href="/blog/2015/08/06/open-sourcing-energy/">Energy</a> and <a href="/blog/2015/11/05/Emergence-Code-Review/">Emergence</a>.</p>

<p>Though Force wasn't quite Open Source by Default, it represented a <em>really</em> important step for  Artsy's OSS perspective but was not the end goal. We were opening our source, but not opening our process.</p>

<p>This month both <a href="https://github.com/artsy/force">Force</a>, the desktop version of <a href="https://www.artsy.net/">Artsy.net</a> and <a href="https://github.com/artsy/microgravity">Microgravity</a>, the mobile version - moved to being built entirely in the open. Read on to find out how.</p>

<!-- more -->


<h2>Force</h2>

<p>Over the course of the last month, I've sat on and off with Charles "<a href="http://charlesbroskoski.com/_/">Cab</a>" Broskoski, and figured out what it would take to migrate Force to work in the public. Previous to this, work happened on a private repo, and we would push that code to the public.</p>

<p>We scoped out what it would require, creating an issue that summarized the work. Then we waited for 2 weeks, to give people the chance to discuss the idea and to offer examples for why we should delay or not move. Not all projects <em>should</em> be OSS, and everyone should have a say when it affects them - giving some time let the team speak their mind. Especially during summer, when people were less active at work.</p>

<p></div></div><a href='/images/oss-milestone/force-oss.png'><img src="/images/oss-milestone/force-oss.png"></a><div class='meta-container'><header>&nbsp;</header></div><div class='date-container'>&nbsp;</div><div class='content-container'><div class='entry-content'></p>

<p>It had been 9 months since the last commit to the public repo, and so auditing the commits was a matter of investigating into configuration files, and seeing what's changed since the last public commit.</p>

<p>Next up, we renamed the current <code>force</code> repo to <code>force-private</code>. This was to keep the old issues and PRs around after we moved to working in the public. With <code>force</code> now available we re-named the already public project.</p>

<p>We then ensured all outstanding PRs were merged or closed, and pushed the commits from <code>force-private</code> to the now OSS <code>force</code>.</p>

<h3>CI</h3>

<p>To get back up to speed we needed to set up CI, figuring this out took time.</p>

<p>We got testing up and running in no time. However, Force is deployed via <a href="https://semaphoreci.com/">Semaphore CI</a>, and to deploy we needed to push compiled assets to S3. To pull that off, we needed access to an S3 key, and token.</p>

<p>In our iOS projects, <a href="https://github.com/artsy/eidolon/pull/607">we do not expose environment variables</a> to PRs from forks, so we don't expect them to pass from external contributors. This is fine, because we have <a href="http://artsy.github.io/blog/2016/01/13/OSS-Expectations/">different expectations</a> for OSS apps vs libraries. We do this to ensure that we don't receive a PR that adds <code>printenv</code> to the CI scripts, exposing our secret keys.</p>

<p>As we couldn't add the keys to our testing environment, we added them to our heroku environment then took them from that. Semaphore sets up our heroku environment only during deployment, so in the deployment phase, we can use a line like:</p>

<pre><code class="sh">export FORCE_S3_KEY=$(heroku config:get FORCE_S3_KEY --app force-production)
</code></pre>

<p>This sets up the environment like we used to have it when force was private.</p>

<h3>Team</h3>

<p>We needed to move all the team members to using the OSS version of our apps. This is a little bit complicated as <a href="/blog/2012/01/29/how-art-dot-sy-uses-github-to-build-art-dot-sy/">we work from forks</a>. <a href="http://www.anandarooproy.com/portfolio">Roop</a>, an engineer on the web team, created a "Force OSS Dance Script" ( sidenote: <a href="http://www.anandarooproy.com/portfolio">his site</a> is worth a visit, there's 15 years of interesting maps. )</p>

<pre><code class="sh">## RENAME THE OLD REPO

# on GitHub

# - Go to my fork https://github.com/&lt;username&gt;/force
# - Go to Settings tab
# - Rename repo to "force-private"

# on my local machine

mv force force-private
cd force-private
git remote set-url upstream git@github.com:artsy/force-private.git
git remote set-url origin git@github.com:&lt;username&gt;/force-private.git


## FORK AND CLONE THE NEW REPO

# back to GitHub

# - Go to the new Force repo https://github.com/artsy/force
# - Fork it to my account

# back to my local machine

git clone git@github.com:&lt;username&gt;/force.git
cd force
git remote add upstream git@github.com:artsy/force.git
cp ../force-private/.env ./
cp ../force-private/node_modules ./ # or just 'npm install' again


# all good now - both repos on local machine with correct remotes, envs, deps
</code></pre>

<p>For Force, all the same commits existed in both repos, so it would be difficult to push secrets to the open repo by accident. However, individuals did to sync up a new version of their forks.</p>

<p>And that, is how we moved force into OSS by Default. :+1: - We'll cover the issues migration later.</p>

<h2>Microgravity</h2>

<p>I have a lot of love for Microgravity. It's the web project that made <a href="/blog/2015/04/28/how-we-open-sourced-eigen/">Eigen</a> possible. Once Force had moved, I started spending time with Craig trying to understand what it would take to open up Microgravity.</p>

<p></div></div><a href='/images/oss-milestone/micrograv-oss.png'><img src="/images/oss-milestone/micrograv-oss.png"></a><div class='meta-container'><header>&nbsp;</header></div><div class='date-container'>&nbsp;</div><div class='content-container'><div class='entry-content'></p>

<p>It is no surprise to find a lot of overlap, both projects are based on the same foundations: <a href="http://ezeljs.com">Ezel.js</a>.</p>

<p>We didn't trust the commit history for microgravity, so we nuked it. Same as our native OSS apps.</p>

<p>We came up with a pattern to make it easier for people to migrate issues, we created a <code>migrate</code> GitHub label that anyone can apply to an issue in a private repo. Then we use <a href="https://github-issue-mover.appspot.com">Issue Mover for GitHub</a> with some inline JavaScript to loop through all our issues to migrate. As it's applying a label we can ask product owners and designers to choose ones that are important to them too.</p>

<p>--</p>

<p>I love that I got to help make these changes, the web team started the process of opening our apps at Artsy, then the mobile team took the next big step. Now the teams are both in lock-step, and if you work on the front-end at Artsy - OSS by Default is the way we all work now.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[On our implementation of React Native]]></title>
    <link href="http://artsy.github.io/blog/2016/08/24/On-Emission/"/>
    <updated>2016-08-24T12:17:00+00:00</updated>
    <id>http://artsy.github.io/blog/2016/08/24/On-Emission</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<center>
 <img src="/images/emission/emission-logo-artsy.svg" style="height:300px;">
</center>


<p>I arrived fashionably late to the <a href="/blog/2016/08/15/React-Native-at-Artsy/">React Native party</a> in Artsy. I had been a part of our <a href="/blog/2016/08/09/the-tech-behind-live-auction-integration/">Auctions Team</a>, where we worked in Swift with <a href="https://cocoapods.org/pods/Interstellar">some light-FRP</a>. We were not affected by the 4 months of simultaneous work on moving to React Native, at all.</p>

<p>It was a quiet revolution. I did not have to install <code>npm</code>, I made zero changes to the code for auctions and the whole app's infrastructure barely changed. Yet we moved to making all new code inside our 3 year old iOS app use React Native. What gives?</p>

<p>Well, first up we weren't planning a re-write, we don't have that kind of luxury and the scope of our app is too big compared to the team working on it. Second, we reused existing dependency infrastructure to support JavaScript based apps. Read on to find out what that looks like.</p>

<!-- more -->


<h3>Why we were in a good position to do this</h3>

<p>Let's talk a little about the Artsy flagship app, <a href="https://github.com/artsy/eigen/">Eigen</a>. It's an app that aimed to comprehensively cover the art world. From <a href="https://www.artsy.net/shows">Shows</a> to <a href="https://www.artsy.net/galleries">Galleries</a>, <a href="https://www.artsy.net/art-fairs">Fairs</a> to <a href="https://www.artsy.net/auctions">Auctions</a>, <a href="https://www.artsy.net/institutions">Museums</a> to <a href="https://www.artsy.net/articles">Magazines</a>.</p>

<p>It all looks a bit like this:</p>

<p></div></div><a href='/images/emission/eigen-overview.jpg'><img src="/images/emission/eigen-overview.jpg"></a><div class='meta-container'><header>&nbsp;</header></div><div class='date-container'>&nbsp;</div><div class='content-container'><div class='entry-content'></p>

<p>Our app neatly splits into two areas of view controllers, ones that act as a browser chrome, and individual view controllers that normally map 1:1 to <a href="https://github.com/artsy/eigen/blob/master/Artsy/App/ARSwitchBoard.m#L122">routes</a> on the Artsy website.</p>

<p>For example, the route <code>artsy.net/artwork/glenn-brown-suffer-well</code> maps to the native <code>ARArtworkViewController</code>.</p>

<p></div></div><a href='/images/emission/eigen.svg'><img src="/images/emission/eigen.svg"></a><div class='meta-container'><header>&nbsp;</header></div><div class='date-container'>&nbsp;</div><div class='content-container'><div class='entry-content'></p>

<p>Just as a browser knows very little about the individual content of the pages that it's rendering, the eigen chrome exists <em>relatively</em> independent of the view controllers that are showing.</p>

<p>Each view controller also knows very little about each-other, so actions that trigger a new view controller are generally done by creating a string route and passing it through the routing system. I've wrote about this pattern in <a href="https://artsy.github.io/blog/2015/08/15/Cocoa-Architecture-Router-Pattern/">Cocoa Architecture: Router Pattern</a>.</p>

<p>Interestingly, if the router cannot route a view controller, it will pass through to a web view. This is why we consider the app a <a href="http://artsy.github.io/blog/2015/08/24/Cocoa-Architecture-Hybrid-Apps/">hybrid app</a>. This pattern means adding new view controllers is extremely easy.</p>

<h3>Introducing Emission</h3>

<p>Emission is what we use to contain all of our React Native components. Our flagship app Eigen, can depend on and use without needing to bother with the implementation details of React Native. At it's core, Emission is:</p>

<ul>
<li>A node module.</li>
<li>A CocoaPod.</li>
<li>An iOS App.</li>
</ul>


<h4>The Node Module</h4>

<p>Emission itself, is a node module. In our case, it is a JavaScript library that exposes 3 JavaScript objects.</p>

<pre><code class="javascript">/* @flow */
'use strict';

import Containers from './lib/containers';
import Components from './lib/components';
import Routes from './lib/relay/routes';

import './lib/relay/config';
import './lib/app_registry';

export default {
  Containers,
  Components,
  Routes,
};
</code></pre>

<p>Another node project can have Emission as a dependency - then can access our <code>Container</code>s, <code>Component</code>s and <code>Route</code>s. A container is a <a href="https://facebook.github.io/relay/docs/api-reference-relay-container.html">Relay container</a>, a component is a <a href="https://facebook.github.io/react/docs/component-api.html">React Component</a> and a Route is a <a href="https://facebook.github.io/relay/docs/guides-routes.html#content">Relay Route</a>.</p>

<p>The thing that's interesting from the integration side, is that each <code>Container</code> is effectively a View Controller that Emission provides to a host application. React Native ignores  the concept of view controllers from the Cocoa world, so we have an <a href="https://github.com/artsy/emission/blob/eb9d0f6ca0edd3eb9f07dd9ff3b8499f095bc45b/Pod/Classes/ViewControllers/ARComponentViewController.m">ARComponentViewController</a> which is subclassed for each exposed <code>Component</code> class.</p>

<h4>The iOS App</h4>

<p>The iOS app acts as a host target for the CocoaPod, and provides an instance of an <a href="https://github.com/artsy/emission/blob/master/Pod/Classes/Core/AREmission.m">AREmission</a> object to the view controllers using React Native. The app is nothing special, it is the default app that is created using <code>pod lib create</code>. We then <a href="https://github.com/artsy/emission/blob/eb9d0f6ca0edd3eb9f07dd9ff3b8499f095bc45b/Example/Podfile">use CocoaPods</a> to bring in React from inside the <code>node_modules/</code> folder the Emission node module creates.</p>

<p>The <code>AREmission</code> instance is the intermediary between the host-app (<a href="https://github.com/artsy/emission/blob/eb9d0f6ca0edd3eb9f07dd9ff3b8499f095bc45b/Example/Emission/AppDelegate.m#L56">The Emission Example app</a>, or <a href="https://github.com/artsy/eigen/blob/41b00f6fe497de9e902315104089370dea417017/Artsy/App/ARAppDelegate%2BEmission.m">Eigen</a>.) It has an API for handling routing, and passing authentication credentials into the React Native world.</p>

<p>We use the example app to do development inside React Native. As of right now, it is simply a tableview that provides a list of view controllers <a href="https://github.com/artsy/emission/blob/eb9d0f6ca0edd3eb9f07dd9ff3b8499f095bc45b/Example/Emission/AppDelegate.m#L159-L169">that represent an exposed Container</a>. Once you are in the right view controller, you can rely on <a href="http://facebook.github.io/react-native/releases/0.31/docs/debugging.html#automatic-reloading">Hot Reloading</a> to simplify your work.</p>

<h4>The Pod</h4>

<p>An important part of working with React Native, is that you can choose to use native code when appropriate. The <a href="https://github.com/artsy/emission/blob/eb9d0f6ca0edd3eb9f07dd9ff3b8499f095bc45b/Emission.podspec">Pod for</a> Emission, created entirely in Objective-C, provides:</p>

<ul>
<li>Communication between React Native and the host app objects via <a href="https://facebook.github.io/react-native/docs/native-modules-ios.html">native modules</a>.</li>
<li><code>UIViewController</code> subclasses for Host apps to consume.</li>
<li>Bridges for existing native views (like our <a href="https://github.com/artsy/extraction/blob/d6a32186f7098eb2ec5d05e2fb5302a8378eff70/Extraction/Classes/ARSwitchView.m">SwitchView</a>) into React Native.</li>
</ul>


<p>The choice of Objective-C is for simplicity, and language stability. Swift is technically an option, but it's not  worth the complications for <a href="https://github.com/artsy/emission/tree/eb9d0f6ca0edd3eb9f07dd9ff3b8499f095bc45b/Pod/Classes">a few simple objects</a>.</p>

<p>In order to share native views with our host app, Eigen, we created a library to just hold the shared UI components, <a href="https://github.com/artsy/extraction">Extraction</a>. These are <a href="https://github.com/artsy/extraction/tree/d6a32186f7098eb2ec5d05e2fb5302a8378eff70/Extraction/Classes">factored out of Eigen</a>, and into a pod. Emission and Eigen have this as a dependency.</p>

<h4>Pod Deployment</h4>

<p>What makes this work well, from the perspective of Eigen is that the React Native comes in atomically. The Podspec <a href="https://github.com/artsy/emission/blob/master/Emission.podspec#L17-L18">references</a> the few native classes, and a single JavaScript file.</p>

<p>This JavaScript file is the bundled version of all our React Native code. It's <a href="https://github.com/artsy/emission/blob/eb9d0f6ca0edd3eb9f07dd9ff3b8499f095bc45b/package.json#L7">updated  by running</a> <code>npm run bundle</code>. This generates both the minified JS, and a source map so that we can transcribe the error reports into the code we write.</p>

<p>Using the CocoaPod, Emission can provide native view controllers that use React Native under the hood. The host app does not need to know the underlying details like <code>npm</code>.</p>

<h3>On Emission</h3>

<p>Whether this is a pattern other apps can follow is hard to say, we were in a great position to do this. Our app has view controllers that have very little communication with each other and the host app does not need to bridge large amounts of information.</p>

<p>As ever, our work is open source, and we ensure that anyone can download and run Emission, so if you'd like to understand more, clone <a href="https://github.com/artsy/emission#reactions--emissions">artsy/emission</a> and study the implementation.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Using VS Code for JavaScript]]></title>
    <link href="http://artsy.github.io/blog/2016/08/15/vscode/"/>
    <updated>2016-08-15T22:17:00+00:00</updated>
    <id>http://artsy.github.io/blog/2016/08/15/vscode</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<center>
 <img src="/images/vscode/vscode_logo_artsy.svg" style="width:300px;">
</center>


<p>I'm an old school TextMate user, who has also been using Xcode for the last decade. These two sit at a very opposite ends of an "editor" spectrum.</p>

<p>TextMate is extremely bare bones at the core, but introduced the idea of bundles as plugins. Making it really easy for others to build their own plugins for their own contexts. Xcode on the other-hand includes a 3D scene editor, the best interface builder I've seen, super rich debugging tools and close to zero support for improving it yourself.</p>

<p>As we agreed on moving to React Native, we needed to decide what the team should use for <a href="https://github.com/artsy/emission/blob/master/docs/vscode.md">working in that environment</a>. After experimentation with many editors, we decided on Microsoft's <a href="https://code.visualstudio.com/">Visual Studio Code</a>.</p>

<p>We wanted to keep a lot of the best features from Xcode, while working in a completely JavaScript environment. For example: debuggers, inline errors, auto-complete, symbol mapping and to ideally have them all inside a single editor.</p>

<p>Let's dig into the principals of how Visual Studio Code works, what makes it a better option for us, and what parts of it really shine.</p>

<!-- more -->


<hr />

<h3>What is Visual Studio Code?</h3>

<p>Visual Studio Code (VS Code) is <em>yet another</em>, JavaScript-based text editor. It's built atop of GitHub's <a href="http://electron.atom.io">Electron</a>. Electron is a framework for writing native apps as easy as building websites. It started as a web component for some Microsoft web-service, and eventually evolved into a fully-fledged text editor.</p>

<h4>IDE - Editor hybrid</h4>

<p>Visual Studio Code (VS Code) believes that the sweet-spot between and IDE and a plain Text Editor, is somewhere a little bit closer to the IDE side.</p>

<p></div></div><a href='/images/vscode/editors.png'><img src="/images/vscode/editors.png"></a><div class='meta-container'><header>&nbsp;</header></div><div class='date-container'>&nbsp;</div><div class='content-container'><div class='entry-content'></p>

<p>This means instead of the Text-Editor style folder based approach, VS Code expects to set up a project structure per-project to start supporting from of the more useful IDE-like features.</p>

<p>It supports TextMate style plugins (called Extensions) through a controlled, but expanding <a href="https://code.visualstudio.com/docs/extensions/overview">extension API</a>. The extension API work takes an <a href="https://developer.apple.com/library/mac/documentation/MacOSX/Conceptual/BPSystemStartup/Chapters/CreatingXPCServices.html">Apple-like</a> approach to ensuring stability by having all extensions run outside of the host process. <a href="https://code.visualstudio.com/docs/extensions/our-approach">This approach</a> ensures any extension crash does not take down the editor.</p>

<p>It's also smart about deciding when to load an extension, for example, my <a href="https://marketplace.visualstudio.com/items?itemName=Orta.vscode-danger">Danger</a> extension will <a href="https://github.com/orta/vscode-danger/blob/a21ccc101b2b1c1be595b10565bca9c88242fb6f/package.json#L18-L20">only load</a> if there is a <code>Dangerfile</code> in the root of the workspace.</p>

<p>These two approaches to extensions are specifically aimed at <a href="https://discuss.atom.io/t/why-is-atom-so-slow/11376">addressing issues</a> seen inside Atom, where any user actions can be / are blocked by extensions, and extensions have full-reign to make any change they want. Even on my Mac Pro, there is a noticable lag. I initially assumed this was the "JavaScript tax" for all Electron apps, but VS Code is fast.</p>

<h3>Making Intellisense</h3>

<p>By default a JavaScript project does not have a way to provide auto-completion, or in VS Code's terminology: Intellisense. Trying to make auto-complete based on a <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Read%E2%80%93eval%E2%80%93print_loop">REPL</a> can only get you so far, because it has to be wary against functions with side-effects. Other alternatives are to build an <a href="http://jointjs.com/demos/javascript-ast">AST</a> from the code, and then introspect that.</p>

<p>In Xcode the auto-complete tools are powered by the type systems of Objective-C and Swift. This means that you can know the structure of an object, without having to dig inside it, potentially breaking it in the process. Vanilla JavaScript does not have a type system. There are a few root classes though: String, Object, Number etc.</p>

<p>To work around this problem, VS Code uses <a href="http://www.typescriptlang.org">TypeScript</a> behind the scenes. TypeScript is a language that compiles down to JavaScript which provides a typing structure on top of JavaScript. This is a similar approach to how <a href="https://flowtype.org">Flow works</a> too, which is the language <a href="https://github.com/artsy/emission/pull/220">we write React Native</a> in.</p>

<p>This can work out really well for your own classes if you are declaring your types, but the npm ecosystem is <em>full</em> of untyped JavaScript, and a lot of your work is about sitting atop those abstractions. The fix for this is offered via <a href="http://definitelytyped.org">DefinitelyTyped</a> which provides type definitions for popular npm modules. For example here is <a href="https://github.com/DefinitelyTyped/DefinitelyTyped/blob/master/redux/redux.d.ts">one for Redux</a> - these act like <a href="https://github.com/artsy/eigen/blob/master/Artsy/App/ARSwitchBoard.h">header files in Objective-C</a> - offering inline documentation, and the shape of the object.</p>

<p>I use an extension to keep these up to date and to have them installed in every project I work in: <a href="https://marketplace.visualstudio.com/items?itemName=jvitor83.types-autoinstaller">Types auto installer</a>. Here's an example of auto-complete for <a href="http://redux.js.org/docs/api/Store.html">a Redux store</a>.</p>

<p></div></div><a href='/images/vscode/redux.png'><img src="/images/vscode/redux.png"></a><div class='meta-container'><header>&nbsp;</header></div><div class='date-container'>&nbsp;</div><div class='content-container'><div class='entry-content'></p>

<p>It'll also provide information about the parameters, which is a life-saver for me. Having grown up with <a href="https://developer.apple.com/library/ios/documentation/Swift/Conceptual/Swift_Programming_Language/Functions.html">named</a> <a href="https://robots.thoughtbot.com/ruby-2-keyword-arguments">parameters</a>.</p>

<p></div></div><a href='/images/vscode/redux-params.png'><img src="/images/vscode/redux-params.png"></a><div class='meta-container'><header>&nbsp;</header></div><div class='date-container'>&nbsp;</div><div class='content-container'><div class='entry-content'></p>

<h3>Runtime</h3>

<p>Using console logs to debug isn't an acceptable answer when debugging for me anymore. <a href="http://blog.cleancoder.com/uncle-bob/2016/07/27/TheChurn.html">That's churn</a> that I'm not willing to lose time to. Luckily for me, VS Code supports debugging across many languages.</p>

<p>It does this by having a generic VS Code <a href="https://code.visualstudio.com/docs/extensions/example-debuggers">Debug Protocol</a> which lets extensions use their own processes to run the debugger. So the ruby debugger runs on the <a href="https://github.com/rubyide/vscode-ruby#debugger"><code>ruby-debug-ide</code></a> gem, and for node-based projects it uses the debugger built into node.</p>

<p>So, here is a common case. I want to start up my web-server, so I need to run <code>npm dev</code>. I can run this from VS Code:</p>

<p></div></div><a href='/images/vscode/start.png'><img src="/images/vscode/start.png"></a><div class='meta-container'><header>&nbsp;</header></div><div class='date-container'>&nbsp;</div><div class='content-container'><div class='entry-content'></p>

<p>Once that's running - I can attach a debugger. This is listing all of the available node processes on my computer:</p>

<p></div></div><a href='/images/vscode/attatch.png'><img src="/images/vscode/attatch.png"></a><div class='meta-container'><header>&nbsp;</header></div><div class='date-container'>&nbsp;</div><div class='content-container'><div class='entry-content'></p>

<p>Then I can add a breakpoint, and when it is triggered, I have a full stack trace and REPL. The REPL is very barebones, for example - there's no auto-complete. However, it's good for quick exploration. I keep <a href="https://www.objc.io/issues/19-debugging/lldb-debugging/#printing-objects">accidentally prefixing</a> my REPL code with <code>po</code>.</p>

<p></div></div><a href='/images/vscode/debug.png'><img src="/images/vscode/debug.png"></a><div class='meta-container'><header>&nbsp;</header></div><div class='date-container'>&nbsp;</div><div class='content-container'><div class='entry-content'></p>

<p>The breakpoint works through a <a href="http://blog.teamtreehouse.com/introduction-source-maps">source map</a>, and so the line you expect is the one that you're working in. That stuff is all pretty magic to me. Good on Microsoft, and the node community for pulling that off.</p>

<h3>Wrapup</h3>

<p>I still feel a little bit uncomfortable in JavaScript projects, as a long-time native developer. However feel like VS Code is a nice mix of the freeform "just do something" style of Text Editors, which work across a lot of systems and the tight-knit IDEs that are bound to a specific domain. It can be a bridge between worlds.</p>

<p>VS Code has become my main editor in Ruby and JavaScript, due to having great support for the projects and being an OSS project which I feel like I can contribute to. No more being <a href="https://github.com/alcatraz/Alcatraz/issues/475">locked out</a> of improving my editor. Awesome!</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
