<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: ios | Artsy Engineering]]></title>
  <link href="https://artsy.github.io/blog/categories/ios/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="https://artsy.github.io/"/>
  <updated>2021-03-11T22:46:25+00:00</updated>
  <id>https://artsy.github.io/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Echoes From the Past: Supporting Old App Versions]]></title>
    <link href="https://artsy.github.io/blog/2020/12/31/echo-supporting-old-app-versions/"/>
    <updated>2020-12-31T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <id>https://artsy.github.io/blog/2020/12/31/echo-supporting-old-app-versions</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><a href="https://artsy.github.io/blog/2020/03/02/ios-deploys-super-weird-totally-normal/">In, a recent blog post</a>, I discussed a fundamental difference between web and iOS deployments. Web software is deployed to servers that are under your control, while iOS software is deployed to users' devices that you have <em>no</em> control over. This distinction really changes how you think about the code that you ship, because that code could be running indefinitely on devices that never get updated.</p>

<p>The previous post focused on this distinction through the lens of accidentally shipping (and then fixing) a bug. This focus on bugs is important, but focusing <em>only</em> on bugs left me unable to articulate an important, nuanced distinction between hosting code and shipping app binaries. So let's dive in.</p>

<!-- more -->


<p>Software, ideally, is made up of more than just bugs; it has working code, too! Just like with (accidentally) shipping bugs, you need to be aware that the working code you ship is <em>also</em> going to be running indefinitely. That puts pressure on developers to make sure that the code in their apps will continue to function correctly, even as (for example) the web APIs that the apps rely on get updated over time.</p>

<a name="A.Case.Study"></a>
<h2>A Case Study</h2>

<p>Artsy's iOS app relies on a services we call "<a href="https://github.com/artsy/echo">Echo</a>" to serve remote configuration. This lets Artsy do things like selectively disable features (for example, to make non-backwards-compatible API changes), provide changes to URL-routing (to match corresponding changes to web URLs), or even to <em>require</em> users on older versions of the app to update (which we have never had to do). Echo has helped Artsy meet its business goals and building this remote configuration for the app was a great idea.</p>

<p>However... Echo was built as a general-purpose remote-configuration-as-a-service, in anticipation of being used by other apps. That use never materialized. It had a web portal and a database and an API, all to only ever serve a single JSON response to the app. That's fine, sometimes engineers build things that don't end up getting used widely as we expected. Echo did one thing, and it did it really well. It ran on a Hobby Dyno on Heroku without incident for years.</p>

<p>If you think about what I've discussed so far in this post, you may realize that the app <em>depends</em> on Echo. If Echo changes in some non-backwards-compatible way, then the app could break. For example, if Echo happened to stop working entirely, then the app could stop working too.</p>

<p>The Echo service went without being deployed for several years. It worked, so why update it? The problem was that at some point, its major dependencies got yanked, so we could no longer build it locally or even deploy it at all. Yikes. I asked a web colleague for help and our conclusion was that it would take more effort to get Echo working with its existing code than it would be to rebuild the whole thing. Double yikes. And finally, Echo was running on the <a href="https://devcenter.heroku.com/articles/cedar-14-stack">Cedar-14 Heroku stack</a>, which was already at end-of-life and had stopped receiving security updates. Triple yikes.</p>

<p>(I have to note here that most of services at Artsy are deployed almost constantly – Echo was an odd one out. Echo never needed any updates, so it never needed to be deployed. However, we should have been keeping its dependencies up to date and deploying it regularly, which would have uncovered its problems sooner when they were still easily fixed. Anyway!)</p>

<p>So we have a service, Echo, that we can't develop, and can't deploy, and isn't getting security updates from our cloud provider. And the app depends on it. Since Echo had always been a bit over-engineered for what it ended up being, I wondered what the minimal replacement could be. My plan was to replace the Echo server with an S3 bucket, an Artsy-controlled CNAME DNS record, and a small shell script that runs automatically on CI.</p>

<p>Seriously! <a href="https://github.com/artsy/echo/pull/39">It worked</a>! I made a proof-of-concept and then another engineer, <a href="https://github.com/pvinis">Pavlos</a>, finished building the new infrastructure. Changes to the app's configuration are now done via GitHub pull requests (<a href="https://github.com/artsy/echo/pull/63">here is an example PR</a>), which we can track over time (unlike the old web interface).</p>

<p>I can't stress enough how much worry I had had about Echo's degrading status and the app's dependency on it. But! Everything about the change to S3 went smoothly.</p>

<p>Okay, so new versions of app are now referring to the S3 bucket instead of the old Echo API. Great! But what about the older versions of the app that are still out there? They're still hitting the Echo API as intended, right?</p>

<a name="The.Problem"></a>
<h2>The Problem</h2>

<p>Echo's API was still functioning, albeit on an EOL stack that we couldn't make any changes to. Since we can't rely on Heroku continuing to run the Echo API indefinitely, what could we do? Well, the easiest way to fix this would be to change Echo's Artsy-controlled CNAME record to point from the old Cedar-14 Heroku app to a new server app, which could pretend to be the old API for the sake of older app versions.</p>

<p>This leads me to one of the most scary lines of code in the entire Artsy iOS codebase. See if you can spot the problem.</p>

<pre><code class="objc">NSURL *url = [[NSURL alloc] initWithString:@"https://echo-api-production.herokuapp.com/"];
</code></pre>

<p>For whatever reason, we never created an Artsy-controlled CNAME DNS record for Echo. We were just hitting the bare Heroku URL directly. That means that there are <em>seven years'</em> worth of Artsy app versions out there that <em>need</em> to be able to continue hitting <em>that specific</em> Heroku URL.</p>

<p>😬</p>

<p>This is what I meant earlier about how you need to think about properly-working code differently when you develop software that runs on someone else's hardware. If this was a server, this whole problem of old-code-hitting-outdated-APIs wouldn't exist. But because we ship apps as binaries that get ran on someone <em>else's</em> hardware, we need to be aware of this kind of issue.</p>

<p>That URL was fine when the code was written and it worked as intended for years. No one could have predicted, when it was added, that it would cause us headaches much later. Nor could we have anticipated that the Echo server's codebase would end up in such a state.</p>

<a name="The.Solution"></a>
<h2>The Solution</h2>

<p>This is the part of the blog post where I get to be a hero (at least in my head). The Heroku app running Echo was on Cedar-14 and while we couldn't make any changes to its code, we <em>could</em> replace the code entirely. This would give us a new server running at the old URL. So I wrote up a small Express server to proxy HEAD and GET API requests from old iOS app versions to return the response body and headers that were expected. <a href="https://github.com/artsy/echo/pull/59#">The work is here</a> if you're curious. The nice thing about Heroku, at least, is that if this had gone horribly wrong we still could have reverted back to the Cedar-14 app while we figured out our next steps.</p>

<p>We will still need to keep this Heroku app running, indefinitely, which isn't ideal. Perhaps Artsy's migration to Kubernetes will never be <em>quite</em> 100% complete, but that's a small price to pay for keeping users of our app happy.</p>

<a name="Conclusion"></a>
<h2>Conclusion</h2>

<p>It's not just bugs that you need to be aware of <em>accidentally</em> shipping in your app binaries. You have to think about how the code that's running <em>as intended today</em>, because it will continue to run for the foreseeable future. This means adding checks for non-200 response codes from APIs, being careful about third-party APIs, and thinking carefully about everything you ship. Apps are more than just their code; apps are everything that their code depends on, too.</p>

<p>This is a lesson that I've been teaching engineers for a long time, but it's only with our recent Echo changes that I've come to understand, at a deeper level, what it means to take ownership of code. Yes, the bugs, and of course, the happy little accidents, but also the mundane interconnected dependencies that make software systems so complex. And, if I'm being honest, that make software systems so much fun to work on, too.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Becoming Mobile First]]></title>
    <link href="https://artsy.github.io/blog/2020/09/29/becoming-mobile-first-at-artsy/"/>
    <updated>2020-09-29T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <id>https://artsy.github.io/blog/2020/09/29/becoming-mobile-first-at-artsy</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>It was a Wednesday, mid-summer 2019. I don't know which Wednesday specifically, but I know that it was <em>a</em>
Wednesday because I was attending Artsy's weekly all-hands meeting. Two hundred colleagues were also there (many
dialing in remotely) and we were all listening to
<a href="https://files.artsy.net/documents/artsy-names-new-ceo.pdf">Artsy's new CEO</a> talk about the company's direction.
Mike Steib had only been around for a few months at that point, getting to know the business. He was talking about
the product direction, and I was listening intently.</p>

<p>With Artsy's iOS app, I knew there were only really two directions we could go. As I listened, I reflected on how
we had gotten here.</p>

<!-- more -->


<p>When I joined Artsy in 2014, I joined the Mobile Team. It was an amazing team. While we were called the "mobile"
team, we only worked on Artsy's iOS apps and not the mobile website.</p>

<p>By 2016, Artsy Engineering had grown to the size that having only a "mobile team" and a "web team" was no longer
working well. We dissolved both teams and distributed the engineers into
<a href="https://artsy.github.io/blog/2016/03/28/artsy-engineering-organization-stack/">new product teams</a>, focused on
vertical aspects of Artsy's business. Auctions. Partner Success. Editorial. And so on. The idea was that each team
would have total autonomy over building products to support their slice of the business, and each would have the
engineering and design resources to build new features across both our web and iOS canvases.</p>

<p>That structure worked well, and continues to work well today (we have continued re-organizing ourselves into new
teams to better meet business goals). But once we dissolved the mobile team, there was no longer anyone looking at
our iOS software holistically. The app had become a series of silos – each silo was internally consistent, but
distinct from each other. Often each silo was written in distinct programming languages (we had also started
adopting React Native).</p>

<p>New iOS technologies had been created by Apple, but our teams weren't taking full advantage of them. We would
update to support the latest versions of Xcode and iOS in the free time between other tickets. It wasn't ideal. Of
the <a href="https://github.com/artsy/mobile">five original members of the Mobile Team</a>, everyone else had moved on except
me.</p>

<p>As a product, the app was languishing.</p>

<p>Yet despite this, it was also hugely popular among our users and very important to Artsy's business. Art collectors
love our app! It gets a large percentage of our total sessions. Also, users place an outsized number of auction
bids and artwork inquiries using our app relative to the number of sessions on our website. In fact, the highest
value artwork transaction <em>ever</em> to take place on Artsy was made on an iPad, running software that I helped build.
I'm still pretty proud of that.</p>

<p>So, Wednesday all-hands. I stood there, not sure of what would happen next. I could see Artsy either making a
massive investment in the app, or I could see Artsy cutting its losses and focusing on the software that we already
knew how to build. Which direction we took largely depended on this new CEO, who was now standing in front of us
all and describing the direction Artsy's product would take next.</p>

<a name="The.Dream"></a>
<h2>The Dream</h2>

<p>Mike said something that caused a lot of raised eyebrows in the crowd. People were excited. <em>I</em> was excited.
Artsy's product organization would shift to adopt a "mobile-first strategy."</p>

<p>Someone asked "does this mean the app will reach feature parity with Artsy's website?"</p>

<p>Mike responded: "No. It means that features are going to launch <em>first</em> on the app. If anything, it's the <em>website</em>
that will be catching up <em>to the app</em>."</p>

<p>I was kind of blown away! I mean, this had been the spirit of our original re-org in 2016, but that hadn't really
materialized. The app had continued to trail the website. At most, only one product team was ever building new
features for the app (usually which ever team I happened to be on). Shifting to this mobile-first strategy would be
a <em>massive</em> undertaking, but I was keen.</p>

<p>In August, an email landed in my inbox from Artsy's head of software. He wanted to spin up a new team to focus on
the app: the team would be responsible for supporting Artsy's new mobile-first product strategy. He wanted to know
what I thought, and he wanted to know if I was interested in leading the team.</p>

<p>Honestly, it was a dream come true.</p>

<p><img src="/images/2020-09-29-becoming-mobile-first-at-artsy/rfc.png" alt="Screenshot of the RFC for creating the Mobile Experience team" /></p>

<p>Here we are, a year later. This is the story of how Artsy created its Mobile Experience team. How we recovered a
languishing iOS app. How engineers helped shift the product organization to a mobile-first product strategy. And
how Artsy grew from <em>sometimes</em> having <em>a</em> team working on the app, to usually having <em>every</em> team working on it.</p>

<p><img src="/images/2020-09-29-becoming-mobile-first-at-artsy/faq.png" alt="Another screenshot of the RFC for creating the Mobile Experience team, describing frequently asked questions" /></p>

<a name="Getting.Our.Bearings"></a>
<h2>Getting Our Bearings</h2>

<p>When Artsy created its new Mobile Experience team, we were already resource-constrained and so the new team would
need to be nimble. We had three full-time engineers (myself as tech lead, and two others), assisted by a designer,
product manager, and data analyst, who would each be spending only half their work time on the Mobile Experience
team. We needed to be scrappy. I'm really proud of the work that that early team accomplished, and I look back
fondly on those first few months working with Sam, Joanna, David, Kieran, and Ani.</p>

<p>The first thing we did was define our own mandate. What was this team responsible for? What was it <em>not</em>
responsible for? "Mobile Experience" is pretty vague, and we had to answer a lot of upfront questions. Would we be
responsible for <em>all</em> of Artsy's iOS software? No, just the main collector app. Would we be responsible for Artsy's
mobile website? No, that's too far-reaching. What about Android? Well, yes, eventually...</p>

<p>After we decided on our mandate, the next step was to get really familiar with the existing app. We storyboarded
out all the existing screens and their connections to one another.</p>

<p><img src="/images/2020-09-29-becoming-mobile-first-at-artsy/walkthrough.png" alt="Screenshot of all the screens in our app laid out to discuss" /></p>

<p><img src="/images/2020-09-29-becoming-mobile-first-at-artsy/brainstorm.png" alt="Screenshot of a brainstorm for app ideas" /></p>

<p>No one on our team had complete knowledge of every screen in the app, not even me, so exploring it together was a
great way to uncover what needed immediate attention. One example was our partner page, which displayed information
to our users about Artsy's partners: galleries, museums, auction houses, etc. We learned that the app actually used
an ancient web view, and it didn't even show the partner's <em>artworks</em>. The artworks! Probably the most important
thing for it to do!</p>

<p><img src="/images/2020-09-29-becoming-mobile-first-at-artsy/old_partner.png" alt="Screenshot of a presentation showing the old partner page" /></p>

<p><img src="/images/2020-09-29-becoming-mobile-first-at-artsy/new_partner.png" alt="Screenshot of a presentation showing the new partner page, which looks much nicer" /></p>

<p>This is where "being scrappy" started to take root. Usually when developing new features, Artsy designers iterate
on a design before we plan on execution, then we implement, test, and deploy. The nice part of replacing something
that was <em>obviously broken</em> was that we didn't feel beholden to this usual process; whatever we built would be
better than what we had. One engineer and our designer started the new partner page with a quick pencil sketch,
using the app's existing UI abstractions to design something that we could quickly build. Once we had a prototype,
the engineer and designer iterated. The whole project took only about three weeks.</p>

<a name="Early.Wins"></a>
<h2>Early Wins</h2>

<p>Learning about the app itself was critical, but equally important was learning about how our users <em>used</em> the app.
We scheduled user interviews and, in the mean time, looked into our anonymized user analytics. Our data analyst
found a few representative sessions and we walked through each action that a user took. One big lesson here was how
much our app users relied on the app's search feature, which was still written in Objective-C and hadn't been
updated in a long time. We found that users would often search for the same query several times in the same
session. For example, users would search for "banksy", wander off exploring some art, and then return to search for
"bansky" again. And again. And again.</p>

<p>Our search implementation didn't show users their own recent searches, which would have greatly reduced the amount
of friction users experienced while exploring the art world in the app. Our other engineer took point working with
our designer to migrate the app's search to React Native. We also added some other features to our search page,
like adding entity subtitles so users would know if the result they were tapping on was an artwork, and artist, a
gallery, and so on. The whole project took about a month to complete, and we have continued to iterate on the app's
search.</p>

<p><img src="/images/2020-09-29-becoming-mobile-first-at-artsy/new_search.png" alt="Screenshot of a presentation showing the new search" /></p>

<p>In early conversations with company leadership, the Mobile Experience team settled on an... interesting strategy to
what we would prioritize. Our mission was "to make the app not suck." This might seem harsh! But it came from a
place of caring. We knew how much better the app could be and we were motivated to make that a reality. In the
spring of 2020, the team felt like we had reached a point where the app no longer "sucked" – our goal now was "to
make the app amazing."</p>

<p>During 2020, we made a lot of changes to the app. We had built a new home page, a profile tab for users, granular
push notification settings, Sign In with Apple, and more.</p>

<p><img src="/images/2020-09-29-becoming-mobile-first-at-artsy/new_home.png" alt="Screenshot of a presentation showing the new home page" /></p>

<p>It was really exciting to show off our progress to the rest of the company at our monthly Demo Day, especially in
those early months. The product team makes up only a quarter of our company and it was really cool to hear gallery
liaisons complementing our new partner page, or sales people complementing our refreshed home feed. I think that
people had gotten so used to the app not moving much at all that this sudden high velocity of development was as
exciting for them as it was for us.</p>

<a name="Setting.Up.Others.To.Succeed"></a>
<h2>Setting Up Others To Succeed</h2>

<p>Artsy's goal for the Mobile Experience team was explicitly <em>not</em> to centralize all our iOS feature development, and
so our mandate included much more that just working on iOS software ourselves. We wanted to sit between a typical
product team and a "platform" team, to provide infrastructure and assistance so any team at Artsy could develop
their own iOS feature. This was a big challenge, and required work at the individual and team levels.</p>

<p>The first step was apparent before we even created the Mobile Experience team. Artsy Engineering runs skills
surveys every six months, and we knew that building iOS software in React Native was something Artsy engineers
weren't really familiar with, but that they really wanted to learn more about. I worked with the Engineering team's
Peer Learning Working Group to design a curriculum – big shout out to Christina and Adam for their help here!</p>

<p><a href="https://artsy.github.io/blog/2019/12/03/ios-learning-group/">The iOS Learning Group took four weeks to deliver four lessons</a>.
The learners were mostly web engineers, so I emphasized the familiar parts of writing React Native software. I also
provided weekly office hours for learners to get assistance with homework. I even stretched my wings as an
educator, developing new skills around curriculum design and delivery. After the course, learners responded
positively to the experience and we have integrated lessons learned from the iOS Learning Group into subsequent
peer learning groups.</p>

<a name="Aligning.Product.Releases"></a>
<h2>Aligning Product Releases</h2>

<p>Now that engineers had a solid grasp of how to build software in our application, we could re-align our product
development process around iOS. I can't speak to the design side of this, but from a product perspective the most
critical milestone was defining a regular 2-week app release cadence. Let me explain.</p>

<p>Prior to the Mobile Experience team, we released the app pretty irregularly. We would release whenever we had
something big to release, basically. There are two major flaws with that approach. The first problem is that since
each release was bigger, each release was scarier. No one really felt confident releasing app updates. The second
problem was that large pieces of work tended to get coupled together. This came to a head last summer when we were
blocked from releasing an redesigned artwork view because we were waiting for a major overhaul to Artsy's GraphQL
API to be completed. Without guidance or structure, different teams were building big projects and both had their
changes in our default branch – it was a bit chaotic.</p>

<p>These two problems are incidental to how we worked at Artsy but there is another, inherent problem to developing
mobile apps:
<a href="https://artsy.github.io/blog/2020/03/02/ios-deploys-super-weird-totally-normal/">deploying iOS software is weird</a>.
Engineers, designers, and product managers at Artsy are used to being able to quickly and cheaply deploy software
to the <em>web</em>, not the App Store. iOS software is deployed to our user's hardware, not to servers we control, which
introduces the possibility that users might not upgrade. Software we shipped years ago is still being run today –
we have the analytics to prove it. Not to mention that every app update has to go through Apple's App Store review
process. Getting our product team aligned on a release schedule might also help us get aligned on the weirdness of
deploying iOS software.</p>

<center>
<blockquote class="twitter-tweet"><p lang="en" dir="ltr">iOS developers! I have a question for you. I hear a lot about teams releasing app updates on a 2-week cadence, to increase user confidence/App Store ranking/team morale/etc.<br><br>Have any teams shared their experiences with this? Bonus points for any quantitative data. Thanks!! 🤗</p>&mdash; Ash Furrow (@ashfurrow) <a href="https://twitter.com/ashfurrow/status/1184845989510811649?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">October 17, 2019</a></blockquote> <script async src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"></script>
</center>


<p><br /></p>

<p>As the Mobile Experience team formed, I reached out to other mobile teams to find out about how they structured
regular releases. <a href="https://twitter.com/Cform">Matt Greenwell</a> from BuzzFeed was really helpful in particular,
outlining their experience of the pros and cons of a regular release cadence. We implemented a two-week release
cadence so that all product teams could align their own feature development and testing around this predictable
structure. We also created documentation for teams to hide their in-progress work behind feature flags. And
finally, we refined our app QA process; teams would QA their own features and bug fixes while the Mobile Experience
team would used a QA script to test the app <em>generally</em>, every other Monday, before submitting an update to the App
Store.</p>

<p><img src="/images/2020-09-29-becoming-mobile-first-at-artsy/cadence.png" alt="Calendar describing our cadence on an example sprint" /></p>

<a name="Making.Deploys.Not.Scary"></a>
<h2>Making Deploys Not Scary</h2>

<p>To further help teams get into the habit of developing and releasing iOS software often, we created nightly betas.
We also adopted a clever idea from our web colleagues: deploy blocks. In case of a technical reason to not release
a beta, we create a block and the CI job that deploys the beta would fail with a descriptive message. This reduced
a lot of chatter in Slack where engineers would ask "could I make a new beta?" Instead, engineers usually just wait
for the nightly beta. And if they get impatient, they now default to action (their beta deploy will fail if we set
up a block).</p>

<p>All of this was automated through <a href="https://fastlane.tools">fastlane</a> on our CI provider. We had been using fastlane
for a long time at Artsy, but the Mobile Experience team took the time to share knowledge of how it worked. Any
engineer at Artsy can now make a beta (<code>make deploy</code>) or promote the latest beta to an App Store submission
(<code>make promote_beta_to_submission</code>).</p>

<p>We deploy more often and, consequently, each deploy is less scary. And everyone is aware of the need to hide
in-progress work behind feature flags. At this point, updates to our app are mundane, predictable, and boring. Just
the way we like them.</p>

<a name="Being.Generous.With.Our.Time"></a>
<h2>Being Generous With Our Time</h2>

<p>Our QA and deploy process touches on something I want to go into more detail about, which is how the Mobile
Experience team helped support other product teams. I described earlier how Mobile Experience sits somewhere
between a normal product team and a platform team, and we leveraged that to our advantage. It would have been easy
to become primarily a supportive team, and leave feature development up to others. However, that would leave us
unaware of how day-to-day development <em>feels</em> in the app. We own the platform, and that includes the developer
experience. By sitting in this ambiguous in-between state, we stayed aware of both the needs of everyday
developers, and the needs of our platform.</p>

<p>I would encourage engineers from other teams to ask us for help, which led to a lot of pairing sessions. To be
honest, I think it probably interfered with our productivity, but it was worth it. A half hour of my time spent
pairing with a colleague might save them three hours of banging their head against Xcode. But it's not the time
saved that I care about, it's the head-banging. I want engineers at Artsy to feel empowered to build their own iOS
software, and that's only going to happen if they feel comfortable and supported.</p>

<p>When the Galleries team kicked off their ambitious Viewing Rooms project, we helped them get started by lending an
engineer to them for a few sprints. When they ran into problems, we were generous with our time by pairing with
them. When they were nearing completion, we helped them test the new feature. This all culminated in a smooth
release.</p>

<p><img src="/images/2020-09-29-becoming-mobile-first-at-artsy/new_loader.png" alt="Screenshot of a presentation showing the new home page's new loading indicator" /></p>

<p>Speaking of Developer Experience, we took a keen interest in standardizing our best practices and modernizing the
codebase. We
<a href="https://github.com/artsy/eigen/blob/dc81bbc9cd33d51d10054a6c57e61a1bd0ee3e75/docs/preferred_practices.md">documented how we wanted the app's codebase to look</a>
and set up
<a href="https://github.com/artsy/eigen/blob/dc81bbc9cd33d51d10054a6c57e61a1bd0ee3e75/tslint-rules/useWrappedComponentsRule.js">processes like lint rules</a>
to encourage developers to follow our best practices. We also invited any engineer at Artsy to join our
twice-weekly Knowledge Share meetings (I'll discuss these in-depth shortly). We looked for bottle necks in the
development process and found many problems, which we addressed.
<a href="https://github.com/artsy/eigen/pull/3022">We combined the Native iOS and React Native repositories</a> (which had
historically been separated). <a href="https://github.com/artsy/eigen/pull/3105">We overhauled the CI configuration</a> to
leverage heavy caching – average build times dropped from fifteen minutes to less than five.
<a href="https://github.com/artsy/eigen/pull/3210">And we adopted stricter TypeScript compiler settings</a> so that engineers
would be forced to deal with nullability and other causes of bugs. (Hey, sometimes you need a carrot and sometimes
you need a stick.)</p>

<p>The React Native community has grown a lot since 2016. If Artsy were to begin our adoption of React Native today,
we would be really well-supported by a community that has defined best practices, documented standard approaches to
problems, and a consolidated opinion on what a React Native codebase should "feel" like. None of that existed in
2016, and our early architectural decisions don't really reflect contemporary best practices. We continue working
to bring our codebase closer to resembling a fresh project created with <code>react-native init</code>.</p>

<p>I'm extraordinarily happy with how things have shaped up, and in the direction we continue to move. This is all an
ongoing process, and should remain an ongoing process. For example, engineers were still facing a bottleneck with
core parts of our app's routing logic that were in Objective-C, so we recently
<a href="https://github.com/artsy/eigen/pull/3771">moved all routing to TypeScript</a>. Not only does moving code out of
Objective-C make it easier for everyone to build, but it also ladders up to a cross-platform Artsy app.</p>

<p>We still have older practices in the app that we want to migrate away from, like testing with Enzyme. But overall,
things are looking good!</p>

<iframe width="100%" height="400" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/IEn2_WSKFHw" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture" allowfullscreen></iframe>


<a name="Knowledge.Shares"></a>
<h2>Knowledge Shares</h2>

<p>We achieved most of these big, infrastructural changes in meetings called <em>Knowledge Shares</em>, which I mentioned
earlier. I should write a dedicated blog post on these (update: <a href="/blog/2020/12/09/share-your-knowledge/">I did write one</a>), but in short: Knowledge Shares are a <em>structured</em> time to
facilitate <em>unstructured learning</em>. Anyone can bring a topic to Knowledge Share, from a ticket that they're stuck
on to an idea they have to a neat trick they recently learned. We set aside these two hours a week to discuss
whatever the team wants, and we don't only invite engineers.</p>

<p>New feature designs, product roadmaps, and data analyses are often brought up by our non-engineering colleagues; we
discuss these at the beginning of the meetings to make sure everyone's time is respected. Throughout the week,
someone will raise a question in Slack. Before we had Knowledge Share meetings, we might schedule a dedicated
half-hour meeting to discussing this question. But instead, we now say "alright let's chat about this at tomorrow's
KS." Usually the discussion lasts a lot less than a half hour, so we save time and needless context-switching.</p>

<p>Knowledge Shares are also a manifestation of my philosophy of tech leadership, which is this: none of us have built
an Artsy before, so instead of optimizing for building an Artsy, let's optimize for <em>learning</em> how to build an
Artsy. The best Artsy we can build. And as a natural byproduct, an Artsy gets built. But it's the <em>learning</em> that
is treated as the paramount goal.</p>

<p>Like I said, I owe you a whole blog post on Knowledge Share meetings. I hope I have conveyed how important these
scheduled "structured unstructured learning" times have been for us.</p>

<a name="The.Results"></a>
<h2>The Results</h2>

<p>So where does that leave us? It's been a year and change, where are we now? Well I'm happy to say that we've made a
huge impact. We've gone from only having (at most) one product team writing iOS software at a time to having nearly
<em>every</em> product team building iOS software. Artsy is through the woods of its transition to a mobile-first product
strategy. We still have a ways to go, but it feels like we have finally realized the dream we had in 2016 where
every team is fully equipped and empowered to deliver on their own business goals, across all of Artsy's canvasses.</p>

<p>Our App Store ranking has shot through the roof – not surprising considering our "make it not suck" and then "make
it amazing" approach. Artsy's iOS app rating now sits at a stout 4.7.</p>

<p><img src="/images/2020-09-29-becoming-mobile-first-at-artsy/ratings.png" alt="Screenshot of a graph showing an increasing average App Store rating" /></p>

<p>We've also started tracking our iOS developer experience within Artsy. We know exactly where we still need work
because we ask our engineers where they need support.</p>

<p>It's taken a mammoth effort, and there's so much more that I could talk about, but this blog post is long enough
already! Looking at the work we've done, the ways we've done it, and the results of our effort... I feel ecstatic.</p>

<a name="Next.Steps"></a>
<h2>Next Steps</h2>

<p>All that said, Artsy's product team is currently embarking on another reorganization. With so much technical and
product debt paid off, Artsy has evolved past the need for a dedicated Mobile Experience team. It's bittersweet,
but I'm proud to say that the new Collector Experience team is about to be born. Our team will continue to own the
mobile platform, including its holistic user experience and day-to-day developer experience, but we'll have an
expanded mandate. That mandate includes a cross-platform Artsy app that will work for collectors on Android as well
as iOS.</p>

<p>The Mobile Experience team has grown, too. Since we started last year with just a few engineers and limited product
support, we now boast a full roster of engineers and product support. I want to thank everyone on the team,
currently: David, Sam, Brian, Mike, Brittney, Pavlos, and Mounir. You have made the past year an incredibly
rewarding experience for me as I learn the ropes of technical leadership. I'm so proud of what we've built together
and I'm excited for what the new Collector Experience team is going to do next!</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[iOS Deploys: Super Weird And Totally Normal]]></title>
    <link href="https://artsy.github.io/blog/2020/03/02/ios-deploys-super-weird-totally-normal/"/>
    <updated>2020-03-02T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <id>https://artsy.github.io/blog/2020/03/02/ios-deploys-super-weird-totally-normal</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Software deploys! What a concept. You have some code running somewhere, and you need to get it running somewhere
else. What could possibly go wrong? While web developers have become accustom to some <em>really slick</em> deploy
processes, iOS developers have to work within some very different constraints.</p>

<p>Today I want to explore the differences between deploying iOS software and front-end/back-end web software. Some of
these differences are inherent to how the code gets executed, and some of the differences are incidental to choices
that Apple has made. These are constraints that iOS developers need to work within. As Artsy has adopted React
Native over the past four years, we have had more and more of our web engineering colleagues contributing to our
iOS app. For these web engineers, getting familiar with the iOS deploy constraints is as important as getting to
know Xcode and CocoaPods.</p>

<!-- more -->


<a name="A.Release.Case.Study"></a>
<h2>A Release Case Study</h2>

<p>We're going to use a case study to frame today's discussion. Artsy's Mobile Experience team recently got a ticket
from our Platform team. The nature of the ticket itself doesn't matter, but it involved a change we were making to
our API. I fixed the bug and submitted a pull request, which quickly got merged. We tested the bug fix in our next
beta deploy, and everything looked fine. Great so far.</p>

<p>Artsy releases iOS software on a two-week release cadence, and this bug fix was scheduled to be released to users
the following week. But our back-end team wanted to quickly deploy that API change, which would require the app bug
fix to get released to users <em>first</em>.</p>

<p>So... what to do?</p>

<p>Do we release off-cadence? Or do we push back on our Platform team and ask them to hold off until the scheduled
release?</p>

<p>Let's actually pause for a moment and consider one of the assumptions we made above. If you're a web engineer, the
idea of releasing only every two weeks might seem pretty strange! I mean, why not release continuously? For
example, Artsy's website gets deployed to our staging environment after every merged pull request, and staging then
gets promoted to production several times a day. This process is generally referred to as "continuous delivery",
and <a href="https://www.thoughtworks.com/insights/blog/case-continuous-delivery">it has a lot of advantages</a>. That's why
it's so common among web engineering teams. So why not use continuous delivery on iOS apps?</p>

<a name="The.Executable.Problem"></a>
<h2>The Executable Problem</h2>

<p>There are two reasons we can't use continuous delivery on iOS. First, continuous delivery is only really possible
when you control where the software gets executed (or, in the case of web front-ends, where the client-side code
gets served from). Artsy controls our own servers, so we can deliver web software continuously. The next time a
user makes a web request, they'll get the updated code. However, the Artsy iOS app runs on our users' devices,
instead. We can't push out updates to users' iPhones or iPads in the same way we can push updates to our servers.</p>

<p>iOS apps are binary executables that are distributed through Apple's App Store, and updates to apps have to be
pulled down by devices. Even if <em>most</em> users have automatic updates turned on, those updates are typically
installed overnight. Consequently, there's quite a lag between when we deploy an iOS update and when users run the
code. While it only takes about a week for 80% of our users to update to the latest version, there's a very long
tail after that.</p>

<p><img src="/images/2020-03-02-ios-deploys-super-weird-totally-normal/graph.png" alt="Graph of in-use versions of Artsy's app, illustrating both the quick adoption of new updates by most users and the long tail of old versions that are never updated" /></p>

<p>iOS software is executed in an environment that we don't control, that we can't push updates to, and most
importantly, that we can't roll back deploys on. If we ship a version of our app with a bug, but then ship an
updated version with a fix right away, there is absolutely no guarantee that users will install that update.
<em>Ever</em>. That means that <em>every</em> deploy we make to our iOS software requires a lot of confidence in that code. In
contrast, rolling back a web deploy is quite painless. If we ship a bug to the web, no problem: just roll back the
deploy, fix the bug, and re-deploy with the fix.</p>

<p>(Note: some readers might be wondering why we don't take advantage of over-the-air updates to our React Native
JavaScript bundle. This is definitely possible, but our app is brownfield with some native code and some React
Native code and we haven't yet built out the infrastructure for this. As more and more code shifts to React Native,
we plan to investigate OTA updates to JavaScript bundles.)</p>

<a name="Apple.s.Platform..Apple.s.Rules"></a>
<h2>Apple's Platform, Apple's Rules</h2>

<p>The second reason to deploy iOS software on a schedule, rather than with continuous delivery, depends on the App
Store review process. This is another big difference that takes web engineers a while to get used to. Whenever we
ship a version of our iOS app, we ship it to Apple for review, and then Apple ships it to our users. I'm not going
to debate the utility of Apple as an intermediary – the fact is that they own the iOS platform and these are the
rules they have chosen. If you want to ship iOS software, then you have to abide by Apple's rules.</p>

<p>App Store review isn't exactly QA. I mean, if we were to ship an app update and it crashes upon launch, Apple isn't
likely to approve that update. But if we have a small bug buried somewhere in the app, we can't expect Apple to
find it. Apple is only testing for adherence to their
<a href="https://developer.apple.com/app-store/review/guidelines/">App Store Review Guidelines</a>. Apple is looking for
things like: is the app trying to steal user data? Is the app displaying objectionable material, given its age
rating? Is the app's description and App Store metadata correct? That kind of stuff.</p>

<p>So not only do iOS software developers need a lot of confidence in every deploy, but they also need to abide by
Apple's guidelines.</p>

<p>Alright. Let's return to the case study from earlier.</p>

<a name="Case.Study.Resolution"></a>
<h2>Case Study Resolution</h2>

<p>We had a bug fix in our app, and getting it deployed was blocking an important change to our back-end API. First,
we had to consider that some users simply wouldn't get the update. We had to ask ourselves if this would block the
back-end change entirely – through open discussions with the team, we decided to move forward. Second, we had to
consider the other work that had been merged since our last release. Were we confident in deploying that work
as-is? And what amount of QA would need to be done to ship those changes as well?</p>

<p>That last point is really interesting because there was actually another option. Rather than deploy the app based
off the current <code>master</code> branch (with the bug fix <em>and</em> other work included), we did something a bit clever.
<a href="https://fastlane.tools">fastlane</a>, the tool we use to automate our iOS deploys, will tag each commit that we
submit to the App Store. So rather than deploy the current <code>master</code> branch, which would require very rigorous QA,
we checked out the previous release tag. We then used
<a href="https://www.atlassian.com/git/tutorials/cherry-pick"><code>git cherry-pick</code></a> to apply <em>only</em> the bug fix changes, and
deployed from there.</p>

<p><img src="/images/2020-03-02-ios-deploys-super-weird-totally-normal/slack.png" alt="Screenshot from Slack where I detailed my plan to cherry-pick the commits" /></p>

<p>This isolated the changes we were making to the app and minimized the amount of QA we needed to feel confident in
our release. Even still, we ran through our usual QA script. As I hope I've demonstrated above, it's always better
to be safe than be sorry when it comes to deploying iOS software.</p>

<p>This <code>git cherry-pick</code> approach has its own trade-offs, but it is very effective in the right circumstance. It's an
approach I've only had to use a few times during my time at Artsy, but it's a good approach to be familiar with.
This situation also highlights a benefit of automating iOS deploys: we know <em>exactly</em> which commit each version of
our app is running, making it easy to <code>git cherry-pick</code> with confidence.</p>

<p>I hope I've illustrated how iOS software is a bit different from web software, both inherently and incidentally.
Many of these same quirks apply to Android deploys as well. Mobile software feels closer to software sold in
shrink-wrapped boxes than it does to Docker images shipped to Kubernetes clusters. And that's okay. Different
platforms will always have different constraints. Hopefully by understanding these constraints, mobile and web
engineers can gain a greater empathy for one another and, ideally, share ideas and solutions so we can all learn
and grown together.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[At Long Last: A Log Out Button]]></title>
    <link href="https://artsy.github.io/blog/2020/01/15/ios-logout-button-at-last/"/>
    <updated>2020-01-15T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <id>https://artsy.github.io/blog/2020/01/15/ios-logout-button-at-last</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>In 2013, Artsy shipped the first version of our iOS app. Typical for an early-day startup, the app was a "minimum
viable product" (with a big emphasis on "minimum"). One of the features that didn't make the cut was something you
expect to see in most apps: a log out button.</p>

<p>When I joined Artsy a year later, there was still no log out button. And there would be no log out button for
another six years, until today.</p>

<p>I want to talk about this quirk of our app, from both product and technical perspectives. Why wasn't this already
in our app? Why was it so difficult to build? These are interesting questions, and their answers shed light on how
products mature over time. I also want to talk about how we finally managed to prioritize this kinda weird feature
request (spoilers: it was our company-wide hackathon). Let's go!</p>

<!-- more -->


<p>When I say that our app doesn't have a log out button, that's a bit of a fib: it <em>does</em> have a log out button... in
the admin-only debug menu. The reason why this isn't a user-facing feature is that the final step of this
admin-only log out feature is a call to <code>exit(0)</code>, effectively crashing the app. That's <em>one</em> way to make sure that
user-specific state doesn't pollute your app's runtime, but of course it would be ridiculous for a user-facing log
out button to crash the app. The only other way to log out was to uninstall the app, which is <em>not</em> something we
want to encourage users to do.</p>

<p>So Artsy staff could log out of the app, but our normal users couldn't. This quirk was acceptable in the early days
of our app, but as the years wore on, it became less of a quirk and more of a product limitation. Even three months
after creating our new Mobile Experience team, we hadn't yet prioritized this feature. Let's
<a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Five_whys">dive into this question</a> a little bit.</p>

<p>The log out button hadn't been prioritized. <strong>Why?</strong> To be honest, we had – and still have – a lot of work to do to
improve the app (<a href="http://artsy.net/jobs">we're hiring, by the way</a>). Among the high-impact work we've been
shipping, the log out button simply never made the cut. <strong>Why?</strong> It turns out be quite complicated to implement a
log out button in our app. <strong>Why?</strong> To answer that, we need to step back and think about software development and
requirements gathering, generally.</p>

<p>Experienced software developers will tell you that it's far, far easier to build a piece of software with a feature
in mind <em>from the start</em> than it is to take an existing piece of software and add something to it that it was never
intended to do. For our app, logging out was something it was never intended to do, and so adding it was
technically difficult. <strong>Why?</strong></p>

<p>Because of <a href="https://softwareengineering.stackexchange.com/questions/148108/why-is-global-state-so-evil">state</a>.
When you log in to our app, the state of the app changes: we get a user ID and access token from the Artsy API and
our code assumes that these values never change. This is further complicated by the fact that our app is split into
two pieces: the native code (written in Objective-C and Swift) and the React Native code (written in TypeScript).
You can effectively think of these as <em>two</em> apps that interoperate with each other. The state now has to be managed
across <em>two</em> pieces of software, further complexifying the work to add a log out button.</p>

<p>Returning to the idea of developing features in mind from the start (versus adding them after the fact), our React
Native codebase had always assumed a logged-in user. Adding support for this later on was too difficult (indeed,
our solution was to
<a href="https://github.com/artsy/emission/pull/2027/files#diff-0cc174f9197fd0b06ecbd2eaa0247833R1020">invalidate the entire React Native runtime upon log out</a>).
This wasn't a limitation of React Native, but rather it was a limitation of how we chose to organize our code. If
we'd added a log out button earlier in the product lifetime, it wouldn't have been so difficult. The longer we
waited, the more and more code we wrote that implicitly relied upon our existing limitations.</p>

<p>In this way, the <em>absence</em> of a feature had gained its own inertia. The missing feature became a present absence,
and I think there's more to think about there – maybe for another blog post.</p>

<p>So what we had was a difficult technical problem that wasn't <em>that</em> high of priority and didn't have an obvious
solution. Our product team wasn't feeling the pain, but our colleagues who interface more directly with our users
<em>were</em> feeling it.</p>

<p>Artsy kicked off 2020 with a company-wide Hackathon. We run these events roughly once a year, and they provide a
great opportunity for engineers and non-engineers to work together to build something over a few days. Maybe it's a
brand-new piece of software to help us do our jobs better. Maybe it's a new zine to collect our favourite artworks
from the site? And maybe, just maybe, it's a long-neglected user feature that never made the cut in prioritization
meetings.</p>

<p>Among all the ideas that Artsy staff submitted for the Hackathon, the Artsy iOS Log Out button received the third
most votes.</p>

<p><img src="/images/2020-01-15-ios-logout-button-at-last/idea.png" alt="Screenshot of our Hackathon ideas board" /></p>

<p>I sat down with another Mobile Experience engineer, Brian, and the people who submitted the Hackathon idea. If we
were going to build this, it was worth doing right, so we asked questions and learned more about why users need a
log out button at all. I'll spare you the details, but it suffices to say that I learned a lot.</p>

<p>Brian and I worked on the feature, digging into the internals of our app and the interop between native and React
Native code. Our solution wasn't necessarily the "best" solution, but it worked within the assumptions that the app
has already made. Here's roughly the plan we set out with.</p>

<p>On the React Native side of the app, build a settings screen with the log out button:</p>

<ul>
<li>When the user taps the button, post a notification through <code>NSNotificationCenter</code>.</li>
<li>Also, show the user who they are logged in <em>as</em> on this screen.</li>
</ul>


<p>On the native side of the app, listen for the notification and take the following steps when it's fired:</p>

<ol>
<li>Tear down the React Native bridge (invalidate it and release it).</li>
<li>Tear down the native user interface (set singleton instance to <code>nil</code>).</li>
<li>Get a fresh unauthenticated API token.</li>
<li>Use the token to show the sign in/up flow (set the window's <code>rootViewController</code> property).</li>
</ol>


<p>Invalidating the React Native bridge is quite a dramatic action to take, but it's effective. We chose this solution
because it allows our React Native code to continue assuming that the user ID and access token never change (during
its lifetime, anyway).</p>

<p>We had a few other items to follow-up on, mostly reference cycles that were holding onto invalid singleton
instances in-memory. Here's the log out button in action:</p>

<p><img src="/images/2020-01-15-ios-logout-button-at-last/logout.png" alt="Screenshot of our new log out button!" /></p>

<p>We learned a tonne about the React Native bridge, the existing architecture of our app, and how we'd like to see
that mature going forward.</p>

<p>I said earlier that the longer we waited, the harder it was to build this log out button because more and more of
our existing code relied upon assumptions that the log out button would break. Now that we <em>do</em> have a log out
button, <em>new code we write needs to take it into account</em>. The assumptions coders can make about this codebase are
shifting over time – this is an experience that I never appreciated while working on minimum viable products. I'm
trying to lean into these shifts and use them to drive further modernizations in our codebase. For instance, I'm
already thinking ahead to how everything will work once our sign in/up flow is moved from Objective-C to React
Native (since the user ID and access token <em>will</em> need to be mutable state).</p>

<p>In case you're curious, all our iOS code is open source. The work to add a log out button is totally open source in
<a href="https://github.com/artsy/emission/pull/2027">these</a> <a href="https://github.com/artsy/eigen/pull/2977">two</a> pull requests.</p>

<p>Any organization structure will lead to features falling through cracks. It just happens, it's the nature of
structured organizations. What we've learned at Artsy is that Hackathons (and cross-team collaboration in general)
are effective "escape hatches" for important-but-not-urgent work to get prioritized. They help our colleagues in
Engineering and other teams get to know each other, get to know our business, and find out what kind of features
our users need – even less-than-glamorous features, like a log out button.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[iOS Learning Group]]></title>
    <link href="https://artsy.github.io/blog/2019/12/03/ios-learning-group/"/>
    <updated>2019-12-03T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <id>https://artsy.github.io/blog/2019/12/03/ios-learning-group</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Regular readers of our blog might be familiar with <a href="https://www.cultureamp.com">Culture Amp</a>, a tool Artsy uses to
collect anonymous feedback and take action on cultural issues (we most recently discussed the tool
<a href="https://artsy.github.io/blog/2019/04/19/having-a-coffee-with-every-engineer/">in this blog post</a>). At a
company-wide level, Culture Amp has helped guide everything from Artsy's evolving culture, to our physical work
spaces, to our support for remote work. At an engineering-team level, we've also been using Culture Amp to guide
our choices in technology, documentation, and training.</p>

<p>In this blog post I'll be detailing a recent learning course we ran to share knowledge about how Artsy builds iOS
software for our entire engineering team.</p>

<!-- more -->


<p>Let's start at the beginning. Earlier this year, Artsy Engineering ran a survey through Culture Amp to get answers
to the following questions:</p>

<ol>
<li>What is our team's opinion on our current technology choices?</li>
<li>What is our team's familiarity with or preparedness for our current technology?</li>
<li>Where are the areas of strength and opportunities for both learning and teaching?</li>
</ol>


<p>There are a lot of things we learned from this survey, and among them was a desire for engineers to better
understand how to build iOS software at Artsy. With a nudge (and support!) from our <em>Peer Learning Working Group</em>,
I set out to create a learning plan. I wasn't starting from scratch – we already ran a few learning groups on
topics ranging from Scala fundamentals to React Hooks. We used the lessons learned from <em>those</em> experiences to
define and deliver a learning plan.</p>

<p>I started by booking five sessions, spread out by a week. I picked a time that was a good fit for as many engineers
as possible, and I scheduled them a month ahead to give people a chance to move their schedules around. Scheduling
them up front was important, to give learners a sense of what to expect; previous learning groups had suffered from
inconsistent schedules, which led to intermittent attendance. I also asked each Tech Lead to make sure at least one
engineer from their team attended.</p>

<p>Next was the actual curriculum. In the spirit of "proudly discovered elsewhere", we actually looked at using
existing learning resources that someone else had already developed. However, since
<a href="https://artsy.github.io/series/react-native-at-artsy/">our iOS stack is a bit unique</a> and I was keen to keep
honing my own skills as a technical educator, we decided to make our own. With the help of our Peer Learning
Working Group, we set learning objectives for the five sessions. Here was the original plan:</p>

<ul>
<li><strong>Week 1</strong>: This week, we will cover how iOS software is developed, QA'd, and deployed. By the end of this
session, all participants should be able to pull the latest code from <a href="https://github.com/artsy/eigen">Eigen</a>
(our native iOS repo) and <a href="https://github.com/artsy/emission">Emission</a> (our React Native repo), see their work
in an iOS simulator, and link the two projects together.</li>
<li><strong>Week 2</strong>: This week, we will cover what makes React Native distinct from React on the web, as well as how Artsy
leverages shared infrastructure (such as our design-system, <a href="https://github.com/artsy/palette">Palette</a>) to make
it easier for engineers to work in either one.</li>
<li><strong>Week 3</strong>: This week, we will cover how to create a new view controller. View controllers are the main unit of
composition for native iOS apps, and we integrate our "Scene" React components <em>as</em> view controllers. This
includes routing between view controller, from both native Objective-C and React Native code.</li>
<li><strong>Week 4</strong>: This week, we will create our own React component to fit within the new view controller from Week 3.
This will be a Relay container, fetching data from our GraphQL API,
<a href="https://github.com/artsy/metaphysics">Metaphysics</a>. We will cover how to fetch data, how to <em>re</em>-fetch data, as
well as how Eigen and Emission integrate together to provide client-side API response caches (both Relay and
others).</li>
<li><strong>Week 5</strong>: This is the final week. Participants are asked to bring an iOS bug from their product team's backlog
that they would like to fix. Pairing is encouraged.</li>
</ul>


<p>Things mostly went to plan. I made sure to provide the learning resources at least a day or two ahead of each
session; this let me respond to feedback from the previous week, and also gave learners a chance to review
materials ahead of time.</p>

<p>Every session was recorded for anyone who missed it. We had a shared Slack channel set up for questions, so
engineers could help each other. I also made sure to provide weekly office hours: this was space for people who
missed sessions to catch up, or to just dig into concepts in more detail. I'll return to the topic of office hours
later in this post.</p>

<p>Around the time of the learning group, I was reading
<em><a href="https://www.amazon.com/Make-Stick-Science-Successful-Learning/dp/0674729013/ref=sr_1_1?keywords=making+it+stick&amp;qid=1575314498&amp;sr=8-1">Make It Stick: The Science of Successful Learning</a></em>.
The book is written for people who want to improve their own learning skills, but it was <em>very</em> helpful to read as
I was developing and delivering this curriculum. Here are a few lessons that I learned from the book that were
helpful while teaching engineers at Artsy about how we build iOS software:</p>

<ul>
<li>If someone tries to do something themselves <em>before</em> being told how to do it, the attempt will strengthen their
understanding of the underlying concept. To put this into practice, I would often ask learners questions that I
didn't expect they could answer yet, and the resulting discussion was always worthwhile.</li>
<li>Interleaving different concepts together helps learners form connections between those concepts. This was
especially important, since a big motivator for using React Native at Artsy was to share skills between web and
iOS codebases. As an example of putting this into practice, I interleaved a discussion of
<a href="https://relay.dev">Relay</a> into our curriculum; I hoped to show learners both a new perspective of Relay, as well
as show them how familiar writing React Native code was to writing React web code.</li>
<li>Allowing for some forgetting to take place before reviewing concepts will
<a href="https://njcideas.wordpress.com/2017/09/22/the-cognitive-science-of-studying-massed-practice-vs-spaced-practice/">help strengthen learner's understanding</a>.
To put this into practice, I would return to topics from a few weeks ago to cement their understanding with
learners.</li>
</ul>


<p>I had to push through some discomfort as an educator, too. Each session ended with homework questions, which we
reviewed at the top of the next session. I would ask each question and then just sit there, in awkward silence,
while everyone looked around for someone to answer. Eventually, inevitably, someone would.</p>

<p>All of the learning materials
<a href="https://github.com/artsy/README/tree/master/resources/mobile/learning-group">are open source</a>. While the materials
are mostly specific to Artsy, they may be of help to others. And regardless, we want to adhere to our
<a href="https://github.com/artsy/README/blob/master/culture/engineering-principles.md#open-source-by-default">Open Source by Default</a>
principle.</p>

<p>We learned quite a lot from delivering this curriculum – lessons we can apply to our next learning group:</p>

<ul>
<li>Learners appreciated the weekly schedule set upfront, affirming what we learned from previous learning groups.</li>
<li>Learners appreciated having access to the materials ahead of time.</li>
<li>Learners appreciated having the sessions recorded, to be reviewed later (or watched, in case they missed the
session).</li>
<li>Learners appreciated having office hours available; even though the office hours weren't well-attended, learners
appreciated having access to them if they needed to.</li>
<li>Learners even appreciated the awkward silences while I waited for an answer to my questions. (One survey
respondent described it as "like pulling teeth, but helpful.")</li>
<li>Learners are varied in how they want to learn. Some liked going through things together. Some thought we went too
slow. Still others thought we should expect learners to do more work ahead of class.</li>
</ul>


<p>This last point is worth expanding upon. While everyone learns differently, there is a distinction between what
<em>feels</em> effective and what <em>is</em> effective. I tried to structure the course so that it was accessible to as many
types of learners as possible: some like to review materials ahead of time, some like to have them on hand during
the session, etc. Some are in-person, others are remote, still others are reviewing the recording. I could write
another blog post about learning styles, but for now it suffices to say that I aimed for <em>inclusion</em> of as many
different learners as possible while also recognizing that I can't make everyone happy.</p>

<p>As I enter a new chapter of my own career, leading Artsy's new Mobile Experience team, it was helpful to return to
some fundamentals; to get familiar with technology choices that we made years ago
(<a href="https://ashfurrow.com/blog/swift-vs-react-native-feels/">choices which I originally resisted</a>); and to learn from
learners' perspectives as beginners. The future of iOS software at Artsy is very bright, and now every product team
is more prepared than ever to deliver user experiences that are of a quality worthy of art.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
