<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: force | Artsy Engineering]]></title>
  <link href="http://artsy.github.io/blog/categories/force/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://artsy.github.io/"/>
  <updated>2016-08-24T14:37:18+00:00</updated>
  <id>http://artsy.github.io/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Artsy's Technology Stack, 2015]]></title>
    <link href="http://artsy.github.io/blog/2015/03/23/artsy-technology-stack-2015/"/>
    <updated>2015-03-23T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <id>http://artsy.github.io/blog/2015/03/23/artsy-technology-stack-2015</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Artsy has now grown past 100 team members and our Engineering organization is now 20 strong. For a brief overview of what the company has accomplished in the last two years, check out our <a href="http://2013.artsy.net">2013</a> and <a href="http://2014.artsy.net">2014</a> reviews.</p>

<p>This is a good opportunity to describe our updated technology stack. Last time <a href="/blog/2012/10/10/artsy-technology-stack">we did this</a> was when Artsy launched publicly in 2012.</p>

<center><img src='/images/2015-03-23-artsy-technology-stack-2015/stats.png'></center>


<p>Three years ago Artsy was a classic <a href="http://rubyonrails.org">Ruby-on-Rails</a> monolith with a handful of adjacent processes and tools. We've since broken it up into many independent services, and continue to heavily be a Ruby and JavaScript shop, using Rails where appropriate, with native code on mobile devices and some JVM-based experiments in micro-services.</p>

<center><img src='/images/2015-03-23-artsy-technology-stack-2015/languages.png'></center>




<!-- more -->


<p>What you see today when you go to <a href="https://www.artsy.net">www.artsy.net</a> is a website built with <a href="http://ezeljs.com">Ezel.js</a>, which is a boilerplate for <a href="http://backbonejs.org">Backbone</a> projects running on <a href="https://nodejs.org">Node</a> and using <a href="http://expressjs.com">Express</a> and <a href="http://browserify.org">Browserify</a>. The <a href="https://github.com/artsy/force">CoffeeScript code</a> is open-source. The mobile version of www.artsy.net is <a href="https://m.artsy.net">m.artsy.net</a> and is built on the same technology. Both run on <a href="http://heroku.com">Heroku</a> and use <a href="http://redis.io">Redis</a> for caching. Assets, including artwork images, are served from <a href="http://aws.amazon.com/s3/">Amazon S3</a> via the <a href="http://aws.amazon.com/cloudfront">CloudFront CDN</a>.</p>

<center><img src='/images/2015-03-23-artsy-technology-stack-2015/artsy.png'></center>


<p>These web applications talk to a private Ruby API built with <a href="https://github.com/intridea/grape">Grape</a>, that serves JSON. We also have a more modern and better designed <a href="https://developers.artsy.net">public HAL+JSON API</a>. For historical reasons, both are hosted side-by-side on top of a big Rails app that used to be our original monolith. The API service runs on <a href="http://aws.amazon.com/opsworks">AWS OpsWorks</a> and retrieves data from several <a href="http://www.mongodb.com">MongoDB</a> databases hosted with <a href="https://www.compose.io">Compose</a>. It also uses <a href="http://lucene.apache.org/solr">Apache Solr</a>, <a href="https://www.elastic.co">Elastic Search</a> and <a href="https://www.google.com/cse">Google Custom Search</a>. The API service also heavily relies on <a href="http://memcached.org">Memcached</a>.</p>

<center><img src='/images/2015-03-23-artsy-technology-stack-2015/developers.png'></center>


<p>Our partners upload artworks, artists and other metadata via a home-grown content-management system built entirely from scratch in 2014 on Ruby-on-Rails. This was a deliberate <a href="http://chris.eidhof.nl/posts/boring-choice.html">"boring"</a> choice that continues to serve us very well. We have adopted a common model for admin-type apps with a shared component library and a reusable UI, all implemented as Rails engines. Using these components we are able to quickly and easily compose beautiful and useful applications - we have built dedicated systems to manage fairs and auctions. We standardized on related services as well - for example, our customers interact with us via <a href="https://www.intercom.io">Intercom</a>. We're also experimenting with some new technologies in our internal apps, notably <a href="http://facebook.github.io/react">React</a>.</p>

<center><img src='/images/2015-03-23-artsy-technology-stack-2015/cms.png'></center>


<p>Our family of mobile applications includes <a href="http://iphone.artsy.net">Artsy for iOS</a>, which is a hybrid app written in Objective-C, and a <a href="https://github.com/artsy/eidolon">bidding kiosk</a>, written in Swift. Both are open-source <a href="https://github.com/artsy/eigen">here</a> and <a href="https://github.com/artsy/eidolon">here</a>.</p>

<center><img src='/images/2015-03-23-artsy-technology-stack-2015/folio.jpg'></center>


<p>A lot of data, including the artwork similarity graph that powers The Art Genome Project, is processed offline by a generic job engine, written in Ruby or by <a href="http://aws.amazon.com/elasticmapreduce">Amazon Elastic MapReduce</a>. We take data snapshots from MongoDB, run jobs on the data and export data back to the database. Other recently rewritten services include image processing, which creates thumbnails, image tiles for deep zoom and watermarks high quality JPEGs. Several new applications use <a href="http://www.postgresql.org">PostgreSQL</a>.</p>

<p>Various front-ends pipe data to <a href="https://github.com/snowplow/snowplow">Snowplow</a> and <a href="https://segment.com">Segment</a>, which forwards events to <a href="https://keen.io">Keen</a>, <a href="http://www.google.com/analytics">Google Analytics</a>, <a href="https://mixpanel.com">MixPanel</a> and <a href="https://chartbeat.com">ChartBeat</a>. Some data is warehoused in <a href="http://aws.amazon.com/redshift">AWS Redshift</a> and <a href="http://www.postgresql.org">PostgreSQL</a> and may be analyzed offline using <a href="http://www.r-project.org">R</a> or <a href="http://ipython.org/notebook.html">iPython Notebooks</a>. We also have a <a href="https://github.com/etsy/statsd">Statsd</a> and <a href="http://graphite.wikidot.com">Graphite</a> system for tracking high volume, low-level counters. Finally, it's also fairly common to find a non-Engineer at Artsy in a read-only Rails console or in Redshift directly querying data.</p>

<p>We send millions of e-mails via <a href="http://sendgrid.com/">SendGrid</a> and <a href="https://mandrill.com">Mandrill</a> and use <a href="http://mailchimp.com">MailChimp</a> for manual campaigns.</p>

<p>Smaller systems usually start on <a href="https://dashboard.heroku.com">Heroku</a> and larger processes that perform heavier workloads usually end up on <a href="http://aws.amazon.com/opsworks">AWS OpsWorks</a>. Our systems are monitored by a combination of <a href="http://newrelic.com/">New Relic</a> and <a href="https://www.pingdom.com">Pingdom</a>. All of this is built, tested and continuously deployed with <a href="http://jenkins-ci.org">Jenkins</a>, <a href="https://semaphoreci.com">Semaphore</a>, and <a href="https://travis-ci.org">Travis-CI</a>.</p>

<center><img src='/images/2015-03-23-artsy-technology-stack-2015/gravity.png'></center>


<p>In terms of Engineering workflow we live in <a href="https://github.com">Github</a> and <a href="https://trello.com">Trello</a>. We tend to have a workflow similar to open-source projects with individuals owning components and services and the entire team contributing to them.</p>

<p>In 2015 we intend to complete our transformation into small independent services built with 10x growth in mind. We can then focus on maturing the Artsy platform both vertically and horizontally and enabling many new directions for our thriving businesses.</p>

<p>We hope you find this useful and will be happy to describe any detailed aspect of our system on this blog. We're always hiring, please e-mail <a href='mailto:jobs@artsy.net'>jobs@artsy.net</a> if you want to work with us. Finally, we welcome any questions here and look forward to answering them below!</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[We open sourced our Isomorphic Javascript website]]></title>
    <link href="http://artsy.github.io/blog/2014/09/05/we-open-sourced-our-isomorphic-javascript-website/"/>
    <updated>2014-09-05T15:09:00+00:00</updated>
    <id>http://artsy.github.io/blog/2014/09/05/we-open-sourced-our-isomorphic-javascript-website</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><img src="/images/2014-09-05-we-open-sourced-our-isomorphic-javascript-website/force.png" alt="May The Force be With You" /></p>

<p>Today we're happy to announce we've open sourced the entire Artsy.net web app, <a href="https://github.com/artsy/force">Force</a>.</p>

<p>Over the past few months, we've rewritten our web front-end to move off Rails and on to a <a href="http://nodejs.org/">Node.js</a> stack that shares Javascript code and rendering between the server and client, otherwise known as <a href="http://nerds.airbnb.com/isomorphic-JavaScript-future-web-apps/">Isomorphic Javascript</a>. After migrating to this new stack, we open-sourced our boilerplate, <a href="http://ezeljs.com">Ezel</a>, and have now gone a step further and open sourced Artsy.net.</p>

<!-- more -->


<h2>Isomorphic vs Monolithic</h2>

<p>Our transition to an isomorphic Javascript stack has been very successful albeit with some speed bumps. If you're interested in the details we've written <a href="http://artsy.github.io/blog/2013/11/30/rendering-on-the-server-and-client-in-node-dot-js/">a blog post</a>, given a talk at <a href="https://www.joyent.com/developers/videos/node-js-on-the-road-nyc-craig-spaeth-brennan-moore">Node on the Road</a> (slides <a href="http://www.slideshare.net/craigspaeth/artsy-node-on-the-roady-slides">here</a>), and another more extensive talk at <a href="http://www.hakkalabs.co/articles/monolithic-to-distributed-how-artsy-transitioned-from-ruby-on-rails-to-node-js-and-isomorphic-javascript#">this meetup</a>.</p>

<p>The short story is that we moved from a monolithic rails app to a couple of Node servers on Heroku. This vastly improved the performance of our site and our own development speed. Using the patterns in Ezel, we are able to tailor assets packages to specific pages and render some of the page on the server. This cut our page-load in half (from 6.5 seconds to under 3 seconds) and our tests take about 5 minutes (down from around 5 hours!) with little reduction in coverage. Performance numbers aside, our real win was dramatically improved development speed due to some architecture decisions we made.</p>

<h2>Modularity</h2>

<p><a href="https://artsy.net/artwork/nathan-sawaya-red-head"><img src="/images/2014-09-05-we-open-sourced-our-isomorphic-javascript-website/sawaya.jpg" alt="Nathan Sawaya, Red Head, 2009" /></a></p>

<p>One of the biggest takeaways from the transition is the pleasure of modularity. By breaking our project up into smaller reusable pieces such as <a href="https://github.com/artsy/ezel#project-vs-apps-vs-components">apps &amp; components</a> we make it easier to experiment, test, and refactor with confidence knowing our code is encapsulated into clearly defined pieces.</p>

<p>For instance, we recently redesigned our <a href="https://artsy.net/about">about</a> page. To gradually introduce the new page, we simply started a new about2 app along side our old about app which you can see <a href="https://github.com/artsy/force/tree/0d5a49da08e94a91b3f23c7cd1005c1e83da7ba5/apps">a little back in Force's history</a>. This let us push code into the new about2 app with confidence it wasn't touching other parts of the stack. When it was time to ship it, we simply deleted the old about app folder and search and replaced "about2" to "about". There was no need to dig around various stylesheets, views, etc. folders looking for places where code for the old about page might still live.</p>

<p><a href="https://github.com/artsy/ezel#components">Components</a> are particularly useful for re-usability. For instance building <a href="https://artsy.net/gene/abstract-expressionism">this gene page</a> (source code <a href="https://github.com/artsy/force/tree/master/apps/gene">here</a>) was mostly a matter of pulling in various components like a <a href="https://github.com/artsy/force/tree/master/components/follow_button">follow button</a>, a <a href="https://github.com/artsy/force/tree/master/components/filter">filter</a> component, this <a href="https://github.com/artsy/force/tree/master/components/artist_fillwidth_list">artist fill-width layout</a>, etc. Because the CSS for those components are clearly self-contained it's easy to build up a small asset package that uses only the minimal CSS needed which you can see <a href="https://github.com/artsy/force/blob/master/assets/gene.styl">here</a>.</p>

<p>We're so convinced this encapsulation is important that we've updated Ezel to <a href="https://github.com/artsy/ezel/tree/master/src/js-example/apps/commits/public/images">use app/component-level public folders</a> by default so you can even modularize static assets, like images, and keep them coupled with their respective apps/components.</p>

<h2>Open Source by Default</h2>

<p><img src="/images/2014-09-05-we-open-sourced-our-isomorphic-javascript-website/octocat.jpg" alt="Ocotcat" /></p>

<p>Even though Force isn't a library, we have open-soured many of its components and libraries. Before open sourcing Force, we open sourced app-specific modules such as <a href="https://github.com/artsy/artsy-backbone-mixins">these backbone mixins</a> <a href="https://github.com/artsy/artsy-passport">this Artsy API authentication library</a>, or <a href="https://github.com/artsy/backbone-cache-sync">this module</a> we use to cache server-side Backbone requests.</p>

<p>Open-sourcing Force was pretty straightforward but we needed to make our sensitive keys/secrets private while not complicating development. To do this we wrote a .env file and uploaded it as a private gist that gets downloaded when setting up the app. We wanted to spread this open-source-by-default culture so we decided to update Ezel's configuration to be able to use a .env file in this way as well. This makes it easy keep your sensitive configuration data private while allowing the rest of your app code to be open source. You can read more about this in Ezel's <a href="https://github.com/artsy/ezel#build-scripts--configuration">Build Scripts &amp; Configuration docs</a>.</p>

<h2>Spreading The Love</h2>

<p>Force serves as an example of how we structured a large <a href="http://ezeljs.com">Ezel</a> project and contains the full commit history of its construction. Unfortunately, due to image licensing issues, we cannot open up the Artsy API and therefore this repository can't serve as a runnable clone of our website. However, we will continue to merge our production code into it. If you have any questions feel free to hit us up on twitter: <a href="https://twitter.com/craigspaeth">@craigspaeth</a>, <a href="https://twitter.com/dzucconi">@dzucconi</a>, <a href="https://twitter.com/zamiang">@zamiang</a>.</p>

<p>We're excited to continue pushing open source at Artsy. For more exciting open source projects take a look at <a href="https://github.com/artsy">our GitHub profile</a>.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Retain scroll position in infinite scroll]]></title>
    <link href="http://artsy.github.io/blog/2014/07/09/retain-scroll-position-in-infinite-scroll/"/>
    <updated>2014-07-09T17:29:00+00:00</updated>
    <id>http://artsy.github.io/blog/2014/07/09/retain-scroll-position-in-infinite-scroll</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><img src="https://camo.githubusercontent.com/4b7e6aefa00b96ba2804b235aaaa811bbb893c4e/687474703a2f2f7777772e6578706c61696e786b63642e636f6d2f77696b692f696d616765732f352f35362f696e66696e6974655f7363726f6c6c696e672e706e67" alt="Maybe we should give up on the whole idea of a 'back' button. 'Show me that thing I was looking at a moment ago' might just be too complicated an idea for the modern web." /></p>

<p>Although <a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=7314965">some find infinite scroll to be a contentious topic</a> at Artsy we've found it to be a useful element in many portions of our site such as <a href="https://artsy.net/browse/artworks?medium=prints&amp;price_range=-1%3A1000">filtering</a>. However, we've run into a common and painful usability issue with infinite scroll. That is clicking on an item redirects to the next page, losing your scroll position, and losing your place when going back. To solve this we have come up with a clever little solution using an iframe.</p>

<!-- more -->


<p>We're pleased to announce we've open sourced this solution into <a href="https://github.com/artsy/scroll-frame">scrollFrame</a>.</p>

<p>scrollFrame borrows from sites like Pinterest that avoid this problem by opening the next page in a <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Modal_window">modal window</a>. Only instead of having to build your entire page client-side, scrollFrame will intercept your click and open the next page in an iframe that sits on top of your current page and covers your viewport (acting as a sort of modal that doesn't look like a modal). scrollFrame will then hook into the <a href="https://developer.mozilla.org/en-US/docs/Web/Guide/API/DOM/Manipulating_the_browser_history">HTML5 history API</a> to remove the iframe modal on back button and keep your URL up to date. <a href="https://artsy.net/browse">See it in action on our browse page!</a></p>

<p>scrollFrame only solves this specific problem with infinite scroll but we've gotten a lot of mileage out of it and we hope you will too!</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
