<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: package-management | Artsy Engineering]]></title>
  <link href="https://artsy.github.io/blog/categories/package-management/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="https://artsy.github.io/"/>
  <updated>2021-04-22T18:19:49+00:00</updated>
  <id>https://artsy.github.io/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[It's time to use Swift Package Manager]]></title>
    <link href="https://artsy.github.io/blog/2019/01/05/its-time-to-use-spm/"/>
    <updated>2019-01-05T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <id>https://artsy.github.io/blog/2019/01/05/its-time-to-use-spm</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>It's been three years, and <a href="https://swift.org/package-manager/">Swift Package Manager</a> (SPM) is at a point where it can be useful for iOS
projects. It'll take a bit of sacrifice and a little bit of community spirit to fix some holes probably but <strong>in my
opinion, it's time for teams to start adopting SPM for their 3rd party dev tools</strong>.</p>

<p><strong>TLDR:</strong> You should be using SPM for 3rd party dev tools like: <a href="https://github.com/realm/SwiftLint">SwiftLint</a>, <a href="https://github.com/nicklockwood/SwiftFormat">SwiftFormat</a>, <a href="https://danger.systems/swift/">Danger</a>,
<a href="https://github.com/krzysztofzablocki/Sourcery">Sourcery</a>, <a href="https://github.com/SwiftGen/SwiftGen/">SwiftGen</a> and <a href="https://github.com/orta/Komondor">Git Hook management</a>.</p>

<p>This post covers: What made it feasible to use SPM now? What are the downsides of the status quo? Why use SPM at
all? What are the downsides to using SPM?</p>

<!-- more -->


<a name="What.changed.to.make.SPM.usable."></a>
<h3>What changed to make SPM usable?</h3>

<p>From my perspective, David Hart's <a href="https://github.com/apple/swift-package-manager/pull/1187">addition of <code>swift run</code></a> to SPM which shipped with Swift 4.0 is what
pushed the project over the finish line to being useful for iOS developers. <code>swift run</code> is contextually the same as
<code>bundle exec</code> in that it will run a locally bundled version of your executable.</p>

<p>This means you can run <code>swift run swiftlint</code> and reliably get the same results as your CI and fellow developers.</p>

<p>Second, all of the big third party tools support SPM already. So, you probably don't need to send any upstream PRs.</p>

<a name="What.are.the.downsides.of.the.status.quo"></a>
<h3>What are the downsides of the status quo</h3>

<p><strong>Using Homebrew</strong></p>

<p>Right now, a lot of folks use <a href="https://brew.sh">homebrew</a> to manage these types of dependencies. Homebrew is useful for rarely
updated tools (like unix-y CLI apps) but it does not handle having different versions of tool available. This is a
totally reasonable call from Homebrew's perspective but it makes homebrew a bad choice for your <strong>project</strong>
dependencies - because it only installs things globally.</p>

<p>This means a developer (or your CI) would get the most recent version of that tool when they last installed the
tool. This isn't a problem for many projects (for example, check out their <a href="https://formulae.brew.sh/analytics/install/90d/">most installed</a> formulas to
see that it's lot of system libraries, languages and global tools like <code>node</code>, <code>git</code> and <code>python</code>)</p>

<p><strong>Using CocoaPods</strong></p>

<p>You can hijack CocoaPod's dependency resolver, and locking system mixed with consistent dependency paths to handle
your tools. This is better than using Homebrew, because everyone has the same version - and so you could reliably
run SwiftLint via <code>./Pods/SwiftLint/swiftlint</code>.</p>

<p>This is a great hack, and CocoaPods is smart here - because these dependencies don't ship any code for your app for
compiling it won't set up a library or framework for you. You can even use CocoaPods to set up <a href="https://guides.cocoapods.org/syntax/podfile.html#script_phase">a build
phase</a> for you too (I have feelings on this but we'll get to those later.)</p>

<p>I don't really have much of a "you shouldn't do this" for using hacking CocoaPods for your tools, outside of SPM
it's probably the right way to do it.</p>

<a name="Why.Use.SwiftPM."></a>
<h3>Why Use SwiftPM?</h3>

<ol>
<li>SPM works</li>
<li>SPM can lock your dependencies correctly. <code>:tada:</code></li>
<li>The primary tools used in our ecosystem already support it, so you don't need to do any extra work</li>
<li>Easy to cache (everything lives in <code>.build</code>) which means fast CI builds</li>
<li>You're using Swift's tools to manage tools built in Swift, promoting and encouraging the ecosystem you want to
thrive</li>
<li>Your team can get used to how SPM works now, because it should be useful for code dependencies some day</li>
<li>SPM is still in a pretty early phase for usage like this, maybe you can find features to add once you've got
started and contribute back</li>
</ol>


<a name="What.are.the.downsides."></a>
<h3>What are the downsides?</h3>

<ol>
<li><p>Running a tool will compile it the first time you use <code>swift run</code>. Running <code>swift run danger-swift</code> would first
build <code>danger-swift</code> from source and then it would run the executable.</p></li>
<li><p>SPM's dependency resolution step is very naive, and will clone all the dependencies in the tree - even if you
don't need them. So, the dependencies of your dependencies (a.k.a transitive dependencies) will have full clones
locally - e.g. the test runner for SwiftLint has to be fully cloned locally in <code>.build</code> if you use SPM for
SwiftLint. I'm hoping <a href="https://github.com/apple/swift-package-manager/pull/1918">this PR</a> and subsequent
improvements will fix this.</p></li>
<li><p>You need to reference a single Swift file in your project to make this work. SPM today does not support a
dependencies only project (it won't build), so you'll need to reference one Swift file in your codebase.</p></li>
</ol>


<p>All of these are fixable, and the first two can be worked around on CI, by caching the <code>.build</code> directory. Locally
these actions normally only happens once when you install, or update.</p>

<a name="Show.me.it.in.action"></a>
<h3>Show me it in action</h3>

<p>What would this look like for a project? IMO, for a reasonably complex Swift app, I think you should have:</p>

<ul>
<li><a href="https://github.com/realm/SwiftLint">SwiftLint</a> for catching potential code issues</li>
<li><a href="https://github.com/nicklockwood/SwiftFormat">SwiftFormat</a> so you don't argue about code style</li>
<li><a href="https://github.com/orta/Komondor">Komondor</a> to automate the above tools, so people don't have to remember to run the tools</li>
<li><a href="https://danger.systems/swift/">Danger Swift</a> to handle cultural rules for PRs like "Please add Changelogs entries"</li>
</ul>


<p>You would write a <code>Package.swift</code> file like this:</p>

<pre><code class="swift">// swift-tools-version:4.2
import PackageDescription

let package = Package(
    name: "Eigen",
    dependencies: [
      .package(url: "https://github.com/danger/swift.git", from: "1.0.0"),
      .package(url: "https://github.com/nicklockwood/SwiftFormat", from: "0.35.8"),
      .package(url: "https://github.com/Realm/SwiftLint", from: "0.28.1"),
      .package(url: "https://github.com/orta/Komondor", from: "1.0.0"),
    ],
    targets: [
        // This is just an arbitrary Swift file in the app, that has
        // no dependencies outside of Foundation, the dependencies section
        .target(name: "eigen", dependencies: ["Danger"], path: "Artsy", sources: ["Stringify.swift"]),
    ]
)

// The settings for the git hooks for our repo
#if canImport(PackageConfig)
    import PackageConfig

    let config = PackageConfig([
        "komondor": [
            // When someone has run `git commit`, first run
            // SwiftFormat and the auto-correcter for SwiftLint
            "pre-commit": [
                "swift run swiftformat .",
                "swift run swiftlint autocorrect --path Artsy/",
                "git add .",
            ],
        ]
    ])
#endif
</code></pre>

<p>Which gives you access to the following commands:</p>

<ul>
<li><code>swift run komondor install</code> - to set up your repo's git hooks</li>
<li><code>swift run swiftformat .</code> - to run SwiftFormat over your project</li>
<li><code>swift run swiftlint --autocorrect</code> - to highlight your linter issues</li>
<li><code>swift run danger-swift ci</code> - to run Danger Swift on your CI</li>
</ul>


<p>Because you can reliably run both SwiftFormat and SwiftLint via Komondor on a git hook, you can remove build phase
steps that run these tools.</p>

<p>An iOS app's compile and run cycle already takes on the order of seconds, so you should avoid adding extra build
steps in Xcode. I realise that people are only doing this due to the (unreasonably) limited extension support in
Xcode, but the build steps are critical path code. When your build and run cycle is already on the order of many
seconds that iteration cycle has to be as tight as possible.</p>

<p>This setup gives you version-locked access to common linting/formating tools (with the ability to use komondor to
add extra checks if needed) in a self-contained <code>Package.swift</code>.</p>

<p>We've started migrating our Artsy projects to use this setup when we work on our native codebases. With our main
iOS app Eigen already using this pattern for Danger Swift, but we don't created/modify enough <code>*.swift</code> files to
warrant linters/formatters yet.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Why is the Swift Package Manager taking so long?]]></title>
    <link href="https://artsy.github.io/blog/2018/12/21/why-is-swiftpm-taking-so-long/"/>
    <updated>2018-12-21T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <id>https://artsy.github.io/blog/2018/12/21/why-is-swiftpm-taking-so-long</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Last month I was chatting at a bar with an engineer working on the Swift team, and we welcomed someone to our
conversation where they opened with the question: <em>"When can I stop using CocoaPods and switch to Swift PM?"</em> I
chuckled, because I get this a lot (I have been helping to maintain CocoaPods for about 6 years now) but they had
made mistake of asking an Apple employee about something which sounds even remotely like a future product question.
So, it didn't go anywhere.</p>

<p>Well, <em>person whose name I don't remember</em>, let me try to re-frame that question into something I can take a
reasonable stab at: <strong>"Why are we all still using CocoaPods now instead of Swift PM for iOS apps three years after
its release?"</strong></p>

<!-- more -->


<p>Three years ago in December 2015, Swift became open source. Inside the source code was a <a href="https://twitter.com/orta/status/672436829250052102">pleasant
surprise</a> that Apple were going to start making their own package manager. Great, CocoaPods was
<a href="https://www.urbandictionary.com/define.php?term=sherlocked">sherlocked</a>, but Apple had control of Xcode and the entire toolchain so they could integrate it natively. I
thought this was pretty cool, and wrote the following about Swift PM in my annual write-up that year:</p>

<blockquote><p>[On the Swift PM team] They’re actively talking with the community and us, finding ways to share work and to
promote collaboration. It’s eased a lot of the friction I had been feeling. Apple has a fresh start in a way we
could not, and will be able to do things much better than the CocoaPods team could.</p>

<p>All in all, when people have been asking what I want to do in the next year, I’m feeling pretty done on the
"lowering the barrier to entry" space, this year it became less fun.</p></blockquote>

<p><em>Fun fact: This is what gave me the space to start working on <a href="https://danger.systems/">Danger</a>.</em></p>

<p>The announcement of Swift PM came out to some fan-fare as the "end of CocoaPods" from the iOS community, and I was
also pretty happy to get some time back to work on other problems. However, a few years down the line it's not
really turned out that way. What gives?</p>

<a name="Why.Swift.PM.exists"></a>
<h1>Why Swift PM exists</h1>

<p>Before Swift PM, you couldn't reasonably manage Swift projects in Linux. Apple have exclusively been building dev
tools for macOS because that's what they own, and so, all their dev-tools customers (internal and external) have to
use Macs to make their software. It's not particularly unreasonable.</p>

<p>However, to make Swift a language with a larger scope than "making iOS and macOS apps" and it's usage being limited
to just the Cocoa community: they would need to support running and compiling Swift apps on Linux.</p>

<p>It's safe to say Apple probably has no plans to port Xcode to Linux, (though look at what Microsoft achieved when
they decided that they needed to support Visual Studio on macOS <a href="https://code.visualstudio.com">somehow</a>) but what's more important here
is the underlying tooling <strong>above</strong> the compiler but <strong>below</strong> Xcode: <code>xcodebuild</code>, wouldn't make any sense in that
context. It's deeply macOS and Cocoa specific.</p>

<p>So, Apple needed something to handle the following problems if you were working in a Xcode-less Swift project:</p>

<ul>
<li>Handling build dependencies</li>
<li>Linking to existing code</li>
<li>Creating library abstractions</li>
<li>Creating executable for the language</li>
<li>Handling sharing code between projects</li>
</ul>


<p>Roughly in that order of precedence too. In short, they needed a build system first, and then a dependency manager
to support remote packages.</p>

<p>There are a few big existing build systems: <a href="https://www.github.com/facebook/buck">Buck</a> and <a href="https://ninja-build.org">Ninja</a> are the biggest players in the game,
but they aim to be language agnostic build tools. This makes them a bit too abstract to be useful as the main way
to build a modular system for building projects in a language. So, each language from Swift's generation of <em>"As
fast as C, but safe"</em> like Rust, Go and D all implement a build system unique to their language.</p>

<a name="llbuild"></a>
<h1>llbuild</h1>

<p>Apple's approach to building a build system is smart. Instead of from scratch creating a build tool for Swift, they
created an abstraction which makes it feasible to build complex builds systems quicker. That's <a href="https://www.github.com/apple/swift-llbuild">llbuild</a>, a
low-level build system. This was used to create the Swift build system. Then, llbuild was re-used to create
<a href="https://lists.swift.org/pipermail/swift-build-dev/Week-of-Mon-20170605/001019.html">Xcode's build system</a>.</p>

<p>The new build system for Xcode came out in 2017 with Xcode 9, and became the default in 2018 with Xcode 10. What's
impressive about the new build system is how much it was just like the last, but better, to quote <a href="https://jamesdempsey.net/2017/06/13/new-xcode-build-system-and-buildsettingextractor/">James
Dempsey</a>:</p>

<blockquote><p>New build system. Same build settings</p></blockquote>

<p>Which is impressive, because the existing system is <a href="https://pewpewthespells.com/blog/xcode_build_system.html">complex</a>.</p>

<a name="Build.System....Package.Manager"></a>
<h1>Build System != Package Manager</h1>

<p>CocoaPods was "useful" for Cocoa development very quickly in comparison (roughly a month from initial commit to
supporting a few existing libraries in an app back in 2011), this was because CocoaPods completely skipped the
build tool stage. There was no need, Xcode has a working build system and you can control it via <code>.xcodeproj</code>
files. This meant that the key output for CocoaPods is to reliably support generating xcode projects and the
underlying abstractions making it actually compile is left to the Xcode team.</p>

<p>The Swift PM team couldn't do this without making it deeply dependent on Xcode. CocoaPods can be in-different to
something like Linux support (fun fact: last month <a href="https://github.com/CocoaPods/CocoaPods/pull/8189">Windows support</a> was added) because no-one is writing
Cocoa apps on Linux, and it's only concern is shipping those Xcode project files to your project's file system.</p>

<p>This difference in abstraction level allowed CocoaPods to work on comprehensive support of the existing library
ecosystem considerably sooner. The config options were already set, the types of projects were known they had to
map to whatever Xcode supported rather than the more mundane task of actually figuring out how to make a project
build, compile and scale.</p>

<p>CocoaPods got focus on more user-facing issues that a dependency manager has considerably quicker, and could focus
on building the most used features first then moving to more niche features (which could be the abstractions those
popular feature relied on) when someone needed it. This meant that the user-facing, and interesting to me, work was
feasible considerably earlier:</p>

<ul>
<li>Discovery of packages</li>
<li>A lot of documentation</li>
<li>Access rights for owners</li>
<li>Creating plugin systems giving hooks for all sorts of projects to be built</li>
<li>Support for esoteric compiler features</li>
<li>Support for esoteric Xcode features</li>
<li>Providing useful metrics on quality/usage</li>
<li>Cool stickers</li>
</ul>


<p>Which generally speaking are problems that Swift PM will eventually have to hit, but instead of jumping straight to
it, the team has to first build the foundations before making the decorations.</p>

<a name="The.cost"></a>
<h1>The cost</h1>

<p>These choices came with a cost though, right now there's only 1 or 2 contexts where Swift PM is useful, the most
prominent is Swift on a Server. It's likely that Swift on a server probably isn't as widely adopted as Apple hoped
it would be by the programming community on whole. Unless you are an iOS developer with existing skills, Swift
probably doesn't even register as being a language you would consider building your web API/apps in. Yes, I know
there are a <a href="https://www.pointfree.co">few</a> <a href="https://talk.objc.io/collections/server-side-swift">good</a> exceptions, but they come from the iOS community.</p>

<p>Which probably hasn't helped with resourcing Swift PM at Apple, where the user-facing team has
<a href="https://github.com/apple/swift-package-manager/graphs/contributors">basically</a> been a one-man operation for about a year and a half. From my external perspective,
this is lower than I'd like. It's a problem close to my heart though.</p>

<p>Given that we're talking about Apple, you shouldn't judge activity entirely from their open source contributions,
but given the project isn't useful for most people who could contribute, they don't. I started working on CocoaPods
because it was fixing a really hard problem that I had, and I knew that working on this would fix it for everyone
else in the industry too, making it worth my time. So, external contributions outside Apple are pretty low.</p>

<p>Build systems are a hard problem, and the Swift PM team very reasonably needs to work on that first, but is
basically doing it pretty much solo. I think this is one of those "<a href="https://ryanparman.com/posts/2011/skating-to-where-the-puck-will-be/">skate where the puck will be</a>"
situations, instead of where it is, which CocoaPods' aimed for. This means it's going to take a much longer time to
be useful and widely adopted. While I don't really know where Swift PM aims to be in the long-term, I think Xcode
integration will probably be the major adoption turning point but in the meantime I've got an idea for a smaller
way to make Swift PM useful to the iOS community. That, however, is another blog post.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
