<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: omakase | Artsy Engineering]]></title>
  <link href="http://artsy.github.io/blog/categories/omakase/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://artsy.github.io/"/>
  <updated>2020-01-17T16:27:14+00:00</updated>
  <id>http://artsy.github.io/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Why does Artsy use Relay?]]></title>
    <link href="http://artsy.github.io/blog/2019/04/10/omakase-relay/"/>
    <updated>2019-04-10T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <id>http://artsy.github.io/blog/2019/04/10/omakase-relay</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>When the mobile team at Artsy considered <a href="/blog/2016/08/15/React-Native-at-Artsy/">moving to React Native</a> back in 2016, one of the most compelling
cases for making that jump was Relay. This, it seems, is a dependency that is rarely used in the JS community and
we often find ourselves re-explaining this decision to new engineers during onboarding, and to the public at large.</p>

<p>Which makes this a perfect blog post topic, so let's have a deep dive into what makes Relay compelling for Artsy's
engineering team.</p>

<!-- more -->


<a name="What.problem.does.Relay.solve."></a>
<h1>What problem does Relay solve?</h1>

<p>Relay is an API client for GraphQL, it comes in two parts: a compiler and a set of front-end components. Relay aims
to provide a really tight binding between your GraphQL API and your view hierarchy. When you build data-driven
apps, Relay removes a whole suite of non-business logic from your application.</p>

<p>Relay handles:</p>

<ul>
<li>Data binding (API → props)</li>
<li>Cache management (invalidation, re-render live components with data updates, etc)</li>
<li>Consistent abstractions for bi-directional pagination</li>
<li>Multiple query consolidation (e.g. consolidate all API requests to one request)</li>
<li>UI best practices baked in (e.g. optimistic response rendering)</li>
<li>Declarative data mutation (describe how data should change, instead of doing it)</li>
<li>Compile-time query generation (removing runtime overhead and allowing you to persist queries)</li>
</ul>


<p>By taking the responsibilities of the grunt work for most complex apps and moving it into Relay you get
Facebook-scale best-practices and can build on top of that.</p>

<a name="How.does.it.work."></a>
<h1>How does it work?</h1>

<p>You write a set of Relay components, you always start with a <a href="https://facebook.github.io/relay/docs/en/query-renderer.html"><code>QueryRenderer</code></a> and a tree of either
<a href="https://facebook.github.io/relay/docs/en/fragment-container.html"><code>FragmentContainer</code></a>, <a href="https://facebook.github.io/relay/docs/en/refetch-container.html"><code>RefetchContainer</code></a> or <a href="https://facebook.github.io/relay/docs/en/pagination-container.html"><code>PaginationContainer</code></a>s. You mostly use
<code>FragmentContainer</code>s, so I'll focus on that here.</p>

<p>A <code>FragmentContainer</code> is based on a <a href="https://graphql.org/learn/queries/#fragments">GraphQL fragment</a>. If you've never used a fragment, they are an
abstraction that lets you declare shared field-selections on a specific GraphQL type to reduce duplication in your
queries. For example:</p>

<pre><code>query GetPopularArtistAndFeaturedArtist {
  featuredArtist {
    id
    name
    bio
  }
  popularArtist {
    id
    name
    bio
  }
}
</code></pre>

<p>To move this query to use fragments:</p>

<pre><code>query GetPopularArtistAndFeaturedArtist {
  featuredArtist {
    ...ArtistMetadata
  }
  popularArtist {
    ...ArtistMetadata
  }
}

fragment ArtistMetadata on Artist {
  id
  name
  bio
}
</code></pre>

<p>It's a tiny bit longer, but you have a guarantee that the data is consistent across both artists. Now that you have
a rough idea of what a GraphQL fragment is, let's look at what a <code>FragmentContainer</code> looks like. Here's a
simplified <a href="https://github.com/artsy/emission/blob/892af2621eef455388e074701cca747330de3b3f/src/lib/Scenes/Settings/MyProfile.tsx#L95">profile page</a> from the Artsy iOS app:</p>

<pre><code class="ts">import React from "react"
import { createFragmentContainer, graphql } from "react-relay"
import { MyProfile_me } from "__generated__/MyProfile_me.graphql"

interface Props extends ViewProperties {
  me: MyProfile_me
}

export class MyProfile extends React.Component&lt;Props&gt; {
  render() {
    return (
      &lt;View&gt;
        &lt;Header&gt;
          &lt;ProfilePhoto initials={this.props.me.initials} image={this.props.me.image} /&gt;
          &lt;Subheading&gt;{this.props.me.name}&lt;/Subheading&gt;
        &lt;/Header&gt;
        &lt;ButtonSection&gt;
          &lt;ProfileButton
            section="Selling"
            description="Sell works from your collection"
            onPress={startSubmission}
          /&gt;
          &lt;ProfileButton
            section="Account Details"
            description="Email, password reset, profile"
            onPress={goToUserSettings}
          /&gt;
        &lt;/ButtonSection&gt;
      &lt;/View&gt;
    )
  }
}

export default createFragmentContainer(MyProfile, {
  me: graphql`
    fragment MyProfile_me on Me {
      name
      image
      initials
    }
  `
})
</code></pre>

<p>There are three moving parts:</p>

<ul>
<li>The TypeScript interface <code>MyProfile_me</code>, generated by the compiler, which ensures we can only use fields that
were selected in the fragment</li>
<li>The <code>MyProfile</code> component, which is a vanilla React component</li>
<li>The exported <code>createFragmentContainer</code> which returns a higher-order component that wraps <code>MyProfile</code> and ties it
to a fragment on a <code>Me</code> type in GraphQL</li>
</ul>


<a name="Isolation"></a>
<h2>Isolation</h2>

<p>The React component <code>MyProfile</code> will be passed in props that directly tie to the fragment that was requested. In
Relay terms, this is called <a href="https://facebook.github.io/relay/docs/en/thinking-in-relay.html#data-masking">data masking</a> and it is one of the first hurdles for someone new to Relay to
<a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Grok">grok</a>. In REST clients, and GraphQL API clients like Apollo Client, you make a request and that request is
passed through the React tree. E.g.</p>

<p></article>
<a href='/images/omakase-relay/tree.png' style="">
  <img src="/images/omakase-relay/tree.png" alt="REST inspired props" style="width:100%;">
</a>
<article class="post">
</p>

<p>This means most components know more about the request than it probably needs, as it may be needed to pass on to
the component's children. This can lead to over-fetching, or even worse, not knowing if you can delete or refactor
a component.</p>

<p>Data masking solves this by hiding data that the component didn't request. I've still yet to find the right visual
abstraction, but I feel this just about pays for itself.</p>

<p></article>
<a href='/images/omakase-relay/isolation.png' style="">
  <img src="/images/omakase-relay/isolation.png" alt="Relay isolation tree" style="width:100%;">
</a>
<article class="post">
</p>

<p>You let Relay be responsible for consolidating all your fragments into a query via the <code>QueryRenderer</code>, causing the
network request, and your response data to be passed your through your component hierarchy. This means Relay
powered components can be safely changed and drastically reduces the chance for unintended consequences elsewhere.</p>

<p>This isolation gives Artsy engineers the safety to work on projects with tens of contributors which regularly
change over time. Providing a guarantee that you can safely work in isolated parts of the codebase without accruing
technical debt.</p>

<p>Relay's container components mean that the components we create are nearly all focused only on the data-driven
aspects of rendering a subset of that GraphQL response into views. It's very powerful.</p>

<a name="Co-location"></a>
<h2>Co-location</h2>

<p>Relay helped us move to one file representing everything a component needed. Effectively a single file now handles
the styles, the actual view content hierarchy, and the exact parts of the API it needs to render itself.</p>

<p><img src="/images/omakase-relay/co-location.png"></p>

<p>In roughly that proportion too, though our most modern code uses the Artsy design system <a href="https://github.com/artsy/palette">Palette</a> which
drastically reduces the need for style in our components.</p>

<p>Co-location's biggest selling point is reducing <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Cognitive_load">cognitive load</a>,
having everything you need in one place makes it easier to understand how a component works. This makes code review
simpler, and lowers the barrier to understanding the entire systems at scale.</p>

<a name="Community"></a>
<h2>Community</h2>

<p>When we adopted Relay, there was no competition - we'd have just used the <code>fetch</code> API. Over time, <a href="https://www.apollographql.com">the Apollo
team</a> came up and really put a considerable amount of effort into lowering the barriers to entry, and
making it feasible to build complex apps easily.</p>

<p>As we hired a set of new engineers, the "Apollo vs Relay" debate came up. Interested in whether we would still
start with Relay today, we ran an audit last year of what it would take to re-create a lot of the infrastructure we
love in Relay atop of the (much more popular) Apollo GraphQL eco-system and saw it was reasonably feasible but
would require a considerable amount of work across many different plugins and tools. With Relay that's all packaged
into one tool, works consistently and has been proven with Facebook having tens of thousands of Relay components in
production.</p>

<p>It's worth highlighting the core difference in community engagement for Apollo vs Relay. Engineers working on
Apollo have great incentives to do user support, and improve the tools for the community - that's their businesses
value. Relay on the other hand is used in many places at Facebook, and the engineers on the team support internal
issues first. IMO, this is reasonable: Relay is an opinionated batteries-included framework for building user
interfaces, and ensuring it works with the baffling amount of JavaScript at Facebook is more or less all the team
has time for.</p>

<p>That leaves space for the OSS community to own their own problems. Notably there's been quite a lot of work going
on in the community-managed <a href="https://github.com/relay-tools">relay-tools</a> GitHub organization.</p>

<a name="Scale.Safety"></a>
<h2>Scale Safety</h2>

<p>Relay puts a lot of emphasis on ahead-of-time safety. The Relay compiler validates your queries against your
GraphQL schema, it emits Flow types for your fragment’s field selections–which we’ve extended to emit TypeScript
types instead, and there are strict naming systems enforced by the compiler. All of these help guide engineers to
build scalable codebases.</p>

<p>How this works in practice is that whenever you need to change the data a component requires, you edit the
fragment, the Relay compiler verifies your query, if successful then your TypeScript types are updated and you can
use the new property in your React component above. See below for a <a href="/images/omakase-relay/relay-process-720.mov">quick video</a> showing the Relay compiler
in action:</p>

<p></article>
<div>
<video controls style="margin: auto 20px; width:100%;">
  <source src="/images/omakase-relay/relay-process-720.mov" type="video/mp4">
  Your browser does not support the video tag.
</video>
</div>
<article class="post">
</p>

<p>Moving all of these checks to be during dev-time means we can feel more confident in our deploys. This is
especially an issue in an iOS native codebase, when any deploy requires a review from Apple and roll-backs are
impossible.</p>

<a name="Cultural.Fit"></a>
<h2>Cultural Fit</h2>

<p>Relay fit well into our team because:</p>

<ul>
<li>We had engineers who were interested in contributing back and extending Relay to work for our cases</li>
<li>We had engineers that were used to the benefits of ahead-of-time error validation tools that compilers offer</li>
<li>We saw a lot of value in a tightly coupling our view structure to our user interface</li>
</ul>


<p>Relay is not without its shortcomings to users outside of Facebook, but Relay has definitely paid for its initial
and occasional complexity for the tightness of our codebases many years down the line.</p>

<!-- prettier-ignore-start -->


<!-- prettier-ignore-end -->



]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
